<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Lucky Cat Home</title>
    <link href="https://www.luckycathome.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://www.luckycathome.com" />
    <updated>2022-08-29T20:25:05-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Melbren</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.luckycathome.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>How to Feng Shui Your Entryway: Top 8 Tips You Should Know</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.luckycathome.com/how-to-feng-shui-your-entryway-top-8-tips-you-should-know/"/>
        <id>https://www.luckycathome.com/how-to-feng-shui-your-entryway-top-8-tips-you-should-know/</id>

        <updated>2022-08-29T20:02:30-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Doors are usually the first to greet you when you enter a home, an office, or pretty much&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/acIvrJQz-xqWn5r7XeBISJSDqc89BvGvLmiZ-dv7F2TrniQOQUaGwlJxah_nrSWsZpQIkgxie25hLdentCMSX4nUUC1Z0Mo0F2h6-IqqCSMpKrvaN49FEf24Doi1YoNHFJ9Peplh" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is acIvrJQz-xqWn5r7XeBISJSDqc89BvGvLmiZ-dv7F2TrniQOQUaGwlJxah_nrSWsZpQIkgxie25hLdentCMSX4nUUC1Z0Mo0F2h6-IqqCSMpKrvaN49FEf24Doi1YoNHFJ9Peplh"></p>
<p>Doors are usually the first to greet you when you enter a home, an office, or pretty much anywhere. And in Feng Shui, the primary entryway holds a great deal of importance because it's where the <em>Chi</em> or the positive energy comes in.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In this article, we'll give you our top 8 tips on how you can Feng Shui your entryway.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #1: Activate your front door regularly</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/feng-shui-basics-attracting-positive-energy-into-your-home/">Feng Shui</a>, they consider the front as the portal of energy or the mouth of chi. Although there might be a backdoor or other doors that you use to go inside or outside, a home's official front door is still the mouth of chi.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>It's okay if you use the backdoor or some other doors daily, but never forget to activate your front door regularly. You can do this by passing through it daily or at least once every nine days. Opening and using the door is the most crucial part because if you're not using your front door, you block out energy and opportunities.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip # 2: Always consider the three elements that make up your entryway</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Entryways or your home's entrance have three essential elements: Door size, decor, and view. These three can affect the positive chi that enters your home.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Door size</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Your front door should be the largest door in your home. The bigger your door, the more chi can enter. But never forget to put the size of your home into consideration. It should still be in proportion to your house.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/1_TU-L43FnYjpcFYzjAHOziz0jwNskTxv6bDQXXSmm4HBATSAIdFXxo0F_xtsf94-HIjWhIgxZux5_gqhr5P0q6p9O3g1Dbcex1uaBElZ4FDFAiaU-ytAkmDhXj7bu2gGM3gDXf7" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 1_TU-L43FnYjpcFYzjAHOziz0jwNskTxv6bDQXXSmm4HBATSAIdFXxo0F_xtsf94-HIjWhIgxZux5_gqhr5P0q6p9O3g1Dbcex1uaBElZ4FDFAiaU-ytAkmDhXj7bu2gGM3gDXf7"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Decor</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The welcoming decors of your entryway, such as the furniture, lightings, and others, should also be chosen carefully. We'll talk more about this later.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>View</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The view seen from your front door is also important. Ensure that the front door is not facing directly to the toilet, kitchen, or straight out to the back of your house. These are known as inauspicious views with your front door. If it somehow can't be avoided, you can place a curtain, standing screen, or plant to help slow down the sightline to an inauspicious view.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #3: Choose the right decor and furniture</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Each house has different entryways. Depending on how big or small your home is, your setup may be a lot different from others. But whether or not you have a spacious entryway, some decor and furniture would be suitable to attract positive chi energy. Here's what you should consider when picking them out.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Lights</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>It's essential to have proper lighting in your entryway. Good lighting can add beneficial energy to your home's entrance and lift its chi. You can elevate the lighting on your foyer by adding some lamps, a crystal chandelier, or some scones if possible. But if you want some minimalist and straightforward light fixture, just bright overhead lighting will do. What's important is to keep the space well illuminated and welcoming for anyone who's coming inside.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Artwork</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Add personality to your entryway by displaying lovely artwork. Choose ones that give a positive vibe to make the entrance calmer and inviting to people coming inside. You can also put a shelf or a small table underneath to give it a more homey vibe (given that you have a space for it). Avoid displaying personal objects like family pictures on your entryway. It's because this area is more public and easily seen from the outside, just a simple reminder to protect your privacy.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Elements</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also activate elements if you want to enhance a specific area in your life. Each sector represents a particular life area like wealth (southeast), fame/recognition (south), career (north), and so on. You can activate these energies by knowing the sector of your house's entrance and putting in the assigned element.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For example, if your entrance is facing north, it corresponds to your career. The north direction's governing element is water, so you can put a small fountain, an aquarium, or artworks that feature water to activate your career energy.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Plants</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"sizeSlug":"large"} --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Incorporating plants into an area makes it a lot more vibrant and lively in an instant. You can also use plants as a barrier or protection from negative energies coming from outside or inauspicious views that can't be avoided. However, you must ensure that you choose the right kind of indoor plants and practice due diligence to maintain and nourish them.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Have a shoe rack</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you're the type who leaves shoes on your front door, it's best if you have a shoe rack or a cabinet where you can keep them. Never leave your shoes scattered near your front door as it is considered inauspicious.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Rugs</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Putting a welcoming rug or doormat on your front door is an excellent addition to your front door. It can give off an inviting feel instantly to the environment. Make sure your rug is low enough and allows the main door to open and close freely. You should also replace your rug or doormat with a new one at least once a year. Replacing the doormat will remove the accumulated negative Chi over the year.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can choose the color and material of the rug based on your door’s facing direction. Here are some ideas you can use:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Rug/doormat ideas based on your facing direction</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Direction</strong></td>
<td><strong>Element</strong></td>
<td><strong>Color</strong></td>
<td><strong>Shape</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>North</td>
<td>Water</td>
<td>Blue, Black</td>
<td>Round or wavy</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>South</td>
<td>Fire</td>
<td>Red, Purple, Orange</td>
<td>Angular shapes - triangles/stars</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>West / Northwest</td>
<td>Metal</td>
<td>White, Gray</td>
<td>Square or round</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>East / Southeast</td>
<td>Wood</td>
<td>Green, Brown</td>
<td>Rectangle</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Southwest / Northeast</td>
<td>Earth</td>
<td>Yellow</td>
<td>Square</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p><!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #4: Choose the right sector color</h1>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/DagHEZCrebB63SKOTiyiIkJIR9tSxPjxXGl8KOVPb4PzSwnM9zNZwDIpChjH7te37i7-zsZEvrkUEzy7yyviKOutO0PmcC1k-E3tKJtiYpXHk_sq02CiSzH5KYHLD0XhdL3rIBwD" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is DagHEZCrebB63SKOTiyiIkJIR9tSxPjxXGl8KOVPb4PzSwnM9zNZwDIpChjH7te37i7-zsZEvrkUEzy7yyviKOutO0PmcC1k-E3tKJtiYpXHk_sq02CiSzH5KYHLD0XhdL3rIBwD"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Choosing the right colors is essential in Feng Shui. Having the right color in this sector can help enhance or elevate the positive energy that enters our home. Similarly, choosing the wrong colors can result in inauspicious energy, which is a big no-no.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can determine the right color for your entryway and front door by knowing your house's facing direction. You can do this by <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/how-to-use-a-feng-shui-compass/">using a Feng Shui compass</a> or an ordinary compass. Knowing your facing direction will help you determine the element that corresponds to your path. Thus, helping you select the color based on that element. Here are some of the perfect colors to use per direction.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>East </strong>- Green, Brown, Black, Blue, Purple</li>
<li><strong>Northeast </strong>- light Yellow, Beige, Clay, Red, Pink, Orange, Magenta, Coral</li>
<li><strong>North </strong>- Black, Blue, White, Gray, Metallic</li>
<li><strong>Northwest </strong>- Gray, White, Metallic, Clay, Beige, Light Yellow</li>
<li><strong>West </strong>- White, Gray, Metallic, Light Yellow, Beige, Clay</li>
<li><strong>Southwest</strong> - Beige, Clay, Light Yellow, Red, Pink, Orage, Magenta, Coral</li>
<li><strong>South</strong> - Yellow, Orange Pink, Coral, Magenta, Purple, Green, Brown</li>
<li><strong>Southeast</strong> - Green, Brown, Black, Blue, Light Yellow</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #5: Avoid Feng Shui mistakes that could drain your money from your home</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Activating your entryway to attract better chi inside your home could result in many positive things. But when you do it wrong, you might also break the right flow of chi, causing an unwanted imbalance in your home. Some mistakes could even result in financial problems, making money drain faster from your home.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here are some common Feng Shui mistakes to avoid if you don't want to encounter this problem.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>BAD: The fireplace is visible from the front door</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Having your fireplace visible from the front door or directly in-line with the front door is inauspicious in Feng Shui. It means you're burning through money from the fireplace.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>BAD: The toilet is visible from the front door</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/A3m0SwNU7zX2VsHg22vJ4QRtWs0KHi5s8NfpCYm2X0C1FBHHNSktZli7DoWjy8gzZU22z82Wr7kjsEzljCr3neRzOejV5185dNYZsld0GvOnkZNUmx7f8kXcdlkmJD3rc1kFuQoU" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is A3m0SwNU7zX2VsHg22vJ4QRtWs0KHi5s8NfpCYm2X0C1FBHHNSktZli7DoWjy8gzZU22z82Wr7kjsEzljCr3neRzOejV5185dNYZsld0GvOnkZNUmx7f8kXcdlkmJD3rc1kFuQoU"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Having a visible view of the toilet from your front door is also considered inauspicious and can cause money loss in Feng Shui. The money will fail to accrue if this happens. You can fix this by putting a standing screen, a plant, or any object that could block the view of the toilet view so that the chi won't flow right through.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The same thing could happen if you have a second floor and the toilet is directly above your entryway. In case you have this at home, you can keep the entryway light on to help lift the wealth and income chi at your front door.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>BAD: The backdoor is directly in-line with the front door</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In Feng Shui, one of the most common ways to lose wealth and money is when your house has a poison arrow. A poison arrow is used in Feng Shui to describe when your front door is in-line with the back door or a window. Poison arrows may cause your money to drain quickly, so it's best to avoid this mistake.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>But if you encounter this mishap at home, you can also fix it by blocking the back door or window view using a standing screen, curtain, plant, etc.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #6: Use mirrors strategically</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>People often use mirrors to make spaces look bigger by reflecting surfaces and light. Mirrors are good decor in Feng Shui as it reflects and doubles the energy in an area. But remember that mirrors don't reflect selectively, it reflects everything - both positive and negative. You can place mirrors on your entryway but make sure that it's not reflecting your front door. It will result in the energy bouncing back out when it enters, pushing the chi energy and wealth away.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Place it somewhere that doesn't reflect your front door, sharp edges, or any other door. You should also check other mirrors in your house and make sure they don't reflect your main entrance at any angle.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #7: Check your stairs</h1>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/XDOYRjMJJCsgFryIhHLttys-DHkoxu-dsQg95EZyA00A9F-j6IB9wyfNIsUe6kkvJTLRTsVptMG0Tf5tmObJmn7kqpxqFgcxWeMLFsR75GO5F0ZtSJ7-ywuBcQWeZlweDU2ZBdng" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is XDOYRjMJJCsgFryIhHLttys-DHkoxu-dsQg95EZyA00A9F-j6IB9wyfNIsUe6kkvJTLRTsVptMG0Tf5tmObJmn7kqpxqFgcxWeMLFsR75GO5F0ZtSJ7-ywuBcQWeZlweDU2ZBdng"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Having your <a href="https://www.nst.com.my/property/2018/07/392311/feng-shui-stairway-rules-balance-energy" class="rank-math-link">staircase facing the front door directly</a> isn't a good sign in Feng Shui. If your staircase is right in front of the main entrance, it could result in the energy rushing quickly upstairs or downstairs and not going onto the main floor. It will leave the main floor empty of the positive chi energy it's supposed to have.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In case you have this problem, you can still fix it by placing proper decor and furniture onto your entryway. Use decors that could slow down the energy and guide it to the areas that need positive energy. You can use artwork, plants, mirrors, and other items appropriate for your wealth corner.  </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #8: You can apply Feng Shui on tiny entryways too</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you're living in a small apartment or studio type room where there's not much space from the front door, no worries, you can still apply Feng Shui on your entryway. You can do any of the Feng Shui tips mentioned above, even just one or two.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>And the most important thing is to keep your entryway clean. Remove shoes, clothes, and other unnecessary objects near your front door. Keep it clean and free of clutter so the chi energy can enter freely.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Bonus tips!</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Tip #9: Give your front door some love</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Aside from your entryway, the front door itself plays a significant part in good home Feng Shui. It's a big part of the entire entrance, so it has a substantial impact on the flow of energy that enters your home. With that said, it's worth giving your front door a bit of attention and take a look at it from time to time. Here's what you should do:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Check the doorknob and the locks. Make sure they are working fine.</li>
<li>Check for chips and cracks. Try and fix them if possible.</li>
<li>Choose a solid and sturdy wooden door. Try to avoid having windows on your door. Having a solid wooden door will give you a better sense of security too.</li>
<li>The front door or main door should be the biggest door in your home (some even use double doors). However, make sure that it's the right size and is proportional to your home.  </li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Tip #10: Keep everything clean!</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This tip is mostly a given. Just like any other area in your house, always keep your entryway clean and clutter-free! Although some people like putting things near the front door for easy access, make sure you'll organize these things properly and not just leave them scattered around the area. Here are some things you can do.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li> Don't leave shoes near or right at your front door. It's considered inauspicious in Feng Shui and viewed as clutter. If you want to have your shoes near your entryway, make sure they are kept inside a shoe cabinet, shoe rack, or any other closed cabinet. This trick will keep your entrance tidy and free of unsightly messy footwear.</li>
<li>Don't put too much stuff on your entryway. You don't have to put furniture or cabinets if it's not necessary. Keep your foyer or entryway clean and spacious as much as possible. Remove obstructions and clear the pathway so the auspicious chi energy can come in freely and spread further and deeper into your home.</li>
<li>For those who have bigger entryways, put a console table in it. You can place your purse, keys, and other items you'd want for an easy grab on your way out. Again, it's essential to keep things well-organized.  </li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Time to Feng Shui <em>your</em> Entryway!</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Paying attention to details is what will make your Feng Shui entryway even better. By following these tips, you'll have pretty much everything covered. Just make sure not to overdo all of these and prioritize what will make your home feel comfortable.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Enhancing the Feng Shui in your entryway will attract and encourage the positive chi energy to enter your home. Combine this with other Feng Shui principles, and the auspicious energy will eventually spread throughout the different rooms and enhance all sectors in your humble abode.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>15 Easy Ways To Make A Small Bedroom Look Bigger</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.luckycathome.com/15-easy-ways-to-make-a-small-bedroom-look-bigger/"/>
        <id>https://www.luckycathome.com/15-easy-ways-to-make-a-small-bedroom-look-bigger/</id>

        <updated>2022-08-29T20:08:30-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    If you're struggling with having a small bedroom, you're not alone. Having a small bedroom is one of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/ZjgzVYKpq82MtxAgsU9XzQuJrUKLpd4bfka8-RVTfhopZ19-R88khvXyEWys7hV4N9yK77t4X37vp3BB9GMbbUvfzknK-EVnPqLq0MKgD6uSMy9ogyqeu8p5j763sCSEyKj4c4v_" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is ZjgzVYKpq82MtxAgsU9XzQuJrUKLpd4bfka8-RVTfhopZ19-R88khvXyEWys7hV4N9yK77t4X37vp3BB9GMbbUvfzknK-EVnPqLq0MKgD6uSMy9ogyqeu8p5j763sCSEyKj4c4v_"></p>
<p>If you're struggling with having a small bedroom, you're not alone. Having a small bedroom is one of the most common issues with decorating. It's a challenge because there are lots of essential furniture you'd want to put inside.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Remodeling and adding some actual space in your bedroom needs too much work (and money). Luckily, there are some cost-effective and easy tricks you can do to make your small bedroom look and feel larger. You can reasonably do these yourself - no need to take down walls and remodel.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To give you some useful ideas, here are a few tips on how to make your small bedroom look bigger. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What colors make a small room look bigger?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Colors play an essential role in any space. Putting the right colors on your walls can actually help make your bedroom appear larger. Here are some points to consider when choosing a paint color for your bedroom walls.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Use light colors on your walls</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/1L4Pb3MYvDdw0eXDO3FqTREzrnkKnvk84ZApIAjT9kfowbRnsupAAgGGjjPyY-jxEHX1sZEPKwMKhsBiAmEyRSNuxNLCEgY7zgek_OxD33W_ZoYIf7VGh243LlbJQQNY80NQeAEl" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 1L4Pb3MYvDdw0eXDO3FqTREzrnkKnvk84ZApIAjT9kfowbRnsupAAgGGjjPyY-jxEHX1sZEPKwMKhsBiAmEyRSNuxNLCEgY7zgek_OxD33W_ZoYIf7VGh243LlbJQQNY80NQeAEl"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Lighter colors like white, cream, pastel colors, and others can reflect light. This will make a room seem brighter, airier, and roomier. Meanwhile, dark colors absorb light. Painting your walls with dark colors will make it feel smaller and more constricting. It's best to stick to light colors if you want to make your room look bigger.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also use wallpaper with horizontal or vertical stripes. These patterns create the illusion of height or width.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>2. Use a lighter color for your trim</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Painting your trim with a slightly lighter color than your walls creates an optical illusion making your walls appear farther back. This can help make your bedroom seem larger. You can paint your door frames, wall trims, even your ceiling a lighter color to create depth. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Use monochromatic paint</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/HV3mfPzMHomXOJyOKYVuI77c-vSopIlKqpxtvyxyv4wOVuY3K_scqDK-doOtcDiGuu34zlA1S5lxPnS_pT5fRJNRQLBwcam5F0RMY0J2rBOb-Zrjp4uahd728McxgXmCg8zNK_lz" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is HV3mfPzMHomXOJyOKYVuI77c-vSopIlKqpxtvyxyv4wOVuY3K_scqDK-doOtcDiGuu34zlA1S5lxPnS_pT5fRJNRQLBwcam5F0RMY0J2rBOb-Zrjp4uahd728McxgXmCg8zNK_lz"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Coordination is also necessary when choosing colors for your room. Painting your bedroom with different or opposing colors will segment off portions when viewing, making it feel smaller. You should opt for monochromatic paint colors throughout your room to create fluidity and space. Try picking a light color and use different shades of it instead of using different colors.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How do I arrange my small bedroom?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Choosing the right furniture and arrangement also matters when setting up your bedroom to be bigger. Remember that you should only put in what's really necessary and try to be creative when choosing your furniture.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>4. Don't put too much furniture</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Bedside tables are good to have, but using two of them isn't necessary if you have a small room. Instead of using pairs of furniture like bedside tables, or a two-seater couch, opt for using just one. Using less furniture vacates more space, thus, making your room seem much bigger. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You should also avoid tall furniture as it can make the ceiling seem lower than it actually is. Another positioning you can do is to place your furniture against the wall or at an angle. Putting it at an angle leads the eye through a longer diagonal distance rather than the shorter wall. You'll also often get some additional storage space behind a diagonally-positioned piece in the corner as a bonus.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>5. Use space-saving furniture</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/atbdl8tXYAWNH3fLj12MGjA1eKZfmzRd7hGPMg9_7HKUWhQtWdB6LGf8zXxJQAfRCTwUcd3pK52dNDLMtG1Hdlt8N-8yiCkPytw3Xnvu6igEUGFMdDbGZ59eXJqy7rteQRxvd83j" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is atbdl8tXYAWNH3fLj12MGjA1eKZfmzRd7hGPMg9_7HKUWhQtWdB6LGf8zXxJQAfRCTwUcd3pK52dNDLMtG1Hdlt8N-8yiCkPytw3Xnvu6igEUGFMdDbGZ59eXJqy7rteQRxvd83j"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Just from the name itself, space-saving furniture allows you to save more space and create more room inside your bedroom. One popular trend in space-saving is using a raised bed.  It almost looks like a double-deck or bunk bed, but the lower part is made into a study area or a closet. If you're not into that, you can also try using a bed with a built-in storage underneath. It will allow you to store more stuff without having to get another cabinet or drawer for it.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also try folding beds. There are ones which transform into a sofa when you fold them. You can just tuck your bed away when not in use, making more space for you to move around your bedroom. There are tons of space-saving and double-purpose furniture in the market. Some stools double as storage bins, folding tables, folding chairs, etc. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>6. Use furniture that has legs</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>"Floor gang" is a trend. But if you want to make a more spacious illusion in your bedroom, choose furniture that has legs. Lifted furniture creates an airy and open feel in the bedroom, making it look bigger. But make sure to keep the area underneath clean and organized. Not everything needs to be legged, but try to have at least one piece with some height.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>7. Use transparent furniture</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/8t0cC5Jk43BgTLkHHJ4xuZBUHFmnPJV7InxWyRB5MXVzlYYCeJTtxRHR8vh6ePuZrvHbbfJD3y1Mrb2V4mQiLU6Nw8zg6brO5xh92RNiro0zp4ClqOzWU_QXUOlBLGOwt0zg0H0v" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 8t0cC5Jk43BgTLkHHJ4xuZBUHFmnPJV7InxWyRB5MXVzlYYCeJTtxRHR8vh6ePuZrvHbbfJD3y1Mrb2V4mQiLU6Nw8zg6brO5xh92RNiro0zp4ClqOzWU_QXUOlBLGOwt0zg0H0v"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Instead of using wooden chairs or desks, try using transparent furniture. Although it still takes up the same amount of space, it can trick your eyes into feeling like it's not. Try using glass-top desks and pair it with acrylic or lucite chairs. This will give you a study area that has a minimal visual impact, thus making it appear like there's a lot of space in your bedroom.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>8. Make built-in shelving around your headboard</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/5U_u9dx9mqeBLlfXaau1yEGYsh-NYuphYs9shY1LEzJ-l6QEuthfRxmG05dc1c3jriV_JCARtIDFgkrSiESKDaCKIxLecH3DW_y8IP2Myy6nZ1lllP2cI-36seKTXec1IPo2DZac" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 5U_u9dx9mqeBLlfXaau1yEGYsh-NYuphYs9shY1LEzJ-l6QEuthfRxmG05dc1c3jriV_JCARtIDFgkrSiESKDaCKIxLecH3DW_y8IP2Myy6nZ1lllP2cI-36seKTXec1IPo2DZac"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Built-in shelving can function as a good storage space. Having some of it above, beside, or even around your headboard will save you the unnecessary drawers. Shelving beside your bed can also double as a bedside table. This will save you space and creates an illusion of depth in the wall, making the small room feel bigger.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How do I decorate my room to make it look bigger?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Using the right decor also makes a big difference when it comes to the appearance of your bedroom. Like your furniture, the fewer, the better. Less is more. Make sure it's on the right scale as your bedroom and avoid overly huge decors. Here are some useful decorating tips you can follow for your bedroom.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>9. Have a full-length mirror</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A small bedroom should have a full-length mirror. Using mirrors is the easiest way to trick the eyes into thinking a room is bigger than it is. Mirrors not only reflect light, but it can also create depth or height, especially a cleverly angled mirror. It's not only a nice decor, but it's also useful for checking your outfit from head to toe.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>10. Hang Ceiling-to-Floor Curtains</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/b7bKOxcBpNUDJf7cfSm9IogFPyhoiRpD2COZe608Ul00UAdFtyL0MU97TdN4awhkEAloNoiiAWUhqfaIq00GHCav3tSVDn0biyHUJwCzBzkmivolywru79i9yPqaJqhZOr_ibCYX" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is b7bKOxcBpNUDJf7cfSm9IogFPyhoiRpD2COZe608Ul00UAdFtyL0MU97TdN4awhkEAloNoiiAWUhqfaIq00GHCav3tSVDn0biyHUJwCzBzkmivolywru79i9yPqaJqhZOr_ibCYX"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For curtains, use a ceiling-to-floor type of curtain as they can make a space seem taller. Go for simple cotton or linen curtains that go well with your walls and avoid heavy drapes. You should also remember not to let the ends of the curtain touch your floor as this can disrupt the room's flow.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A simple solution is to tie them up or choose a curtain that is a few inches shorter. If there is a constraint in space, you can opt for blinds that are sleek in appearance.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>11. Keep your beddings simple</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A clean and simple look will make your room feel more spacious. You should also apply this to your beddings. Avoid heavy patterns for the pillows, bedspread, and throw cushions. Try to coordinate the colors and shapes of your bedding with your curtains to match the room's flow.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>12. Keep It Simple</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/CYd8mPZz6gAEu3mTLn_OTeHyYPoZsHhNSC95cXuavZS0fXbRyyBKZ1jZhC-xWU2Ut4OK8kWkQWr91psqzyjFptSXTFRYhjcWK8m3cQikHVOREWDtCui6YWtJxBaM9Xd8LNWzV2cO" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is CYd8mPZz6gAEu3mTLn_OTeHyYPoZsHhNSC95cXuavZS0fXbRyyBKZ1jZhC-xWU2Ut4OK8kWkQWr91psqzyjFptSXTFRYhjcWK8m3cQikHVOREWDtCui6YWtJxBaM9Xd8LNWzV2cO"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>While it's easy to place decors in your bedroom, having so many unnecessary decorations in your room will just make it look clumped and cluttered. If you want to make your room appear bigger, keep everything simple. The only essentials you need are a small lamp, a lovely plant, and a few pictures. That'll be enough.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>13. Maximize lighting</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A well-lit room makes a big difference compared to a dark one. Try to maximize the flow of natural light inside your room during the daytime. It can open up the interior and make the room look larger. If you don't get too much daylight, try using different lighting fixtures to bring some light inside.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>14. Use wall-mounted lamps by the bed</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/eH4HMY5ENgIqfjtlZTM1cKdvy8bZ-Kpxu4zDWdHqywwB0_neTTqjteeKSHHs76VLTr6OJmMjMsyMLTkxUzS3jtHPeNcOUIDlWU9sYu0w3plCbhDe4Tp-GSrr1UdadvfN6beWNOVS" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is eH4HMY5ENgIqfjtlZTM1cKdvy8bZ-Kpxu4zDWdHqywwB0_neTTqjteeKSHHs76VLTr6OJmMjMsyMLTkxUzS3jtHPeNcOUIDlWU9sYu0w3plCbhDe4Tp-GSrr1UdadvfN6beWNOVS"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Instead of using a bedside lamp, you can use wall-mounted lights and place them slightly beside your headboard and a bit higher than your bed. This draws the eye upward and helps give the room an open, airy look. It also reduces the visual clutter around your bed. Choose adjustable lamps as they are perfect for reading during the night.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>15. Clear all the clutter</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Last, but is no doubt, the most important tip is to clear your room from clutter. If you want a bigger space, you should try making more space by clearing out unnecessary things inside your bedroom. A well-organized, clutter-free, and minimalist bedroom looks visually bigger than how it actually is. Do cleaning and decluttering a habitually and avoid overcrowding your space.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Transform your bedroom and open more spaces</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Keeping your room clean and organized can already make a significant change. But if you still feel like your bedroom is constricted and small, you can follow the tips we've given above. You don't need to change or entirely remodel your room. A few changes and the elimination of unnecessary stuff will do. I hope this guide is useful for your bedroom. Which of these tips will you try?</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Feng Shui Office: Transforming your Workspace for Better Productivity</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.luckycathome.com/feng-shui-office-transforming-your-workspace-for-better-productivity/"/>
        <id>https://www.luckycathome.com/feng-shui-office-transforming-your-workspace-for-better-productivity/</id>

        <updated>2022-08-29T20:16:17-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Work can get pretty stressful at times, but you don't have to let your workspace contribute to that.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/ItVZCEe91J04_4ako4DRAItxeySAkPuOLETDUGKrnSj9teEyihKDrC4ce1ru5pGBCFOMzZLttd7ArKYtizLZDahjtWmCLbgScMf-75j-6cFb_fN6srcBQ-n3jeB5K1B_8j7HvSsP" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is ItVZCEe91J04_4ako4DRAItxeySAkPuOLETDUGKrnSj9teEyihKDrC4ce1ru5pGBCFOMzZLttd7ArKYtizLZDahjtWmCLbgScMf-75j-6cFb_fN6srcBQ-n3jeB5K1B_8j7HvSsP"></p>
<p>Work can get pretty stressful at times, but you don't have to let your workspace contribute to that. Having a vibrant, well-arranged office can actually help become more productive. And you can achieve more with that with the help of Feng Shui.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you want to transform your office to achieve a more stress-free and productive environment, here are some useful tips on how to change and Feng Shui your office for better productivity.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How to feng shui your office?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Many people mistake <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/index.php/2020/08/12/feng-shui-basics-attracting-positive-energy-into-your-home/">Feng Shui</a> for a "Chinese" style of decorating. Although the practice of Feng Shui involves decoration, it's not just about that. Feng Shui is more of the science and art of attracting positive energy (chi) into your space, making it more pleasant and positive for you overall.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can apply Feng Shui in almost any space, and that includes your office. There are a lot of ways to Feng Shui in an office. It still largely depends on your personality and preference as the occupant. However, there are essential points on how and where to apply Feng Shui they are:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Your office layout</li>
<li>Your desk's position</li>
<li>Your office decor</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>We will elaborate more on these points later. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Feng Shui Office Bagua map</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The Feng Shui Bagua (also known as pakua) is one of the primary tools used in Feng Shui. You can use the Bagua to analyze the energy of a space, be it at home, garden, or office. The Bagua serves as the Feng Shui energy map of your space and shows you which areas of your space are connected to certain areas of your life.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>How to map your office using a Bagua</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/eL3TVtW70sNjMOGm84bKzKuzAi-f_pUeFbEVQqcHCPAUSNBb89adUMk8aLu9SloXy2nGl7UN5GE2XAth90W2NSPxfaqAp0a8MKINGYv5DfgIR_oVxcyOYYZ5fLnK_UAqggCQf6-w" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is eL3TVtW70sNjMOGm84bKzKuzAi-f_pUeFbEVQqcHCPAUSNBb89adUMk8aLu9SloXy2nGl7UN5GE2XAth90W2NSPxfaqAp0a8MKINGYv5DfgIR_oVxcyOYYZ5fLnK_UAqggCQf6-w"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The traditional Bagua has nine sides. Each side corresponds to a specific area of your life which include:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Abundance and prosperity</li>
<li>Fame and reputation</li>
<li>Love and relationship</li>
<li>Family and community</li>
<li>Health</li>
<li>Creativity and children</li>
<li>Wisdom</li>
<li>Career life and purpose</li>
<li>Helpful people and travel</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To map out your office, you may need to use a <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/index.php/2020/08/12/how-to-use-a-feng-shui-compass/">compass</a> to know the right-facing direction of your office. Knowing what direction will help you align the side of the Bagua properly.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>After mapping out the sections, you should ask yourself which parts of your life and/or business you'd want to focus on. For example, you'd want to enhance your career. You can locate where the career section is in the Bagua, and you may want to put an item that could help amplify the energy in that area.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Which direction should your office desk face?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Like what we mentioned earlier, the position of your desk is a vital part of practicing Feng Shui in your office. Here's how you can position your desk the right way.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Place your desk in a command position.</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The command position is where your desk is facing the doorway. You should be able to see who's coming in and out of your office. You can put your desk vertically, horizontally, or diagonally depending on your space.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/KhEgr9Nt7YHZi_kiCVEUrtKyL-EEeoyTzr65ee2QfBqnnqBniHbz2S39sIVux-7YSvzXv3HVl-wbz9_SgrHh_1bt7z76qgGSQvSxduPEXhZyiLXKg4UnRR0Slt3n-MJV5IorAiGx" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is KhEgr9Nt7YHZi_kiCVEUrtKyL-EEeoyTzr65ee2QfBqnnqBniHbz2S39sIVux-7YSvzXv3HVl-wbz9_SgrHh_1bt7z76qgGSQvSxduPEXhZyiLXKg4UnRR0Slt3n-MJV5IorAiGx"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>But keep in mind that your desk shouldn't be directly in line with the door. You should be able to see the door, but it shouldn't be directly in front of you. This could give off negative energy which you wouldn't want in your office.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>2. Desk facing wall</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This is the position you should avoid when positioning your desk. A desk that facing a wall has an inherent bad energy flow in Feng Shui. It also symbolizes obstacles, which get in the way of your productivity. Moreover, it can make you feel less motivated and less inspired because there's no beautiful view in front of you.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Back against a window</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Another position to avoid is having a window against your back. This also promotes negative energy flow in Feng Shui. Having your back against a window could mean that negative energy would stab you in the back.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>4. Back against a wall</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In Feng Shui, you should always have something solid and stable behind you. And a wall is a perfect example. This will provide you with stability, which is the best for career support. If you can't put your desk chair against a wall, you can also use office chairs with high backrest.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>5. Face your lucky direction</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also use your lucky direction to position your desk. You can determine this by finding your Kua number. You can use this <a href="https://www.wofs.com/kua-number-calculator/">Kua calculator</a> to find your Kua number.</p>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/iX6Zm5kkZEZB5IEFPvNGJv4ixrw5Zx2gzDQnHfj-9JQwgxyJ8leHatOgHOr8y9TclXhOqXvZAethMBkY4jJi-poFOBmwObGYGddCIBX8zCcd71wbLK9bDmIajgcwl34nAjOIYAtt" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is iX6Zm5kkZEZB5IEFPvNGJv4ixrw5Zx2gzDQnHfj-9JQwgxyJ8leHatOgHOr8y9TclXhOqXvZAethMBkY4jJi-poFOBmwObGYGddCIBX8zCcd71wbLK9bDmIajgcwl34nAjOIYAtt"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.luckycathome.com/media/posts/15/iX6Zm5kkZEZB5IEFPvNGJv4ixrw5Zx2gzDQnHfj-9JQwgxyJ8leHatOgHOr8y9TclXhOqXvZAethMBkY4jJi-poFOBmwObGYGddCIBX8zCcd71wbLK9bDmIajgcwl34nAjOIYAtt" alt=""></figure>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>North, East, South, and Southeast are good for those who have Kua numbers 9, 4, 3, and 1</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>West, Northeast, Northwest, and Southwest are good for those who have Kua numbers 8, 7, 6, and 2</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For those who have Kua number 5, it is the same as Kua number 2 for males and Kua number 8 for females.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also utilize your Kua number to determine your lucky <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/index.php/2020/08/12/what-is-my-feng-shui-element/">element</a>, which you can use to decorate your office. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>6. Choose the right desk</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Aside from choosing the right position, selecting the right desk is also essential. Choose one that has enough space for all your essentials. A rectangular one (with rounded edges) is good. You can also go for a curved desk, but make sure you're sitting inside the curve, so the positive energy will towards you.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Don't choose brightly colored desks, too, as it could make you feel restless and uneasy.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How to arrange Feng Shui office furniture?</h1>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-N-D4cPDTZJWW7xc7cVArP7TZa1hgEPLSBmpfiRmYr8XA6X9DpY8eWlUv7hgd6Yt9dydiGYD1Pr4ihfqpsw-beyudK4jsNTxCo70dToLWpoPk3GqbAgWq0Nj7H4-6MEyALDBXN3c" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is -N-D4cPDTZJWW7xc7cVArP7TZa1hgEPLSBmpfiRmYr8XA6X9DpY8eWlUv7hgd6Yt9dydiGYD1Pr4ihfqpsw-beyudK4jsNTxCo70dToLWpoPk3GqbAgWq0Nj7H4-6MEyALDBXN3c"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>We've talked about the proper placement of the main furniture in your office, which is your desk. So how should you lay out the rest of the items in your office? Here are some tips.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>If you're sitting in a cubicle, place a mirror on your desk to see anyone coming up behind you.</li>
<li>Use a round or oval table in conference rooms to attract auspicious chi energy to move around the room.</li>
<li>Arrange your storage spaces and avoid storing clutter in them.</li>
<li>Put out updated magazines and replace worn or tattered reading materials on your receiving area.</li>
<li>If you don't have a receiving area, put plants and lighting on your doorway to make the space more inviting.</li>
<li>Avoid sharp corners when choosing furniture.</li>
<li>Avoid sharp edges pointing at you.</li>
<li>Avoid sitting below a beam.</li>
<li>Put some pictures of your loved one(s)/family on your desk.</li>
<li>Place the things you need on easy reach.</li>
<li> Keep only your daily items on your desk.</li>
<li>Avoid overcrowded bookshelves.</li>
<li>Use pieces that reflect your personality.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What is the best feng shui color for an office?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In Feng Shui, every color has a different meaning and attracts different energies. In an office setting, these are the highly-suggested colors you can use:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Green - improves health and balance</li>
<li>Yellow - attracts happiness and good times </li>
<li>White - brings creative energy </li>
<li>Blue - supports career success and growth</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you want to destress, you can add some earthy tones like browns, light grey, etc.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you want to attract more energy that could drive you up during the day, you can add vibrant colors like orange, red, and bright yellow. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What plants are best for office Feng Shui?</h1>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/3I-9pMLPoYjvW96cYjgqgtHSYIs8cl3Yb2vE6RhNGYqmcUCm-LHtF2l6u9QVBLKYo1gKLSSPtN1Xb9WrMgeGU7uiIC7Fhwi6ZDhFNFf5-uMgt-pi4QMqq2koRgbpo2T9dNPM2XxD" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 3I-9pMLPoYjvW96cYjgqgtHSYIs8cl3Yb2vE6RhNGYqmcUCm-LHtF2l6u9QVBLKYo1gKLSSPtN1Xb9WrMgeGU7uiIC7Fhwi6ZDhFNFf5-uMgt-pi4QMqq2koRgbpo2T9dNPM2XxD"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Plants are both excellent and Feng Shui and good for your health, so placing one in your office is a must. Plants clean the air, making your environment more refreshing. Right plants can also bring you good luck.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here are some plants you can put in your office:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Areca palm</li>
<li>Reed’s palm</li>
<li>Dwarf date palm</li>
<li>Boston fern</li>
<li>Janet Craig dracaena</li>
<li>English ivy</li>
<li>Australian sword fern</li>
<li>Peace Lily</li>
<li>Rubber plant</li>
<li>Weeping fig</li>
<li>African violet</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Make sure to use living plants. Avoid dead and artificial plants as these could attract negative energy.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How do you create positive energy in an office?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/QxM1EH-j51lD2-vJO8OcboZQWjVpfym9BT_kHzfBQc6NQ7zIhdopZ868ZvV9OCkJCubKNIlUtFPdDiaCReMrUMYJEmnqID8TKwnZA1oqe83buNp9M6Olg1aLF89p28DKhKclcGk2" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is QxM1EH-j51lD2-vJO8OcboZQWjVpfym9BT_kHzfBQc6NQ7zIhdopZ868ZvV9OCkJCubKNIlUtFPdDiaCReMrUMYJEmnqID8TKwnZA1oqe83buNp9M6Olg1aLF89p28DKhKclcGk2"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>We've talked about proper table positioning, using the right colors, and adding some plants to create better Feng Shui in your office. Besides the above mentioned, you can also use decor and other fixtures to create positive energy in your workspace. Here are some additionals you should consider:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Keep your office clean and clutter-free, especially your desk and the floor.</li>
<li>Add some water features like a small fountain or aquarium in your office.</li>
<li>Use motivational quotes as decor on your walls.</li>
<li> Use aromatherapy and diffuse calming oils to create balance.</li>
<li>Dispose of and replace broken furniture, decor, lighting, etc.</li>
<li>Maximize your exposure to natural light.</li>
<li>Keep your office well lit and clean.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How to fix bad office Feng Shui?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can rearrange your office and replace items according to the best Feng Shui. Still, in some cases, you can't avoid certain contradictions like having your back against a window or a desk facing the wall.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You shouldn't put pressure on yourself too much with these conditions. Remember, the purpose of this is to make a positive and motivating environment for you to work on, so you should feel comfortable in your office.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/NZ7KtQhToLHeXEpQhJoDQn6YQYtCD7ZYq82bz7wXtldSSQ7Fmn1yhIqakcGB2O6pWFIJs7FKtdMtAHu_kxdjpVSWCyO_2zthX6uWzO-2AB51F_avhNzNySyAw7SscAeeDbfe1FKH" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is NZ7KtQhToLHeXEpQhJoDQn6YQYtCD7ZYq82bz7wXtldSSQ7Fmn1yhIqakcGB2O6pWFIJs7FKtdMtAHu_kxdjpVSWCyO_2zthX6uWzO-2AB51F_avhNzNySyAw7SscAeeDbfe1FKH"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can use 'cures' in unavoidable bad Feng Shui if you want to. Here are some useful ones you could look into.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Issue #1: Desk facing the wall</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Cure:</strong> Place a beautiful picture of an open and low area like a garden or bed of flowers.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Issue #2: Sitting below a beam</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Cure:</strong> Paint the beam the color of the ceiling or stencil it with "uplifting" design like clouds or birds in flight.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Issue #3: Sitting straightly in-line with the door</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Cure:</strong> Put a small bell or crystal near the door. You can also put a plant in between your desk and the door. This will help slow down the rushing energy.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Issue #4: No solid support behind you/sitting with a window behind  </h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Cure:</strong> You can put a picture of a mountain or a tortoise behind you. This will give you reliable support.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/2EyUfYO6Rila2kE6RGgJluVXXti20iJjSiDBNi_vfYRm-Bcjq2MhT01Dt7fBKI0HEex-dI41yhNASI6Bt83bgPCQwPDSnZwnEkjtEQoRvnR64vuhrt4kd7VPeTO-a02Q_LsmK-1g" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 2EyUfYO6Rila2kE6RGgJluVXXti20iJjSiDBNi_vfYRm-Bcjq2MhT01Dt7fBKI0HEex-dI41yhNASI6Bt83bgPCQwPDSnZwnEkjtEQoRvnR64vuhrt4kd7VPeTO-a02Q_LsmK-1g"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Issue #5: Sitting with a door behind you</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Cure:</strong> Put a small mirror on your desk or cubicle to help you see the door behind.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Bring in the positive vibes to your office!</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Every office has the potential to bring us to success, especially when it looks and feels motivating and positive. Aside from a positive outlook towards your goals, attracting positive energy into your workspace could also help.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>With a bit of help from the Feng Shui practice, you can surely transform your office into a more prosperous and productive space.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>5 Amazing Coffee Filter Crafts You Can Make at Home</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.luckycathome.com/5-amazing-coffee-filter-crafts-you-can-make-at-home/"/>
        <id>https://www.luckycathome.com/5-amazing-coffee-filter-crafts-you-can-make-at-home/</id>

        <updated>2022-08-29T20:17:50-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    What if we tell you that coffee filters are not just for coffee? You can actually make tons&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/qFbmG5kNOO1haPQ-ToJoiqse1yS1Fq_0Trg7IbsmOGOT3DfuLjmd8MAXJBd4wfLsRlAW3WvdB1mFeAalXV87DABgznpBbsPJ3ueucKjXy9USf8lTl0YfLCmTB8zjd3HD2liX4mIx" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is qFbmG5kNOO1haPQ-ToJoiqse1yS1Fq_0Trg7IbsmOGOT3DfuLjmd8MAXJBd4wfLsRlAW3WvdB1mFeAalXV87DABgznpBbsPJ3ueucKjXy9USf8lTl0YfLCmTB8zjd3HD2liX4mIx"></p>
<p>What if we tell you that coffee filters are not just for coffee? You can actually make tons of other exciting things using that piece of filter paper. This simple-shaped and lint-free designed paper can be helpful in lots of other ways, too. Read on, and we'll show you how.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What are some uses for coffee filters?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Aside from filtering the coffee in your coffee machine, coffee filters can also work as:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Plate liners</li>
<li>Window cleaners</li>
<li>Snack bowls</li>
<li>Oil-absorbing sheets</li>
<li>Popsicle drip catcher</li>
<li>AND MORE...</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Other than being an essential household item, coffee filters are also great for crafting. And you can make tons of crafting projects with it.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How do you use a coffee filter for crafts?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Crafting with coffee filters can be done in so many ways. You can cut them, stick them together, paint on them, make amazing decor with them. The list is endless. </p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/0ZOkloKUukZcpdqgLBoB1uoQiiSa9gG8rNyTzR7WvuGMOSZvFg4ZCaI4-5ezNnRueEmkH93-wKY4hZHN_UCMjWqMreaeKkwvhq2g7AbWUCKpoU3yhcP26nk8JIkM4PW-w_na1uuy" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 0ZOkloKUukZcpdqgLBoB1uoQiiSa9gG8rNyTzR7WvuGMOSZvFg4ZCaI4-5ezNnRueEmkH93-wKY4hZHN_UCMjWqMreaeKkwvhq2g7AbWUCKpoU3yhcP26nk8JIkM4PW-w_na1uuy"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you have a bunch of coffee filters lying around, here are 10 amazing coffee filter crafts you can make at home. The best part is, you can create and have fun with these crafting projects with your kids.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What crafts can you make with coffee filters?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here is the list of crafts you can make using coffee filters. They are easy and really fun to make. So bring out your coffee filters and let's start crafting!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Coffee filter butterfly </h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/Sm3AQ4b-8QHatWTRMCB65GsmTxaIKcZP41w1ChTAj4QFQ3yQz19-zOio-zrFCmN-_HvFshtLHwqHh-pP_G0v7CFX4fm2N8oK5xUgnAkG10AWoQ80bjPuOkZrAy2t13G4FUmx963p" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is Sm3AQ4b-8QHatWTRMCB65GsmTxaIKcZP41w1ChTAj4QFQ3yQz19-zOio-zrFCmN-_HvFshtLHwqHh-pP_G0v7CFX4fm2N8oK5xUgnAkG10AWoQ80bjPuOkZrAy2t13G4FUmx963p"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>These colorful coffee filter butterflies are great for spring decor. You can attach them on strings or stick them on a wall for that lively and colorful spring effect.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Materials:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>white coffee filters</li>
<li>watercolor paints</li>
<li>colored pipe cleaners or chenille stem</li>
<li>paintbrushes</li>
<li>water</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Procedure:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>1. Lay the coffee filter flat on a surface and paint them using the paintbrush and watercolor paints. Make sure to lay a newspaper or a paper plate on the surface before doing this. It's because the water from the watercolor might soak through. Once done, just set aside to dry.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>2. Once your coffee filters are dry, fold them in an accordion style, in about half an inch pleats.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>3. Fold one pipe cleaner in half and place the folded coffee filter in the middle of the fold. Center the coffee filter at the bend.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>4. Twist the open ends of the pipe cleaner around the coffee filter to secure it in place.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>5. bend or curl the open ends of the pipe cleaner to create the butterfly antenna.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>6. Fan out or spread the butterfly wings.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>7. You can attach it on a string or stick them on a wall. And you're done!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>2. Ocean Animal Suncatcher</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/u46YG86rn8n8drqkvk_5lciUjyueUu_ky0Xu649Vz9htq5f811jhbGCsthDn2SaqQfLQQXK0jJij3I7qc3w9z13T8gsntITZ3Ml7cVrsRwZyJseYeNGMQBQudBqm4mwXy7dMafGz" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is u46YG86rn8n8drqkvk_5lciUjyueUu_ky0Xu649Vz9htq5f811jhbGCsthDn2SaqQfLQQXK0jJij3I7qc3w9z13T8gsntITZ3Ml7cVrsRwZyJseYeNGMQBQudBqm4mwXy7dMafGz"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For a fun ocean-themed project, this ocean animal suncatchers are great for kids who love fishes and other water animals. You can stick them on your windows for a beautiful, colorful sunlight effect. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Materials:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Dark blue or black art paper </li>
<li>Watercolor paints</li>
<li>Paintbrush</li>
<li>Scissors</li>
<li>Glue</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Procedure:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>1. Paint your coffee filters using watercolor paint. You can paint in as many colors as you like. The more colorful, the better! Leave it to dry.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>2. Print or draw sea animals on the dark blue or black paper and cut them. Make sure your cut-outs are not larger than the coffee filters.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>3. Glue the animal cut-outs on the dried coffee filters.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>4. You can stick your finished project on the window to get hit by sunlight for a beautiful silhouette effect.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Peonies</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/njJT0x-9pINKwsc38iVxNSeijOOLPxhuhNjce-5RNQAbmLkixf69t8fj-rqOMUOPCxmoUMQvaDJcaC5YEsdl9i6m3h_SdkQmL4Cmy0wqT4ZEuep9Os92EgyExEb19kCLJA4gXFM4" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is njJT0x-9pINKwsc38iVxNSeijOOLPxhuhNjce-5RNQAbmLkixf69t8fj-rqOMUOPCxmoUMQvaDJcaC5YEsdl9i6m3h_SdkQmL4Cmy0wqT4ZEuep9Os92EgyExEb19kCLJA4gXFM4"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Aside from their beautiful appearance, Peony flowers are a symbol of prosperity, good fortune, a happy marriage, romance, compassion, and honor. You can actually make your own wilt-free peonies using coffee filters. Here's how:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Materials:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>White Coffee Filters (8 pcs. per flower)</li>
<li>Floral Wire</li>
<li>Floral Tape</li>
<li>Food Coloring</li>
<li>Scissors</li>
<li>Pencil or Pen</li>
<li>Bowl</li>
<li>Water</li>
<li>Glue or Hot Glue Gun</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Procedure:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>1. Fold your coffee filters in half. Continue folding them in half for three times more (you'll get around 16 petals). You can do 2 coffee filters at a time.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>2. When you get that cone shape, use the scissors to cut the open edge of your coffee filters to a more rounded edge.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>3. After cutting the edges, unravel the coffee filters.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>4. This is optional. You can make white peony flowers, but if you want colored peony flowers, you can dye them.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Put some water in the bowl and add a few drops of food color in it. You can put as many drops of food color as you want, depending on how deep you want the color to be. To test it out, try dipping a coffee filter and pull it out to see the color payoff.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>5. After mixing your dye solution, dip the coffee filters into the water and pull them out. Place them on a surface to dry.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>6. Cut your floral wire to 12-inch lengths. You can use two wires if you want a sturdy stem. Using a pencil, wrap one end of your wire several times into a coil. Then slide it off the pencil and press the loop together. This will be the center for your flower and a stopper, so your coffee filters won't slip through.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>7. Using the other end, poke the floral wire through the center of your first filter petal. Put some hot glue on the coil to hold the first petal in place (be careful with using hot glue). Twist the bottom of the coffee filter to secure it in place.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>8. Repeat step #7 until you have all 8 filter petals on the floral wire. Make sure to glue the last petal in place.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>9. Grab your floral tape and cut about a 12-inch to 16-inch strip. Wrap your floral wire using the tape, starting at the base of coffee filters. Use a dot of hot glue to stick the end of your floral tape.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Remember to pull on your floral tape slightly so it would stretch. This will also activate its stickiness.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>10. Wrap your wire by spinning your floral tape all the way down your floral wire to create your stem. You can wrap it all the way down and then back up again to make it more sturdy. Once you finish wrapping, it's done!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>11. You can create a couple of these and put them on a vase to display. You can also turn it to a bouquet.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>4. Coffee Filter Fall Leaf Garland</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ftT939o-musM8yN2Y-Eupqw9-J6Bg3uz1oUrP6RMfAFXDpp-V0XAGpDtzxPKVVqaC7SgmmAT47fp1r9oZzrq7WMV1Wxoolcq07D_QeNrxTOmx7QYH-m7r6JSTWE0UM5pqhnI-ssL" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is ftT939o-musM8yN2Y-Eupqw9-J6Bg3uz1oUrP6RMfAFXDpp-V0XAGpDtzxPKVVqaC7SgmmAT47fp1r9oZzrq7WMV1Wxoolcq07D_QeNrxTOmx7QYH-m7r6JSTWE0UM5pqhnI-ssL"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This leaf garland is a fantastic decor for the fall season. You can hang them on your windows, doors, or pretty much anywhere.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Materials:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Coffee filters</li>
<li>Red, yellow, orange, and brown markers</li>
<li>Red, yellow, and orange watercolor paint</li>
<li>Paintbrush</li>
<li>Hole punch</li>
<li>String</li>
<li>Scissors</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Procedure:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>1. Draw leaf shapes on your coffee filters using the red, yellow, and brown markers.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>2. Using the watercolor paints, paint on the leaves you drew on the coffee filters. The watercolor paint will mix and blend with the markers and make really colorful leaves. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>3. Repeat the procedure until you have a stack of painted leaves. Set aside to dry.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>4. Once the coffee filters are dry, cut out the leaves by following the outlines you drew earlier. Using a hole punch, place a hole on one end of the leaf for lacing.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>5. Cut a long strand of string and tie a knot on each leaf to secure them in place.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>6. Find a great spot to hang your finished garland, and you're done!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>5. Coffee Filter Wreath</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/PHuJyPZHO4U_SVvAgUDoFfBjsu6-mmFJ5tt-DlMipaTvo7YzQ_AHrRuDXbvPxkucZTTKdtqQ_4iteG21F3SyN-qIm0z-dXn17mY5I0TeiGk6Y_5pTXSwa5YhuFmwT8grYYKb8-2v" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is PHuJyPZHO4U_SVvAgUDoFfBjsu6-mmFJ5tt-DlMipaTvo7YzQ_AHrRuDXbvPxkucZTTKdtqQ_4iteG21F3SyN-qIm0z-dXn17mY5I0TeiGk6Y_5pTXSwa5YhuFmwT8grYYKb8-2v"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can use wreaths on almost any occasion. Depending on what color or theme your wreath is, you can always hang one on your door. Making a plain white wreath like this is great for any occasion. You can just attach any holiday-themed stems and wrap them around the wreath.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Materials:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Coffee Filters (150 pcs.)</li>
<li>Foam wreath form</li>
<li>Hot Glue Gun</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Procedure:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>1. Fold your coffee filter in half. Fold it and again to make it quarters.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>2. Loosely roll your folded filter paper to a cone shape.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>3. Pinch the tip of the cone to keep it closed. You can also dab a little hot glue on it to lock it in place.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>4. Repeat this process for about 100 times (You can do this while watching TV).</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>5. Take your foam wreath form and attack the filter papers to the back inside of the wreath.   </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>6. When there are filters around the circle, turn the foam over and push/fold the filters in to cover the inner part of the wreath.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>7. Do the same procedure but on the outer part of the wreath foam.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>8. Add two rows of filters in the middle part to cover the entire wreath foam. Don't forget to fluff the filters for a fuller effect.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>9. Tie a ribbon on one side for hanging, and it's done! </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>More coffee filter crafts</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here are some more fun and creative coffee filter crafts you can make at home.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://terryriciolidesigns.blogspot.com/2017/12/coffee-filter-angel.html">Coffee Filter Angel</a> - beautiful angel ornament that's unbelievably made from coffee filters.</li>
<li> <a href="http://craftsbyamanda.com/2010/12/coffee-filter-christmas-tree.html">Christmas Tree</a> - This small but adorable Christmas tree is great for tabletop decorations.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.lbrummer68739.net/3rd-grade-projects-gallery-2/coffee-filter-batik/">Batik Circles</a> - Kids will surely enjoy this fun and exciting project. They could show off their artistic skills with it too.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.thehappierhomemaker.com/2012/09/coffee-filter-pumpkins.html">Pumpkins</a> - Want some centerpiece for your tables on that pumpkin patch party, or maybe Halloween? Here's a cute one for you.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.classyclutter.net/diy-christmas-decor-coffee-filter/">JOY for Christmas</a> - Bring in more joy into your home by making this impressive lettering decor. You can create one for other parties too!</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Start crafting with coffee filters!</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Coffee filters are indeed a versatile item. You'll be surprised by how useful and crafty they really are. Which of these crafting projects will you try? Or maybe you're interested in other <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/index.php/2020/08/12/99-crafts-to-make-and-sell-for-money/">crafting projects you can sell</a>?</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Happy crafting!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to Soundproof a Bedroom: 8 DIY Tips That Actually Work</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.luckycathome.com/how-to-soundproof-a-bedroom-8-diy-tips-that-actually-work/"/>
        <id>https://www.luckycathome.com/how-to-soundproof-a-bedroom-8-diy-tips-that-actually-work/</id>

        <updated>2022-08-29T20:20:12-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Have you ever felt the struggle of just wanting to get to that 'sleep' mode, but you're suddenly&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/mkU-AtjWUuNTWO9LnB3d1Z0ZAMzsWDAttc0ioTGM0aV2bC02eIhN2fANqwfnzPTTy0s8_x5NcA2KCZVQfs0O-wCkI4ZEy7-hoezZDoyR3BsNPtjJoRFHp25Ac4I6oWvPr_G-o2dE" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is mkU-AtjWUuNTWO9LnB3d1Z0ZAMzsWDAttc0ioTGM0aV2bC02eIhN2fANqwfnzPTTy0s8_x5NcA2KCZVQfs0O-wCkI4ZEy7-hoezZDoyR3BsNPtjJoRFHp25Ac4I6oWvPr_G-o2dE"></p>
<p>Have you ever felt the struggle of just wanting to get to that 'sleep' mode, but you're suddenly interrupted by noisy, partying neighbors or honking car horns? Oh yeah, the anger. The frustration. Yes, I feel you (hugs).</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you're having trouble getting that calm and peaceful vibe in your bedroom because of external disturbances, like noise, maybe it's time to consider soundproofing your room. Here are some effective DIY tips on how you could soundproof your room.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What is soundproofing?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Soundproofing is a method of reducing or removing any unwanted noise from your house, office, and general vicinity. It is often achieved using insulative materials to reflect, suppress, diffuse, and absorb sounds or noises coming from a source.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are two types of noises you can encounter in terms of bedroom soundproofing - impact noise and airborne noise.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Impact noises</strong> are sounds created by an impact like footsteps, dropped heavy objects overhead, or crazy neighbors bouncing off the walls. <strong>Airborne noises</strong>, on the other hand, comes from honking car horns, car alarms, the sound of shouting drunken nightclubbers outside, or from a TV in the next room. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>These two are the noises you'd want to avoid or conceal with soundproofing.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Why should I soundproof my bedroom?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are actually many benefits to soundproofing your room. And among them are the following:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>You'll have a more quiet and peaceful environment.</li>
<li>It'll allow you to have a better sleep.</li>
<li>Provides more privacy</li>
<li>It will also allow you to make noises (even on late nights) without disturbing other people in the house or your neighbors.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The best part of this is, you can actually do it yourself without spending too much.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To sum it all up, soundproofing will make your room quieter and private while also allowing you to make (loud) noises without getting complaints from anyone. A total win-win, right?</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How to soundproof my bedroom?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Since we're talking about soundproofing your own bedroom, we'll focus on ways to soundproof from the INSIDE. To do that, we must first identify the main points that can make a place feel noisy.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Source of the sound</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"align":"center"} --></p>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/QpT6WUrzyphMZySaFE7A1nKMs1G9nEr0-f8aNH7wSIQbp_LVKPqpHETfUK1RCI2G-smIr5oMU9wC5giq6e8Xn-r9T3TVVNPhtHLIoCP4_bLO1wRepMn_ADDm3uoALz8s5D5o9dm8" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is QpT6WUrzyphMZySaFE7A1nKMs1G9nEr0-f8aNH7wSIQbp_LVKPqpHETfUK1RCI2G-smIr5oMU9wC5giq6e8Xn-r9T3TVVNPhtHLIoCP4_bLO1wRepMn_ADDm3uoALz8s5D5o9dm8"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.luckycathome.com/media/posts/13/QpT6WUrzyphMZySaFE7A1nKMs1G9nEr0-f8aNH7wSIQbp_LVKPqpHETfUK1RCI2G-smIr5oMU9wC5giq6e8Xn-r9T3TVVNPhtHLIoCP4_bLO1wRepMn_ADDm3uoALz8s5D5o9dm8" alt=""></figure>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You must first identify the potential sources of noise. If we're dealing with noises from your room, these could come from your TV or an instrument. If it's outside, this can come from different things like cars, animals, your neighbors.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Knowing the source will make it easier for you to contain the sound, especially when it's coming from a specific spot.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>2. Entry point</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The entry point is where the sound could enter to your room. These could be specific areas that are adjacent to the source of the sound like windows or doors. It could also be an entire wall, which is common on shared walls in condos, apartments, or duplexes.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Reflection point</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When the sound enters your room, it will bounce off to a surface known as the reflection point. Sounds bounce back at the same angle of entry. So if it enters a straight line, it will most likely bounce back as a straight line. Identifying the reflection points will help you strategize on where to put soundproofing materials better.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Effective ways to soundproof your bedroom</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Now, we will talk about different ways on how to effectively soundproof your bedroom. These are easy and affordable techniques that you can do yourself. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Seal your door</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Your door most likely has gaps around it, most commonly at the bottom, causing an air leak. Sounds travel through the air, so if it has air leak, sound can probably pass through the gaps.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can check this by standing inside your room with the door closed and the lights off. If you see some light shining through the edges of your door, it does have an air leak that sound can travel through.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/cz1fEmhISp1LvDc_p-fwuZAOyx5nIvZVqcrak13TLWgfgOh6MVHDltcgKhas2XilwU0AL_pcNJ_vt8NWPd_ylnYP69545J3weHfHBLgTDdaw32pkWpTL7DQXfF2unzyAVVksjQXS" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is cz1fEmhISp1LvDc_p-fwuZAOyx5nIvZVqcrak13TLWgfgOh6MVHDltcgKhas2XilwU0AL_pcNJ_vt8NWPd_ylnYP69545J3weHfHBLgTDdaw32pkWpTL7DQXfF2unzyAVVksjQXS"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To fix this, you can put a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mr-Rice-Adhesive-Stripping-Soundproof/dp/B072QDSJKT/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=soundproofxpert-20&amp;linkId=517436a041b629973cfb0b41996f6b71">door sweep</a> at the bottom of your door. These are cheap and do a petty good job at concealing gaps. You can also put some weather stripping seal tape around the edges of your door to better seal them. It's also highly suggested to have more solid wooden doors to make sound penetrate less.  </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>2. Seal your windows</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/BbWvBvKBWBVDMHm9l1qulc_47yX0_Z8D1RNGY9yEidD_sVTTH6fl10ojR1fV8RD28DDGhDuPmYf5gRCNLqdazQ6Hh65b5yu7YfUwsQxW0ENOGD9WZ_sfxEkK5oHGkC-gaO9Xxsx6" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is BbWvBvKBWBVDMHm9l1qulc_47yX0_Z8D1RNGY9yEidD_sVTTH6fl10ojR1fV8RD28DDGhDuPmYf5gRCNLqdazQ6Hh65b5yu7YfUwsQxW0ENOGD9WZ_sfxEkK5oHGkC-gaO9Xxsx6"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>No, we don't mean you seal them shut permanently. Just like the door, your widows might have some gaps where sound can pass through. To fix this, you can also put in some <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Trim-Lok-D-Shaped-Rubber-Seal-Thick/dp/B00NL49QCA/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1534446337&amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;keywords=door+seal&amp;psc=1&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=generatorgrid-20&amp;linkId=f147e37e2086a4195b9590d441c5fa31">weather stripping seal tape</a> around the edges of your windows to seal them.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Put padding on your floor and ceiling</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-SCYF5o7AErnJkoX3BUj23GKYlzzGGwH3Sw6P8tIPQwbSFQutLHb55TBkkBZb7Z69fP8ihb09JV6mflwpoy5ZvyFww9sCPBsa7Bx1QB3jXUSoG_yGb_aiKj6miPY5IND_k1MQ4W0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is -SCYF5o7AErnJkoX3BUj23GKYlzzGGwH3Sw6P8tIPQwbSFQutLHb55TBkkBZb7Z69fP8ihb09JV6mflwpoy5ZvyFww9sCPBsa7Bx1QB3jXUSoG_yGb_aiKj6miPY5IND_k1MQ4W0"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If noises come from your neighbors above, you may want to consider putting some padding on your ceiling, like these <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sonex-WWC-2-Whisper-Wave-Clouds/dp/B07CKKDZ84/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=soundproofxpert-20&amp;linkId=e5872198de3d90a1cb3bf2f88fb8ab37">ceiling clouds</a>. These work nicely and help with footstep noises coming from above.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>But if you're the one on the upper apartment and your neighbors below are making noises, invest in some thick and heavy carpets/rugs. Not only will it help minimize the noise coming from below, but it will also help conceal noises coming from your floor. They do make a big difference, especially when you put an extra soundproofing vinyl under your rug.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>4. Use thick curtains</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/9JTicIU3r0OARrhajvGfPOofsCKwu8k3fb9NKLzdQWSv3GrmmHs0RX6DJmff-TCV51zhOu2ej5K4l3PCZG6MlscawbOjp3K_2ec4wh66GzpN10bdzISFanI46s3H9FvVl1Z4vHjC" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 9JTicIU3r0OARrhajvGfPOofsCKwu8k3fb9NKLzdQWSv3GrmmHs0RX6DJmff-TCV51zhOu2ej5K4l3PCZG6MlscawbOjp3K_2ec4wh66GzpN10bdzISFanI46s3H9FvVl1Z4vHjC"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Special <a href="https://www.amazon.com/NICETOWN-Microfiber-Reducing-Insulated-Blackout/dp/B01CS31NDE/ref=sr_1_6?crid=310GR2HSKKAZN&amp;dchild=1&amp;keywords=soundproof+curtains+noise+cancelling&amp;qid=1598037118&amp;sprefix=soundproof+curtains%2Caps%2C436&amp;sr=8-6">thick soundproofing curtains</a> don't only help minimize sounds, they also work as great blackout curtains. These curtains can help absorb extra sound from the outside and the ambient noise that floats around your room.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The greater the density of your curtains, the better. Instead of using just 2 drapes, you can use 4 drapes to increase the curtains' mass.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>5. Hang acoustic panels or foam</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/7x-mwpJLgKrFlgsiEuSCAxZ-Oc2WtKvyKPauPqDjB7scZETNlTjU5DVk5_y7sJKWQeSL53LQGrnzJUOU4TK7INdMCUH21Tsxv0lWg7jJSpzpWBAUHUY88Ktj4-SHIW2DXFUsp997" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 7x-mwpJLgKrFlgsiEuSCAxZ-Oc2WtKvyKPauPqDjB7scZETNlTjU5DVk5_y7sJKWQeSL53LQGrnzJUOU4TK7INdMCUH21Tsxv0lWg7jJSpzpWBAUHUY88Ktj4-SHIW2DXFUsp997"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Hard surfaces can reflect and amplify sounds. You can invest in some cheap <a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=soundproof+foam">acoustic panel or foam</a> to help elevate your soundproofing. These are soft, which absorb more sound, making them bounce a lot less. These panels come in a lot of colors and designs and help add some aesthetic to your room.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You don't have to cover all your walls with this material. You can just place them on the reflection point of the sound, usually the opposite wall of the source.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>6. Hang some canvas art</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/SmN6wrlxT-ilOK8hsUFRuPGVhgNdXbjQuphajsnBi6gxCJ_7Ir1aEaJ6lzGkUYV29LdSFCbuH_NnlxmlyLB8mevwWjZVYiZ7570Cj8E5-zRgDJ2WzPzlGR3B2RYSUGy8DXWBjJUB" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is SmN6wrlxT-ilOK8hsUFRuPGVhgNdXbjQuphajsnBi6gxCJ_7Ir1aEaJ6lzGkUYV29LdSFCbuH_NnlxmlyLB8mevwWjZVYiZ7570Cj8E5-zRgDJ2WzPzlGR3B2RYSUGy8DXWBjJUB"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you're not into acoustic panels, you can also try hanging some canvas art. Painting, posters printed on canvas, etc. are excellent alternatives. Not only do these help absorb sound, but they are also very pleasing to the eyes.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Remember that soft and deeply textured materials are much better than hard, smooth materials because they can absorb sound a lot better. Aside from canvas art, you can also use some tapestry and hang them on your wall. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>7. Put on some background noise</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/IAe3rqoRRvfe4fKzeKhbkVm-kz2wKo6I8eSKt2GjJguUVa7Z0sSn_1Fq8Tc7s4vJjy6NHRBjignE04R6r-smB0kPu0UfQW29AsHqotGRQClUgzgKgZgmsvzALOrIGuGvLGfybG7t" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is IAe3rqoRRvfe4fKzeKhbkVm-kz2wKo6I8eSKt2GjJguUVa7Z0sSn_1Fq8Tc7s4vJjy6NHRBjignE04R6r-smB0kPu0UfQW29AsHqotGRQClUgzgKgZgmsvzALOrIGuGvLGfybG7t"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When you have something else to listen to, it becomes easier to drown out the more annoying sounds around. You can purchase a <a href="https://amzn.to/2C6oSSh?tag=moderncastle-20">sound machine</a> that plays a variety of background noises like rain, white noise, fireplace, and more. These are relatively cheap and are an excellent quick fix that can be useful, especially for temporary situations.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>8. Add furniture</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/ys2Jz5lQQ-_SvO2vUBiO2iiKQbEM-S6fRZWOtBeBBb9cGx-Lq5bRLT2KaS3ZkRaVWvW_RlF3LD64qHU9HQgOsVRXxpmIIyYS2v4e-tPhFJQXpPHkVSDI8vidhZvp04n0azwu6_5H" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is ys2Jz5lQQ-_SvO2vUBiO2iiKQbEM-S6fRZWOtBeBBb9cGx-Lq5bRLT2KaS3ZkRaVWvW_RlF3LD64qHU9HQgOsVRXxpmIIyYS2v4e-tPhFJQXpPHkVSDI8vidhZvp04n0azwu6_5H"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you have more vacant space in your bedroom, you can also add more furniture. Upholstered furniture like chairs or sofa is highly recommended because it keeps sounds from bouncing as much and gives more areas for sound to be absorbed into. If you don't have more room for a sofa or chair, you can add more pillows and thick blankets on your bed.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also opt for floor-to-ceiling shelvings and fill them with a lot of books and magazines. You can also use the shelves as storage space. It could help absorb sound more efficiently.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Another tip if you're a bit extra</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you have that extra budget to spend, add another layer of drywall to your entire room. It will help lessen the sound vibrations. Apply some caulk in between sheets of drywall to help with the absorption of the sound from outside.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Apply about 3/8 inch-thick of acoustical caulk to keep the sounds at bay. When done, refinish and repaint the drywall you've installed on an existing wall and extend the electrical outlets for easier access.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>But this isn't necessary. This requires quite some work, so you can just consider it when all else fails.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Time to get better sleep with bedroom soundproofing</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Your bedroom is a safe haven. It's totally okay to take some extra steps to try and upgrade it. Like <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/index.php/2020/08/13/feng-shui-bed-placement-tips-for-good-luck/">finding the right position of your bed</a> or soundproofing your entire room to make you feel more relaxed and comfortable.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Soundproofing doesn't require a lot of money or expertise. You can fairly do it by yourself with the help of the right materials and a bit of time. Do know that doing these tips won't totally block all the noises from outside. But it can certainly reduce those unwanted noises immensely.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For those who are having a hard time dealing with unwanted noises, take some time to soundproof your bedroom. You'll totally feel the difference right after. Better sleep, more quiet time, and yes, you can make noises if you want to. No worries.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>5 Easy Ways to Open a Locked Bedroom Door</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.luckycathome.com/5-easy-ways-to-open-a-locked-bedroom-door/"/>
        <id>https://www.luckycathome.com/5-easy-ways-to-open-a-locked-bedroom-door/</id>

        <updated>2022-08-29T19:56:22-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Your bedroom is your ultimate private space, where you can always be in control. But there are some&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/SgYVICG3AN6SjfxrN-PEfIYk8wuh0AMDzJoqt5U45ZGmbsV7EQfMBVQ3jv1pN1qQTCqnHj3t2Tq6xQ5EMFGet2GEDKDHMAMk5pzarlatD1UImsjV9QqjFBePXZaHYlKpI-DfI9Qb" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is SgYVICG3AN6SjfxrN-PEfIYk8wuh0AMDzJoqt5U45ZGmbsV7EQfMBVQ3jv1pN1qQTCqnHj3t2Tq6xQ5EMFGet2GEDKDHMAMk5pzarlatD1UImsjV9QqjFBePXZaHYlKpI-DfI9Qb"></p>
<p>Your bedroom is your ultimate private space, where you can always be in control. But there are some instances where you can get locked out of it.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>It may be due to a relative, roommate, or a toddler accidentally locking himself/herself inside the room; you, accidentally locking yourself outside, or any other reason. Now you can't get in.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>No keys.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>No locksmiths.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>What should you do?</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To help you get through this situation (or if it ever happens again), here are some tips and tricks on how to open a locked bedroom door (without a key).</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What to do before opening a locked door?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Doors are made with different materials for various purposes. Usually, a bedroom door isn't designed for security but for privacy. Which is why it is possible to open them with a bit of force and maneuvering.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>But before all the unlocking action, you must first determine the type of lock your bedroom door has. Generally, a bedroom door has a push button in the knob or one that will use a twist button to lock. However, some people install more secure locks (like a deadbolt lock) on their bedroom door; these types are harder to open. So do consider what type of lock you're going to deal with.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For this article, we'll consider the standard type of lock for bedroom doors, which are the push button or twist button locks.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Ways to open a locked bedroom door</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>We compiled a list of different methods on how to unlock a locked door without a key. Some of these may cause some damage to your doorknob or the tool you'll be using, so keep that in mind.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Using a card</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/0P3Px_nZ1yvqqgB3faTwaq0yj2K9GFZxtm5ir4ZaULPXcYAz-ql4-1hKdjak7Ua6a4QrKdgEjn-7PT8Ca_9zFas8dKCqfwoNdFCw05cOk3gul3KEGM3EMJptZgV6cwozc-2MbEjB" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 0P3Px_nZ1yvqqgB3faTwaq0yj2K9GFZxtm5ir4ZaULPXcYAz-ql4-1hKdjak7Ua6a4QrKdgEjn-7PT8Ca_9zFas8dKCqfwoNdFCw05cOk3gul3KEGM3EMJptZgV6cwozc-2MbEjB"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If your bedroom door has a latch bolt, with the angled edge is facing toward you, you can pop it free with a card. The card might get damaged/bent during the process, so make sure you're not using an important card like your debit or credit cards. Use cards that can be easily replaced, like a store rewards card, library card, or other flexible and quickly replaceable cards are best. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Procedure:</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Take the plastic card and slide it into the gap between your door and the doorjamb.</li>
<li>Begin right above the door handle, and slide the card downwards and in.</li>
<li>You may have to wiggle or maneuver the card a bit. It could press against the latch assembly and allow you to open the door. </li>
<li>Some doors may require you to lean against them so that there is a little pressure. That pressure may help engage the lock more securely when you are sliding the card down. If it doesn't work when you slide the card down, try sliding the card up.</li>
<li>If you're lucky, you'll be able to open it on the first try. But it may require you to do this several times.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2> 2. Using a hairpin</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/81eFZo3OQxrRoTvL8XBLLav9UJ752ZzSESidmbd-FRDWEObPf83AOEOfcAgavA_mmdEAZ38TgCS1sc56rGm9GCqq0ILAfkMkMSYNxFNS2t7GCaI7NQfjMAlBin855GHDVlPLMP70" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 81eFZo3OQxrRoTvL8XBLLav9UJ752ZzSESidmbd-FRDWEObPf83AOEOfcAgavA_mmdEAZ38TgCS1sc56rGm9GCqq0ILAfkMkMSYNxFNS2t7GCaI7NQfjMAlBin855GHDVlPLMP70"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also use hairpins or bobby pins to unlock your bedroom door, just like the old trick you see in movies. Hairpins are usually easy to bend and manipulate to the shape you're aiming for since it's made of thin metal. It's not that had to open a door lock using a bobby pin, which is why many people opt for this method. You'll be needing two hairpins for this procedure.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> you can also use paper clips for this method.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Procedure:</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Get one bobby pin. Bend one centimeter or so of the joint end for about 90 degrees, so it is perpendicular to the two free ends.</li>
<li>Insert this into the bottom of the keyhole and use the two free ends as a handle.</li>
<li>Take another hairpin and stretch it all the way through, so it becomes a single straight metal stick.</li>
<li>Add a small upward bend to one straight end. This acts as the "pick," and it goes into the top half of the keyhole.</li>
<li>Use your pick to push the spring-loaded pins up. Do this one at a time until the cylinder is free to turn. </li>
<li>There are two ways to pick the locks in your doorknob:</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Scrubbing Method</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>With this method, push the hairpin at the lower part of the keyhole and lift it upward. You have to repeat this in a circular motion until you successfully lift all the pins inside the doorknob. Remember to apply constant pressure to the other bobby pin below and turn the doorknob until it eventually opens.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Pin by Pin Method:</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If the scrubbing method does not work, you can try this method instead. Insert your hairpin, and as it comes into contact with the pins inside the doorknob, try to catch it right on the bend and lift the pins upward until it snaps into place. Repeat this with multiple pins until the lock will turn.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Using a butter knife</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/O7BlnePCEmt8HhOggNShHtlhwbe4laAjrjsV4IUmkIxXqS6Hb7VXs1jB26N18N-UGkMFpvlQpaT-qKv75chUEXwb2pfpCTt2-c78mlXFawsrufANVv2GqopQQVdXs00i0zlBJuu9" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is O7BlnePCEmt8HhOggNShHtlhwbe4laAjrjsV4IUmkIxXqS6Hb7VXs1jB26N18N-UGkMFpvlQpaT-qKv75chUEXwb2pfpCTt2-c78mlXFawsrufANVv2GqopQQVdXs00i0zlBJuu9"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you don't have plastic cards, bobby pins, or paper clips around, you might have a butter knife in your kitchen. Don't use a sharp knife for this method because you might accidentally hurt yourself. This method is very similar to the plastic card method.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Procedure:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Put the butter knife between the door and the doorjamb, just right above the doorknob. </li>
<li>Slide the knife down quickly, while leaning against the door.</li>
<li>Try this a couple of times until the door unlocks.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>4. Using a screwdriver</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/X4KKB3BmCLesJnXit5DkQ3Wv9IOWmqTU-7wFewUujyyuU5BQdMlVSiccRe5k9-t6mHaDLEJE8cMz8qYVf_wC63JYAP2Ld-ARlr-ufNhv77zopLAQv2jpdbMFXM3b8PfBr6oLiLcZ" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is X4KKB3BmCLesJnXit5DkQ3Wv9IOWmqTU-7wFewUujyyuU5BQdMlVSiccRe5k9-t6mHaDLEJE8cMz8qYVf_wC63JYAP2Ld-ARlr-ufNhv77zopLAQv2jpdbMFXM3b8PfBr6oLiLcZ"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If none of the above-mentioned methods above work, you can try to use a screwdriver to unlock your door. There are two ways on how you can use a screwdriver. Different types are used for these two procedures, so it's helpful to have a small and a standard-sized screwdriver.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Procedure 1: </h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Use a small and flathead screwdriver and push the screwdriver into the keyhole on the doorknob. Put it straight through for as far as you can.</li>
<li>Twist or turn the screwdriver until the lock is opened.</li>
<li>You can also use a slotted screwdriver to open the spring locks if you wedge it between the bolt and frame.</li>
<li>Then, wiggle the screwdriver until you push the lock back into the door.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Procedure 2:</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>You can also use a larger, flathead screwdriver to remove the door hinges. This will only work if the hinges are exposed.</li>
<li>Grab a flathead screwdriver and a hammer or mallet (or anything hard that can be used to strike the screwdriver).</li>
<li>Position the screwdriver at the bottom of the knuckle, and the pin on the door hinge. Tap the handle of the screwdriver downwards using the hammer/mallet.</li>
<li>Once they are loose enough, remove the head and pin. You must repeat this for all the hinges. This may take some force and effort to finish.</li>
<li>Or you can also just remove the screws of the door hinges if it's exposed. </li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>5. Using a drill</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/qWD1eSCjMDj-xz8sIMPol5AFkm0_Pql47emcI2HTfcOUd4pTpPhmxDTNECeG1GpUcr-h2iQ-aA-qTn8myFKnwxg0gT4ShGf9L8pCgQYJqBakN4sbQXgoj0kBfxi8TQnzBwA343NI" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is qWD1eSCjMDj-xz8sIMPol5AFkm0_Pql47emcI2HTfcOUd4pTpPhmxDTNECeG1GpUcr-h2iQ-aA-qTn8myFKnwxg0gT4ShGf9L8pCgQYJqBakN4sbQXgoj0kBfxi8TQnzBwA343NI"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This method requires a more complicated tool, but you may have it at home - an electric drill. Unlike the previous ones, this method will leave permanent damage to your lock. You'll definitely need a new doorknob after this one.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Procedure:</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Use the drill to trill the pins on the lock of your doorknob.</li>
<li>Drill it just above the top of the keyhole, in line with the cylinder's threshold and the pins' position when they are pushed free.</li>
<li>Experiment with different drill bit sizes. Start with a small one, and try using some lubricating oil to help.</li>
<li>Once you've finished drilling, try using a screwdriver into the keyhole, and you should be able to turn it.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>When nothing else works</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you've tried everything to unlock the door and nothing is working, then you have some other options. Here are some of them.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Force the door open by kicking it</strong>. This may destroy your entire door, the doorknob, and the door frame. Not only will it shatter your bedroom door, but you can also hurt yourself in this process. This should definitely be the last resort and use it only in emergency situations. </li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/nvZC6HfiaQ9RNmCdko8MIbxzHjVPu9ZCFModcypCt9W081u2uEZcw_ORqpmi0X9yxVUIYWGbG7ZASC0EuGhU6NVb0SXDLksdsTGozM8cwhq5nFrWkczX1TwnFN4PjC4nB4DQfWFB" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is nvZC6HfiaQ9RNmCdko8MIbxzHjVPu9ZCFModcypCt9W081u2uEZcw_ORqpmi0X9yxVUIYWGbG7ZASC0EuGhU6NVb0SXDLksdsTGozM8cwhq5nFrWkczX1TwnFN4PjC4nB4DQfWFB"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Use a hammer to smash the doorknob</strong>. This will definitely damage the doorknob, and you'll need to purchase a replacement. Strike your doorknob repeatedly using a hammer, mallet, or any other hard object. A broken doorknob is an unlocked doorknob, that's for sure.</li>
<li><strong>Call a professional.</strong> When you don't want to do any damages and are not really sure of what to do, you can just call a professional locksmith to unlock the door for you. These professionals have the needed skills and tools to unlock a door, so it's a guarantee that you'll have it opened.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>No more locked bedroom doors!</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Now you know different tricks to open a locked bedroom door. But remember, do these tips ONLY when you get locked out of YOUR BEDROOM. Don't ever do it to try and break into someone else's rooms. These methods take several minutes and very obvious, so you'll most likely be caught.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can practice these tricks, so it'll be easier for you to do it when an actual emergency comes. Nothing or no one could ever lock you out of your bedroom again. Not your toddler, not your roommate, not even your own door.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Feng Shui Living Room: 20 Rules and Tips You Shouldn&#x27;t Miss</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.luckycathome.com/feng-shui-living-room-20-rules-and-tips-you-shouldnt-miss/"/>
        <id>https://www.luckycathome.com/feng-shui-living-room-20-rules-and-tips-you-shouldnt-miss/</id>

        <updated>2022-08-29T20:21:49-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Living rooms are an essential part of any home. It is where you usually hang out and accept&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Living rooms are an essential part of any home. It is where you usually hang out and accept guests for social gatherings. That's why it is crucial to make it comfortable and enjoyable for everyone.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/Pez3DS4hGg-TT2qhEe5gQcxFbSzg1fn6j2oKhhi2YLmva9kyAA2lziKRi_v4JjWGCUxhDOSNt3LzhmfT8cX52yljlveg9p6l__40PERWg3RXOJYKC1ZyJ7z8ZgX8glQ7g9K4RG8q" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is Pez3DS4hGg-TT2qhEe5gQcxFbSzg1fn6j2oKhhi2YLmva9kyAA2lziKRi_v4JjWGCUxhDOSNt3LzhmfT8cX52yljlveg9p6l__40PERWg3RXOJYKC1ZyJ7z8ZgX8glQ7g9K4RG8q"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>More than just properly arranging furniture and painting walls, finding the perfect balance between the energy and objects in your living room is necessary. Achieving this balance can be done through <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/index.php/2020/08/12/feng-shui-basics-attracting-positive-energy-into-your-home/">Feng Shui</a>. No worries, you don't need to be a Feng Shui expert to start, you can actually do it yourself.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To help you create balance and welcome positive energy, here are some Feng Shui rules and tips you should follow for your living room. We will talk about location, placement, furniture, and overall vibes.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How can I Feng Shui in my living room?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The first thing you should consider is the location of your living room. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Your living room should be in the front part of your house</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Your living room should be the first room to welcome anyone who's coming into your house. Ideally, it should be close to the front door.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>2. Clear clutter</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/WFIx3mV2m1e54o-oc6lxnGmzi2sk5-9SYmuQN3q8Q5GA9kWjAThwoKYeBPnCM9VTyKoeJvnz0pzM9HKdq5dKPm_R5jtqjcDpMRm-yxTnCfE7P_HRsYleCr6mQ6D8ooJX4wXhjFUu" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is WFIx3mV2m1e54o-oc6lxnGmzi2sk5-9SYmuQN3q8Q5GA9kWjAThwoKYeBPnCM9VTyKoeJvnz0pzM9HKdq5dKPm_R5jtqjcDpMRm-yxTnCfE7P_HRsYleCr6mQ6D8ooJX4wXhjFUu"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The primary principle of Feng Shui is to create spatial harmony. Thus, to achieve a good living room feng shui, you must declutter the space. Having many unnecessary objects around could disrupt the flow of energy in your living room.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To keep the positive vibe and good chi energy flowing, try getting rid of some excess furniture or any other object with no specific function in the room.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Your living room should have four corners</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Many modern design houses have irregular shaped living rooms. Some come in triangular, round, and other irregular shapes. This is not ideal in Feng Shui. Your living room should have four corners like a square, rectangle, or other four-cornered shapes. These shapes are believed to attract people who are more virtuous or righteous.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>4. It should be in an auspicious area based on Personal and House Kua</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Besides your bedroom, your living room is most likely the room you'll spend most of your time in. Therefore, it is best if it's located in an auspicious area inside your home. You can check this by knowing your Kua number or the facing direction of your home and see if it is in the ideal location.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In case your living room is not in a favorable location, You can make some adjustments based on your Kua number. But keep in mind that your sofa needs to be placed conveniently. Don't force it if the placing looks too awkward for the layout of your living room. Besides, comfort is your primary target here.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>5. Avoid low and slanted ceiling</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/SRHA4BFYiUh3aH10AJkOGCS5jjpwkKoziwJl54U76S3lK4-4TxUvTJTEnsrAlsgDb1eksicA5UyLLwoCXSSHpgFm3J_UDy5XwOaFYlHVeVMQx-sIsbrBpj6dAtWw3Z88vY9IYADf" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is SRHA4BFYiUh3aH10AJkOGCS5jjpwkKoziwJl54U76S3lK4-4TxUvTJTEnsrAlsgDb1eksicA5UyLLwoCXSSHpgFm3J_UDy5XwOaFYlHVeVMQx-sIsbrBpj6dAtWw3Z88vY9IYADf"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Low ceilings give off a negative vibe, which makes you feel too compressed. It could make you and your guests feel uncomfortable because of the invisible pressure. It will also make it hard for energy to flow and gather in the space because it feels small.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Aside from low ceilings, avoid slanted ceilings too because they give off the same vibe. But if your living room was made with slanted ceilings, try your best not to put your sofa underneath the slanted parts. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>6. Your living room should have multiple windows</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Having a single window on an area for multiple people can be quite sad. It's also wrong in Feng Shui because the positive Chi energy won't flow freely. This could affect your ability to make social connections. Thus, the occupant(s) might become more of a loner and avoid human interaction.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Which direction should my couch face?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The sofa is the biggest and is the most essential furniture in your living room, that's why it's placement is crucial. But how should you position it? Here are some tips.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>7. Use the command position on your sofa</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Similarly, on how to <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/index.php/2020/08/13/feng-shui-bed-placement-tips-for-good-luck/">position your bed in Feng Shui</a>, the sofa in your living room should also be in the command position.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/J_pQMTnzR0xd1kUbFQj2V1oTAp_TRu0HuovjgHgQGMGD_W__ik3I77uui0kVQlc4m2mIF9psueI7j2r7z02LYUNjV97CN4ljXNRSZncPyLaVu7otQZ3Toqu2n6dyW54ZfWu8SjWF" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is J_pQMTnzR0xd1kUbFQj2V1oTAp_TRu0HuovjgHgQGMGD_W__ik3I77uui0kVQlc4m2mIF9psueI7j2r7z02LYUNjV97CN4ljXNRSZncPyLaVu7otQZ3Toqu2n6dyW54ZfWu8SjWF"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Basically, the command position is placing an object (in this case, the sofa) on an area where you can see the front door. However, your sofa shouldn't be directly in line with the door. The ideal position is setting the sofa or couch with a wall behind it. The person sitting on it should be able to see the front door directly. That's your command position.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you can't position your sofa against a wall, support it using large furniture like a table or cabinet and put it behind the backrest.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>8. Avoid placing your sofa directly in front of a door</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This rule is connected to the previous one. If you follow the command position, you shouldn't put your sofa directly in-line with a door. More so, if your front door leads to a narrow hallway that leads to the couch. This forms an arrow position that builds negative energy - something you wouldn't want in your living room.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Suppose you can't avoid having your sofa directly in line with the door. Then you can just make a remedy by placing a divider or other furniture somewhere in the middle.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>9. Avoid having a walkway behind the sofa</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Having a walkway behind your sofa makes you more vulnerable. It could also attract people that might do you harm (in different ways). Doing this could also make it harder for you to get help and from your friends. Ensure there is support or a wall behind your couch (just like what we mentioned in #5). </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>10. Avoid placing your sofa under a beam</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In Feng Shui, beams are believed to bring a form of negative energy (Xa) that can cause issues to your health. Some also say that staying under a beam will put you in a situation where you are "forced to submit, bow, and concede." This is why it is best if you avoid placing your sofa under a beam. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Where should I put my TV in my living room?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Your TV should also be strategically positioned as it affects the overall vibe of your living room. Here are some proper TV placement tips you should follow. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>11. Choose an auspicious area</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Following the Feng Shui Bagua, here are different auspicious directions you can place your TV:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>North</strong> - This is the career side. You can place your TV in this position to attract good luck in one's career.</li>
<li><strong>South</strong> - This side corresponds to fame and recognition. If you wish to enhance your opportunity for fame and respect, put it in this area.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>12. Avoid putting your TV above the fireplace</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/vWPrn_7tMTcFWg-SbTadCsUcWdv70nPqCdQohvSmhK3B0urP5P4jI1koHO1U6Z6jlp5-nS_dICMeLLzktF_iCSSmJQ1lIe-RlunBi0mLFnM1h2WcPFNHldbPt9sK1t0HXo6oF5sG" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is vWPrn_7tMTcFWg-SbTadCsUcWdv70nPqCdQohvSmhK3B0urP5P4jI1koHO1U6Z6jlp5-nS_dICMeLLzktF_iCSSmJQ1lIe-RlunBi0mLFnM1h2WcPFNHldbPt9sK1t0HXo6oF5sG"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A TV above the fireplace is a big no-no in Feng Shui for two reasons:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>The electricity of the TV creates excess heat. It is not an ideal combination with the "Fiery" symbolism of the fireplace.</li>
<li>It might not be a comfortable viewing position.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Where should Feng Shui plants be placed indoors?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Plants have amazing benefits not only to your living room's visual appeal but also to your health. To get the best out of your Feng Shui indoor plants, here are some tips on positioning them.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>13. Use large potted plants</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Large plants bring in more energy in a room, so large plants are suitable in the living room. Jut remember not to put large plants on the following areas:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Southwest</li>
<li>Northeast</li>
<li>Northwest</li>
<li>Center</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Putting plants in these areas may bring in some adverse effects that could affect your marriage and your children's ability to learn (Southwest and Northeast). Putting plants that clash with the prominent element in an area (like gold in the northwest)can negatively affect the energy in your living room.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>But if you still want to put plants in these areas, you can always do so. But choose smaller plants instead.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>14. Choose plants with round leaves</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Choose plants with large rounded leaves because it's believed to have the ability to attract positive energies. It's best to avoid pointy leaves because they are considered a bad form in Feng Shui.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>15. Make a small window garden</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/m7QXByb3iSj59CaWFPlyzMcEluVtGxgeroV0WfcD0EimYAjeWhzuV10x9yGpqJha1PWynjnOR1epfu8Meu66uDcXGq5NamAikAs0z2f93rVt433hVgKMBGmMpeiIz2SC0txdvu-y" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is m7QXByb3iSj59CaWFPlyzMcEluVtGxgeroV0WfcD0EimYAjeWhzuV10x9yGpqJha1PWynjnOR1epfu8Meu66uDcXGq5NamAikAs0z2f93rVt433hVgKMBGmMpeiIz2SC0txdvu-y"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If your living room is small and doesn't have enough space for large plants, you can set up a small garden near your window. Put some small potted plants and flowers near your window, or maybe some herbs.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Plants absorb negative energy and clean the air, so putting it, even in a small room, it's great for you overall. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How to make my living room look attractive?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Adding decorations and other elements won't only affect the look of your living, it could also enhance the flow of positive chi energy. Here are Feng Shui tips on how you can decorate and make your living room more attractive.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>16. Have lots of lighting</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Bring in some bright, uplifting energy using natural light and layered lighting. Try to put lighting on dark corners to brighten it up. Light also represents the fire element, which should be represented in your living room for harmony and balance.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>17. Put some rug for grounding</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Putting a rug in the living room grounds space. You should choose a flat square-shaped rug. This brings in the earth element of stability and good health.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>18. Choose uplifting artwork</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Choose uplifting and personal artwork. You can go for scenic pictures, quotations or just art that you really enjoy. You can also use family pictures since they are considered excellent in Feng Shui, but it isn't necessarily required. Also, make sure you don't hang them too low. Artworks hanging low can cause depression in the home. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>19. Use expansive mirrors</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/UytKxAQeTI8qGJjMmjn177igWrc1PDxseqZHofQ6-QhhH0lJPXRpOmNe8JkrFv8fVCGFrL6oXKR03zAyWMMx3JETH6z-xax5f61LOVJ1qSxBgomo4w4aphU-Sf80POyVEN53NpKm" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is UytKxAQeTI8qGJjMmjn177igWrc1PDxseqZHofQ6-QhhH0lJPXRpOmNe8JkrFv8fVCGFrL6oXKR03zAyWMMx3JETH6z-xax5f61LOVJ1qSxBgomo4w4aphU-Sf80POyVEN53NpKm"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Mirrors can make a room feel bigger. If possible, hang your mirror near a window to bounce natural light into the room. If you have a landscape outside, try to position our mirror where it reflects the view. This would attract more positive energy into your home.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You should also choose a mirror that reflects your entire head, shoulders, and chest line to ensure you 'capture your aura.'</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>20. Incorporate the five elements</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Create the right balance by incorporating the five elements (wood, fire, earth, metal, and water) in your living room through decors. Try to use decorations representing each element, whether it may be furniture, accessories, art, and more. Try to use a Feng Shui map or Bagua to track the best locations of where to put them.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Set up that relaxing living room!</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Living rooms are mainly for entertainment and relaxation. But unlike the bedroom, living rooms are meant to be shared with others. With the help of Feng Shui, you can now create a more relaxing, comfortable, lucky, and positive living room by following these tips. Now go set up your living room and have fun!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>5 Natural Ways to Get Rid of Ants in Your Bedroom</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.luckycathome.com/5-natural-ways-to-get-rid-of-ants-in-your-bedroom/"/>
        <id>https://www.luckycathome.com/5-natural-ways-to-get-rid-of-ants-in-your-bedroom/</id>

        <updated>2022-08-29T20:13:49-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Ants are highly social insects. When you see one, there are probably thousands more roaming around. That wouldn't&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/95JPp6bzedG09QlAeus8BVMyc_ZBhXBhqWtkB71iFFdzkP5-kHsg0bog0Fzqa76NmsP_8Bh-L-O1J7XGyKkXZGtf7J-k95zpPeEQ1uSCw3DZLZ0RfoK7SuzRwBj_Iv03TH4rL1hd" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 95JPp6bzedG09QlAeus8BVMyc_ZBhXBhqWtkB71iFFdzkP5-kHsg0bog0Fzqa76NmsP_8Bh-L-O1J7XGyKkXZGtf7J-k95zpPeEQ1uSCw3DZLZ0RfoK7SuzRwBj_Iv03TH4rL1hd"></p>
<p>Ants are highly social insects. When you see one, there are probably thousands more roaming around. That wouldn't be much of a problem when you're doing some nature tip outdoors. But that could instantly become a problem when you see them inside your bedroom.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are about more than <a href="https://www.terminix.com/blog/education/types-of-ants-eight-common-invaders/">12,000 species of ants</a>. Some of them can be harmful to humans because they bite (and it's painful) and even damage your house. When you encounter an ant infestation in your bedroom (or anywhere in your home), it's best to quickly get rid of them. Here are our 5 natural ways to get rid of ants in your bedroom.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Why are there ants in my bedroom?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Ants may come into your home for various reasons, but hunting for food is undoubtedly the one on top. Ants may see your home as a possible source of food and water. It can also provide them with protection from predators, thus serving as a potential site for new colonies when they're ready to expand.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here are a few more reasons why ants might be coming into your bedroom:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>They're escaping from bad weather.</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Like other species, ants are also affected by inclement weather. If their colonies are attacked by floods, snow, heat, and bad weather, they need to move and escape to more favorable environments.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>They follow the scent of other ants.</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/XHoKi9A2MkynT-lfq0Qxk9Xsp3g1HMcgdwz1YkUbTId15TQ3zG08SdmdFC9ebaT1Vfj1xrjQCN9YPZP1YqdL7DQiGVkuYLUNJx9sZyf7xlaou0rhRxEYt9UAPaLD9o6yZOx_VeVb" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is XHoKi9A2MkynT-lfq0Qxk9Xsp3g1HMcgdwz1YkUbTId15TQ3zG08SdmdFC9ebaT1Vfj1xrjQCN9YPZP1YqdL7DQiGVkuYLUNJx9sZyf7xlaou0rhRxEYt9UAPaLD9o6yZOx_VeVb"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Another reason why ants are infesting your home is that they may have picked up a scent that has attracted them. It can be the scent of other ants and even their own scent if their colony has previously invaded your home. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>They need moisture.</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Ants also need moisture to live. If water is no longer available in their colonies, they will go to other areas to look for fresh supplies. That is why if the humidity in your house is high, ants will be attracted to it even if there's no food exposed around.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>They spillover your home</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Another reason why there can be ants in your house even if it's squeaky clean is that they can spillover from your neighbor. There is a high possibility of this if your home is attached to another house like an apartment dwelling. Much more when you have a neighbor that's not fond of cleaning. If their house is infested by ants, that colony may spill over your premises.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How do I get rid of ants in my room?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Some people just resort to cans after cans of bug spray to fix their ant infestation problem. But aside from being costly, this method is also potentially harmful to the people residing in a household because of the toxic chemicals these sprays have.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are actually tons of natural remedies you can use to solve this problem. Here are the top 5 natural remedies on our list.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Pepper</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/byM8JXQAKd6Axdg4POu9lpW20QhQQA4AJISG_Q1q11djxw4qqFInsIyKjcv-pL82_h012ke3kgHJOtr1Pk1UY1tfZ0E7uWPgpBdNmZz3ExijjhIAiuw630QDYkEtTKt80jlb0ToS" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is byM8JXQAKd6Axdg4POu9lpW20QhQQA4AJISG_Q1q11djxw4qqFInsIyKjcv-pL82_h012ke3kgHJOtr1Pk1UY1tfZ0E7uWPgpBdNmZz3ExijjhIAiuw630QDYkEtTKt80jlb0ToS"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Ants seem to hate the scent of pepper. You can try using Cayenne pepper or black pepper to help get rid of ants. Sprinkle some of these on the area where ants potentially enter your room. You can also make a solution by mixing pepper and water and spray it near the entrant areas. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The pepper wouldn't kill the ants, but it can definitely deter them from returning to your house. Don't forget to clean the area where you want to spray the pepper solution. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>2. White Vinegar</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/DkO4UJ-4NmfmUF9Fhkm9nPiODYYj_LeQn3Gn7hmuBAp9bW-x-lASu0_ZiH18vTQYLN6H_QA0Z5CL724cASp4HGvJF6ZxJfDapoezCl3QoPryp4EVbeqK6PKY7oTs9zjGzHOv7aWK" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is DkO4UJ-4NmfmUF9Fhkm9nPiODYYj_LeQn3Gn7hmuBAp9bW-x-lASu0_ZiH18vTQYLN6H_QA0Z5CL724cASp4HGvJF6ZxJfDapoezCl3QoPryp4EVbeqK6PKY7oTs9zjGzHOv7aWK"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Like pepper, ants also can't bear the smell of vinegar, so it's a good ant repellant. Mix some equal parts of white vinegar and water (50% white vinegar and 50% water). Spray this solution on at the points from where the ants enter for at least once a day. Spray it around your doorway, windowsills, and other places where you usually see ants coming.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This solution may not kill the ants, but it can definitely keep them from entering your bedroom. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Tea tree oil</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/kW4yaqMMJzS9ozfjymvbiSBnAIgVkTOiBqEO01wbCdDblJBFYswfrNFgEBNzlRn1eUaYC4w-2vqI6tLjuw-Z_xHIm1blbnVpdfABYniDH8WYZBLBESPIkVKfNxN0E9ev_Am8vfyV" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is kW4yaqMMJzS9ozfjymvbiSBnAIgVkTOiBqEO01wbCdDblJBFYswfrNFgEBNzlRn1eUaYC4w-2vqI6tLjuw-Z_xHIm1blbnVpdfABYniDH8WYZBLBESPIkVKfNxN0E9ev_Am8vfyV"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Tea tree oil can both repel and kill those pesky ants in your bedroom. Put 5 to 10 drops of tea tree oil on 2 cups of water and use it as a spray. You can also try soaking some cotton balls and putting them around your home where you've seen ants.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you're bothered with the scent, try mixing some peppermint oil with tea tree oil and some water. You should also keep this way from pets, especially cats, because tea tree oil can make them ill.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>4. Cinnamon</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/33GeSutE_l0xpnioqSt0A10sO-5c7mONXNEoSMYN1hcQMPEXzv9del0RH1Xu4-wgAVMoxYMxnv57_pHCpJzGA_YUBclLAZnEbVA9HjOilWPs89JagaTVf8CEKGe9XtDgEyWPxJDv" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 33GeSutE_l0xpnioqSt0A10sO-5c7mONXNEoSMYN1hcQMPEXzv9del0RH1Xu4-wgAVMoxYMxnv57_pHCpJzGA_YUBclLAZnEbVA9HjOilWPs89JagaTVf8CEKGe9XtDgEyWPxJDv"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Cinnamon can also act as a strong natural ant repellent because it's a strong scent. Ants can't stand strong scents; that's why cinnamon is an effective DIY ant control option. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can place some cinnamon and cloves on your bedroom entrance, or anywhere the ants may enter. It is also a good method to also keep your house smelling fresh and earthy. You can also add some essential oils to the cinnamon powder to emit a more pungent smell, keeping the ants away. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>5. Glass cleaner and liquid detergent</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/5jCzuC0H_ceFjqy4y1k4Hk6BstkE7rDPNTdGmpeXQvX59Nsu_nep0ICa2XnjMx2SKZmmXVV3nNtfyNzJhrf0nuYK9Evy5L1MLN0e9J722F72vA4Y8liDRhMaOFAJyH_iQXA_K6dC" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 5jCzuC0H_ceFjqy4y1k4Hk6BstkE7rDPNTdGmpeXQvX59Nsu_nep0ICa2XnjMx2SKZmmXVV3nNtfyNzJhrf0nuYK9Evy5L1MLN0e9J722F72vA4Y8liDRhMaOFAJyH_iQXA_K6dC"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Mixing spray-on glass cleaner and liquid detergent or dish soap can help repel ants from entering your home. This mixture helps remove the scented pheromone trails they leave behind as they walk. You can use this to spray on areas where ants seem to originate from. Wipe down the area after spraying, leaving a light residue.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>More useful tips when dealing with ants</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Aside from the natural remedies we mentioned above, there are more things you can do to permanently stop ants from going inside your bedroom. Here are some useful and easy tips on how to permanently eliminate ants in your bedroom.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Keep your room clean.</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Proper sanitation is critical in the prevention and control of any kind of pests. Ants mainly leave their shelter to find food for their survival. That's why you should seal all your food containers, regularly sweep your floors, and keep surfaces clean. This will prevent the ants from getting attracted to find food in your room.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Seal up the cracks</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Ants can conveniently crawl into tiny spaces and openings because of their size. You can minimize this by sealing up and small gaps they could pass through. Seal around doors, windows, and all pipe, cable, and wire entry points. You should also inspect your foundations for any cracks where they can also pass through.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Identify ant trails</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>One of the best steps you could do is to identify the ant trails. These are the paths where the ants' pass-through from their nest to anywhere they're headed. Ants rely on the scent left by their scouts to guide them from their colony to specific food sources in your home. Knowing their trail is helpful in finding their colony. You can now plan on how you'll eradicate the entire colony and stop them from coming into your room.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Use ant baits</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/d-n0x8-P9rB-pWd8bHc4I5LajPSGj6Ld8xsOKII-hebwWoXOtvbXerhLeL6aoZYkl9pi8hcX8HFvLyo4XFdDi7vxpSrol5yCJ6hA_uqQbZNXCzOEd9o90bxXIGTmQ0BeXxhQpisH" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is d-n0x8-P9rB-pWd8bHc4I5LajPSGj6Ld8xsOKII-hebwWoXOtvbXerhLeL6aoZYkl9pi8hcX8HFvLyo4XFdDi7vxpSrol5yCJ6hA_uqQbZNXCzOEd9o90bxXIGTmQ0BeXxhQpisH"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Giving ants a handful of ant baits can help eliminate them right from the colony. Ant baits are edible materials, usually made of sweet, sugary carbohydrates, combined with toxic substances to ants but have only minimal toxicity to humans and animals. You can trick the ants by letting them bring home this bait and have them consume it. Place your ant bait on the ant trails you've found so the ants can easily find them.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Use some pesticide outdoors to destroy their colony.</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Once you've followed the ant trails and fins their nest, you can now use some heavy dose of liquid pesticide that can soak down to reach the queen. Drenching the nest with some pesticides can be really effective. Just follow the instructions written on the pesticide package and ensure that you follow them correctly. Pesticides can be lethal to all insects, even the beneficial ones, so be careful when using them.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Just make sure that the ants you're getting rid of are actually infesting your room or house. Many types of ants are helpful garden creatures that you have no reason to kill. If they happen just to stay outdoors and not really infest your room in any way, it's best to leave them instead. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Be patient</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/qsKkUZ6RHo76esrt6hOzM98IoFqHTLhwjPQkVbzwpr17q6P-cNauAgnVecoz2a84dRj3DQowLY_cj8U8Fnr6p2IRNN5lmcuXzosTRr542gVD6CdxXPGUrjGjr-5vEHbsSkHRSnV-" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is qsKkUZ6RHo76esrt6hOzM98IoFqHTLhwjPQkVbzwpr17q6P-cNauAgnVecoz2a84dRj3DQowLY_cj8U8Fnr6p2IRNN5lmcuXzosTRr542gVD6CdxXPGUrjGjr-5vEHbsSkHRSnV-"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Getting rid of thousands of ants that are going near your bedroom isn't as easy as putting these remedies at one time. It can take you das or even weeks to completely eliminate them, especially when they come from a big colony. Just be patient, and you'll gradually see the effect of your efforts.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Stop those ants from infesting your bedroom</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Ants are generally helpful and inspiring species when it comes to hard work and perseverance. But they can be a total pain when they start invading spaces that are not meant for them, like your bedroom.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>I hope these natural and safe remedies could help you get rid of these tiny little invaders. These are totally cheap, and you may actually have these ingredients lying around your home already.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>But in case all else fails, you always have the option to call professional exterminators to help you with your problem. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to Wear a Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.luckycathome.com/how-to-wear-a-feng-shui-pixiu-mantra-ring/"/>
        <id>https://www.luckycathome.com/how-to-wear-a-feng-shui-pixiu-mantra-ring/</id>

        <updated>2022-08-29T19:52:12-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    There are many charms, bracelets, and other accessories related to Feng Shui. They are known to attract different&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/bXI4frqcMzSDaGaZ4iQys-y3uOlAY8pmDJV7dKSU29qkYL0QjDHpwX6vZb4KYzuje7bmFm2Brdl0b7dsQ3KC9qxvA7PNvG1WaMM8EZXDxJfqAXhVFzhUrmh6N6Mpc3xETeTQqYiV" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is bXI4frqcMzSDaGaZ4iQys-y3uOlAY8pmDJV7dKSU29qkYL0QjDHpwX6vZb4KYzuje7bmFm2Brdl0b7dsQ3KC9qxvA7PNvG1WaMM8EZXDxJfqAXhVFzhUrmh6N6Mpc3xETeTQqYiV"></p>
<p>There are many charms, bracelets, and other accessories related to Feng Shui. They are known to attract different energies, depending on their symbols and what they are made of. In particular, one is a ring known to attract good fortune and wealth - the Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In this article, we'll talk about the Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring and how its energy attracting abilities help you improve your wealth.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What is a Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring is commonly made of silver or copper with two distinct Feng Shui symbols, the Pixiu and the Mantra.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>What is Pixiu?</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/uoIjn-f_GAoeE1UA0-jR1-9ILqKHePi1E7lL4JCYNzYu_46KpPEoDlLG8pT2jVoVyIl_zdzXWo6Z8gpnYx062Na61z8eWGxa6XznAvNfy-3r8AK3TplxD1G7QKWM_CKrj_d2I0qy" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is uoIjn-f_GAoeE1UA0-jR1-9ILqKHePi1E7lL4JCYNzYu_46KpPEoDlLG8pT2jVoVyIl_zdzXWo6Z8gpnYx062Na61z8eWGxa6XznAvNfy-3r8AK3TplxD1G7QKWM_CKrj_d2I0qy"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Pixiu or Pi Xiu is a Chinese celestial auspicious creature that is believed to draw money and wealth. According to Chinese legends, Pixiu can only eat gold, silver, and other precious treasures. When the Jade emperor sealed its anus, all the treasures Pixiu has devoured stayed in its belly for eternity.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This legend led to the belief that Pixiu attracts fortune and won't permit wealth to leave one's life. Thus, making it a truly powerful symbol of wealth.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>What is a Mantra?</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A mantra (originally from Buddhism and Hinduism) is a sacred sound or utterance repeated frequently. It is known to have religious, magical, or spiritual powers.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The Pixiu ring is also called a mantra Pixiu ring because a mantra is imprinted on the ring's inner part. This famous Mantra came from ancient Sanskrit and is called Om Mani Padme Hum. This Mantra is believed to possess the power of bringing the wearer good luck, accumulated fortune, and, of course, happiness.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"align":"center"} --></p>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/TONUvfdcQJn219sLC4fPIeEAsVCrhzYCssnbqpPX2wLPm4H76FJR5MwykUOOWBSErBvCmq5VhYQpcrajVJmuQuM4FVRyYuHqX-xFJRhchbUjktN34waZLKqsOdElynB5AuRtE2b-" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is TONUvfdcQJn219sLC4fPIeEAsVCrhzYCssnbqpPX2wLPm4H76FJR5MwykUOOWBSErBvCmq5VhYQpcrajVJmuQuM4FVRyYuHqX-xFJRhchbUjktN34waZLKqsOdElynB5AuRtE2b-"></figure>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>What does the Om Mani Padme Hum Mantra mean?</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The Mantra, Om Mani Padme Hum, translates to praise to the jewel in the lotus. Each syllable has its own meaning too:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --></p>
<h4>Om - Purifies ego.</h4>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Om is perhaps the most powerful and ancient word used in meditation and chants. It's believed that the frequency/vibration of this syllable connects your soul to the creator. It is used to purify or cleanse. It's also believed to detach the ego, so the soul can temporarily stay and reconnect with divinity.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --></p>
<h4>Ma - Purifies jealousy.</h4>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Ma represents ethics and is a cleaner of jealous tendencies. It aids you in releasing attachments and provides you with the energies that initiate compassion.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --></p>
<h4>Ni - Purifies desire.</h4>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Ni represents one's patience and compassion. It purifies the passionate emotions of want and desire.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --></p>
<h4>Pad - Purifies ignorance.</h4>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Pad represents diligence. It purifies ignorance and lets you release your prejudices, so you no longer stand in judgment of others.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --></p>
<h4>Me - Purifies greed.</h4>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Me represents concentration. It provides you the ability to disconnect yourself from various earthly attachments, such as greed.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --></p>
<h4>Hum - Purifies hatred.</h4>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Hum represents the unification of all things. It is the energy that diffuses inner wisdom and purifies hate by letting you release negative thoughts of hatred and aggressive desires.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>With all these, the Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra ring may:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Conduct good luck and fortune</li>
<li>Enhance wealth and riches</li>
<li>Bring unexpected windfall luck</li>
<li>Protect individuals and building</li>
<li>Protect against evil forces, obstacles, and hardship</li>
<li>Generate good Feng Shui or earth luck</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How do you wear a Pixiu ring?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In Chinese culture and tradition, rings don't only function as an accessory. You should also wear them on the right finger as each one has significance and meaning.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For a Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring, it is best to wear it on your <strong>right middle finger</strong>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/0cMcuPx1hfzsfkyZBdepzvhR91V2c6New82F7ryepZKm5NR_8_fO6A-TrqEkialdYNy3qLSQNaSC0v0Of6GssprZtPkZC_9-x9wyzbI3UAGKFI88UTmHQTaxFrZaPaOLkfv2DJVV" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 0cMcuPx1hfzsfkyZBdepzvhR91V2c6New82F7ryepZKm5NR_8_fO6A-TrqEkialdYNy3qLSQNaSC0v0Of6GssprZtPkZC_9-x9wyzbI3UAGKFI88UTmHQTaxFrZaPaOLkfv2DJVV"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Placing a feng shui ring on your middle finger connects the gap between that finger and the index finger, right where the palm's Wealth Line runs. So it helps to strike a balance and is linked to responsibility. <strong>It is believed that a ring worn on the middle finger attracts money by increasing your money luck and assists you in accumulating wealth.</strong> Thus, making it perfect for a Pixiu Mantra ring. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Be careful <strong>not to wear this ring on your thumb</strong> because it is believed that a ring on the thumb will rob you of all wealth and sabotage your career success.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Where should Pixiu be placed?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When wearing the Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra ring, Pixiu must be placed on your finger's top center with it facing outwards. If it's in your right hand, Pixiu should face to the right. If it's in your left hand, Pixiu should face to the left.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Wearing Pixiu outwards symbolizes going out to gather wealth, luck and bring it back for you. Do not wear it facing towards yourself.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are also a few things you need to remember when wearing a Pixiu accessory. Just like the popular <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/index.php/2020/08/12/feng-shui-black-obsidian-bracelet-how-does-it-work/">Pixiu Black Obsidian Bracelet</a>, a Pixiu Mantra ring also requires a few maintenance steps before using and when not in use. Feng Shui experts believe that Pixiu will remain devoted to its master when it's well taken care of. Once neglected, Pixiu can choose to fly away. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>How to activate your Pixiu Mantra ring</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/XikziQlgnibW644Tn5F003jnvki1Cghqw-SLD_7Eu7_HCqhOg5zphdndw2rkRI4B_AfnwDRE1IJmj1RRF1NnHHO15LBS_UVe4Zxv_WuNP-ONKX_PD4rZd5IAhWo6-EA58-bRlj4_" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is XikziQlgnibW644Tn5F003jnvki1Cghqw-SLD_7Eu7_HCqhOg5zphdndw2rkRI4B_AfnwDRE1IJmj1RRF1NnHHO15LBS_UVe4Zxv_WuNP-ONKX_PD4rZd5IAhWo6-EA58-bRlj4_"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To activate your Pixiu Mantra ring, you'll need a silver bowl and a few pieces of gold (coins or other gold items), precious gems, or jewelry. Fill the bowl with these items and place it in your living room (never your bedroom). When not in use, put your Pixiu Mantra ring in the silver bowl with Pixiu facing your front door. It helps Pixiu draw more riches towards your home.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When in use, you must also give it attention by touching Pixiu a few times a day to bring luck and good fortune. Be careful not to touch its eyes and mouth. According to legends, touching Pixiu's mouth may ruin the owner's wealth. There's even an ancient Chinese saying that illustrates how to handle Pixiu:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong><em>"Touch Pixiu once, good luck comes.</em></strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong><em>Twice money rolls in.</em></strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong><em>Three times, promotions all the way up!"</em></strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What finger do you wear a lucky ring on?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>As I mentioned earlier, in Chinese culture, rings must be worn on the correct finger as they have various meanings. The same goes for Feng Shui. Wearing the ring on the right finger has many superstitious beliefs. Here are they:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/ogvE2EHpTxMvp9U9Ou6unguiIAcKIpl1rq2HVq6U7mzWgoSLT_uJSX_P91iiJHk7mWQyNM75SLsHZeUVImEUASvKmVVgC1UgoRjRhxWLjkjBB5ZnALHjTsFzTQOr3yQlV-Sqjnmo" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is ogvE2EHpTxMvp9U9Ou6unguiIAcKIpl1rq2HVq6U7mzWgoSLT_uJSX_P91iiJHk7mWQyNM75SLsHZeUVImEUASvKmVVgC1UgoRjRhxWLjkjBB5ZnALHjTsFzTQOr3yQlV-Sqjnmo"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Appropriate hand</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The appropriate hand used for wearing a ring depends on the yin (female) yang (male) symbol. To attract the best Feng Shui energies, men should wear rings on their left hands. Women should wear their rings on their right hands.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>The fingers</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Index finger</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In Feng Shui, the index finger is known as the finger of authority. Choosing to put a ring on this finger is regarded as a way to demonstrate social standing, power, and authority. It is best for people in sales or business and for someone seeking a promotion or a raise.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Middle finger</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Wearing a ring on the middle finger attracts money by increasing your money luck and accumulating wealth. It is also known to help strike a balance and is associated with responsibility.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Ring finger</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The ring finger is known to attract everlasting love, so it is most connected to marriage and engagement. For Singles, you should avoid wearing a ring on this finger to prevent misunderstanding.  Instead, you can wear a yellow gold ring on your index finger (left male, right female).</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When you meet the love of your life, move this ring to your middle finger to guarantee your relationship will move closer to marriage and your ring finger.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/d2FrnOWLX1DiVQAuhwC5SM6qVKVQZMDK-MZmiDl7FVkxSZG-32wvIosmY0PeGea5WMlcwG3K9J3NlAd94xYMrDCGRjd7Za98S1dSCDyVs_5kguhmRY7DIH55IdOvDN1I3Km86e52" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is d2FrnOWLX1DiVQAuhwC5SM6qVKVQZMDK-MZmiDl7FVkxSZG-32wvIosmY0PeGea5WMlcwG3K9J3NlAd94xYMrDCGRjd7Za98S1dSCDyVs_5kguhmRY7DIH55IdOvDN1I3Km86e52"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Little/pinky finger</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Wearing a jade ring on your little/pinky finger is believed to bring you wealth. You should wear the lucky ring on your left hand for males, and for females, you should wear it on your right hand. Besides that, it is also said to protect you from villains and backstabbers.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Thumb finger</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Some cultures believe the thumb represents longevity and health and advise to wear a ring on this finger. However, in Feng Shui, it is recommended to never wear a ring on this finger. It is believed that a ring on the thumb will take away all your wealth and sabotage your career success.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Can I wear Pixiu to sleep?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are two instances where you should NEVER wear your Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra ring: when bathing and sleeping.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When not in use, place it in your living room, on the silver bowl I mentioned earlier. Remember, Pixiu should be facing your front door or a window to attract wealth luck towards you.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here are other things you should remember when wearing a Pixiu Mantra ring:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Do not allow others to touch it as it could disconnect from you. When someone else touches your ring, cleanse it with water.</li>
<li>Don't let your Pi Xiu be contaminated by blood. Otherwise, its money-drawing effect could be ruined.</li>
<li>People aged under 16 and over 70 should not wear a Pixiu Mantra ring as they might not control the vital energy from the fierce creature.</li>
<li>Pregnant women should not wear any Pixiu accessories. They can do this after giving birth.</li>
<li>When wearing Pixiu, remember to touch it frequently to let it know you are its master.</li>
<li>Don't eat chili while wearing Pi Xiu because it can ruin your luck in making money.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Should you wear a Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Now that you know many things about the Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra ring, You can try out its luck and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DATOO-Adjustable-Mantra-Protection-Wealth/dp/B07SSH2K1S">purchase one</a>. But do take note of the responsibilities attached to this ring. You must be ready to do it for you to maximize its wealth-attracting effects. </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Maneki-Neko: The Famous Lucky Cat</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.luckycathome.com/maneki-neko-the-famous-lucky-cat/"/>
        <id>https://www.luckycathome.com/maneki-neko-the-famous-lucky-cat/</id>

        <updated>2022-08-29T20:25:05-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Have you ever been to a Chinese or Japanese section of an Asian store? If you have, there's&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/27bpp3n-Bg_enskLPXEwLGoykX37jj6TK_ipwzwx6VGJrFzt5BFwW06cL9X0n3XFpApIN80-28uFnL-RJZxwt0wroKFa4-nbPi1cOetggJ_5WrTlkW4KSlT7dLEkh4Gx6Y5VnPWf" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 27bpp3n-Bg_enskLPXEwLGoykX37jj6TK_ipwzwx6VGJrFzt5BFwW06cL9X0n3XFpApIN80-28uFnL-RJZxwt0wroKFa4-nbPi1cOetggJ_5WrTlkW4KSlT7dLEkh4Gx6Y5VnPWf"></p>
<p>Have you ever been to a Chinese or Japanese section of an Asian store? If you have, there's a big chance you've seen that adorable waving cat figurine quietly perched on the counter. Many people know this as the Lucky Cat or the Fortune Cat, but it actually has a name - it's Maneki Neko (招き猫).</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Aside from being a symbol of fortune, there's actually more to this cat than most people know. And being a curious cat myself, I decided to dig deeper into this cute kitty of luck. Join me as we learn more of Maneki Neko, and see how it helps one attract good fortune.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What is Maneki-Neko?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Maneki Neko is a Japanese phrase that literally translates as "beckoning cat." Traditionally, it depicts a calico Japanese Bobtail cat and is often believed to bring good luck to the owner. You'll commonly see this cat figurine with one paw raised in the air as if it's waving.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>These figurines are commonly displayed in shops and other businesses because they are known to bring good luck and attract more customers. Hence, the name Lucky Cat, Fortune Cat, Money Cat, etc.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Brief History</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The origins of Maneki-Neko goes back to the <strong>Edo Period</strong> in Japan (17th century to the mid-19th century). There are many famous legends about the origins of the Maneki Neko. Still, the most popular one is said to be about a wealthy lord named Ii Naotaka.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/JkSDkKaCYOUFdcaukvPU72bzSGizrU7z07LN_5TviS7o1qDWvpyKHB7XSVwo6sEGn2XWYEMoR0feZmgo09WBe9V2ZDxVJjzTAL8yo3wd_KTKcemTuY57HBlA34aEnu6CoFjT1iS1" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is JkSDkKaCYOUFdcaukvPU72bzSGizrU7z07LN_5TviS7o1qDWvpyKHB7XSVwo6sEGn2XWYEMoR0feZmgo09WBe9V2ZDxVJjzTAL8yo3wd_KTKcemTuY57HBlA34aEnu6CoFjT1iS1"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>According to the legends, Ii Naotaka tried to shelter himself from the rain by going under a tree near the Gotoku-Ji temple. Lord Ii saw the priest's cat, named Hanako, beckoning at him and decided to follow him to the temple.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Just then, a strong lightning bolt struck the tree he took shelter in only moments earlier. Moved by his luck, Lord Ii was so thankful for the cat that had saved his life befriended the priest. Lord Ii became a benefactor of the temple and brought much prosperity to Gotoku-Ji with his gifts.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When Hanako passed away, they buried him in a special graveyard for cats. In the temple, a Maneki-Neko statue was made to commemorate this special cat and has been revered ever since.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Fun fact:</strong> The Gotoku-Ji Temple, located in the Setagaya ward of Tokyo, is known as the birthplace on Maneki-Neko, and when you decide to visit this temple in Japan, you'll see tons of this Maneki-Neko figurines in one corner of the temple. They come in different sizes too.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Tourists can even buy a lucky cat figurine, make a wish or prayer for good luck on it, and leave it on the temple with the rest of the figurines. You can also take them home and keep them until the wish has been fulfilled. When that happens, it is advised to go back to Gotokuji and put the cat figurine back at the temple to give thanks.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>How to pronounce Maneki-Neko?</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Maneki-Neko (招き猫) is a Japanese term and is pronounced as:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>招 (mahne) き (keeh) 猫 (nehko).</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Ma-Neh-Key Neh-Ko.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Not</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Man-e-key Knee-ko.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Is Maneki Neko Chinese or Japanese?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Because of its popularity in the Chinese community, Maneki-Neko is often mistaken to be of Chinese origin. It was even known as the 'Chinese Lucky Cat' or jīnmāo ("golden cat").</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>But that's not true. Maneki-Neko <strong>originated in Japan, not China</strong>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/PmbVcLzbV3evpPKIwYAm3n7csDM1C0k3NLjAgUfHl7H_vyH-dbGiKB4EQ4WnKEontbtNgcUZtycrQ_G1jsMDbHHMmuS_pH394BTQ2AtLnqbhdm1Z8viGKMOjv4KPSemBfZbFa8Rd" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is PmbVcLzbV3evpPKIwYAm3n7csDM1C0k3NLjAgUfHl7H_vyH-dbGiKB4EQ4WnKEontbtNgcUZtycrQ_G1jsMDbHHMmuS_pH394BTQ2AtLnqbhdm1Z8viGKMOjv4KPSemBfZbFa8Rd"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This lucky cat somehow reached the straights of China, where it became popular with many businesses. There was even an old Chinese proverb saying that if a cat washes its face, it will rain. Thus, there is a possibility that the belief of a cat washing its face would bring in customers was brought by this proverb.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>China's Tang Dynasty author, Duan Chengshi, wrote in his Miscellaneous Morsels from Youyang: "If a cat raises its paw above the ears and washes its face, then patrons will come." Statues of cats washing their faces were found as early as the Northern Wei Dynasty (386 to 534 AD).</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What gender is Maneki-Neko?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There is <strong>no specific gender</strong> recorded for Maneki-Neko, so it can be either male or female.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The most famous Maneki-Neko cat breed is the Calico Japanese Bobtail. And since most calico cats are female, people assume that Maneki-Neko is female. However, since there are many varieties of Maneki-Neko (which we will talk about later), that isn't necessarily true.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What does the raised paw of the Maneki-Neko mean?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You'll often see a Maneki-Neko holding one paw up in the air like a waving position. But it's actually different from waving (which is done side to side). The Japanese style beckoning gesture is made by holding up one hand, palm down, and folding the fingers down and up repeatedly.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Because of the difference in body language and gestures recognized by Westerners and the Japanese, a Lucky Cat with the cat's paw facing upwards, in a beckoning gesture, was made to be more familiar with Westerners.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-v7wFT0KWNZYIJBwk0mGQ_Y8cCsF4VEvJ8LlW_XUzm4gbpkbTp-_VJ9dldKwvHFUvqxdjMR85bUx3sCxJ8w0iqEjM_UhOVLMtyHIfh64h1MhZQ5maXLJR93YlUGYvva0oxkAPC42" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is -v7wFT0KWNZYIJBwk0mGQ_Y8cCsF4VEvJ8LlW_XUzm4gbpkbTp-_VJ9dldKwvHFUvqxdjMR85bUx3sCxJ8w0iqEjM_UhOVLMtyHIfh64h1MhZQ5maXLJR93YlUGYvva0oxkAPC42"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Different paws raised</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Different Maneki-Neko figures have different paw positions. There's a raised right paw, raised left paw, and sometimes both. Each of these actually has its own meaning.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Right paw raised</strong> - This is the most common one. A raised right paw is believed to attract wealth and good luck.</li>
<li><strong>Left paw raised</strong> - The raised left paw is known to attract customers and invite people to come. This is commonly used in business establishments.</li>
<li><strong>Both paws raised</strong> - A lucky cat with both paws raised is said to be a combination of both and gives protection from evil.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>No matter what paw is raised on you, Maneki-Neko, it is believed that the higher the paw is raised, the more luck the cat is to invite!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Aside from having one paw raised permanently in the air, there are also new Maneki-Neko figurines with battery-operated or solar-powered arms that move back and forth, making it endlessly engaged in the beckoning gesture.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What do the different colors of Maneki-Neko mean?</h1>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/rpfHysWUu3tecZoGT-7eaxPGqhRtFA3C_NclozW1u4UdJ_fRB_3pPG05AYKYXP6ovcOEIRfauOCIZ8JigvMhkZUTbNDcOU4nLLcii5ubG_yk2oLuJk3m6gipUTCYxyb2auszfG2E" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is rpfHysWUu3tecZoGT-7eaxPGqhRtFA3C_NclozW1u4UdJ_fRB_3pPG05AYKYXP6ovcOEIRfauOCIZ8JigvMhkZUTbNDcOU4nLLcii5ubG_yk2oLuJk3m6gipUTCYxyb2auszfG2E"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Over the years, there have been multiple colors of Maneki-Neko seen in the market. These colors actually have different meanings and are targeted towards various aspects of your life.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>1. Tri-color / Calico</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The calico is the traditional and most common type of Maneki-Neko. It is modeled from the Japanese Bobtail cat and is known to bring general good fortune to its owner.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>2. White</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The all-white Maneki-Neko is believed to bring happiness, purity, and positivity for things to come.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>3. Gold</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The golden cat is said to bring vast wealth to the person lucky enough to own it.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>4. Red</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The red Lucky cat is known to ward off illness, especially in children.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>5. Pink</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The pink cat is for those who are in search of romance because it is supposed to beckon love into your life.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>6. Green</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The green Maneki-Neko is for those who wish for good health and wellness.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>7. Blue</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The blue cat is used to attract intelligence, wisdom, and success.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>8. Yellow</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The yellow Lucky Cat is for people who are looking for stability in health and relationships.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>9. Black</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This is probably the most interesting one. In western culture, black cats are known as a symbol of bad luck. However, the black Maneki-Neko is known to keep away stalkers and general evil.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What is written on Maneki-Neko?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Maneki-Neko figurines are often seen holding an oval-shaped metal plate with an inscription on it. This golden metal plate is actually a golden coin modeled after a Koban, a gold coin used in the Edo Period. One Koban is equivalent to one Ryo, which is roughly $1,000 by today's standards. There are different inscriptions seen on these Ryo coins. Here are some of them:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/zU7yh2SXqmNHepp3kIt8G5ss0Vm0h32oDrEJ8iH_hUAxQOM0_c-ffBrgop7LQMHaZYkYLDxcB9ilYzGZx72NI1wJ86iPlU01sUrIWLMZscLrv5-lRY35RxQGeHeVnO7DleP7ab_x" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is zU7yh2SXqmNHepp3kIt8G5ss0Vm0h32oDrEJ8iH_hUAxQOM0_c-ffBrgop7LQMHaZYkYLDxcB9ilYzGZx72NI1wJ86iPlU01sUrIWLMZscLrv5-lRY35RxQGeHeVnO7DleP7ab_x"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sen Man Ryo</strong> (千万両) - This means 10,000,000 Ryo, which is an incredible amount of money, especially during that period.</li>
<li><strong>Kai Un</strong> (開運) - This means "open luck."</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Some Maneki-Neko figurines also have banners held by one hand or stuck right on their front. These banners also show various inscriptions which read as one of the following:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/Y1W7HRhm0C2pvXbp5kIMV_6-tBGa_5TLDnUufkkc92uffM5LCsCmObSvIYDCyLH5PefZeiHkK2_x7OK50TzDfz3m59KwhISMbagq3C2bhwYQJ1FsORjUnG3TyZTwDpsX5NRVtPCE" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is Y1W7HRhm0C2pvXbp5kIMV_6-tBGa_5TLDnUufkkc92uffM5LCsCmObSvIYDCyLH5PefZeiHkK2_x7OK50TzDfz3m59KwhISMbagq3C2bhwYQJ1FsORjUnG3TyZTwDpsX5NRVtPCE"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Genkin Manpuku</strong> (現金満腹) - Literally translated as "bellyful of cash," which means getting even more wealth than you've wished for.</li>
<li><strong>Sen Kyaku Man Mai</strong> (千客萬来) - Literally means "1000 customers come." This is commonly seen on Maneki Neko displayed on business establishments.</li>
<li><strong>Shou Bai Han Jyou</strong> (商売繁盛) - This means "thriving business." Another variety usually used in businesses.</li>
<li><strong>Kin-Un Sho Fuku</strong> (金運 拐福) - This means "to invite in luck in money."</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Other Maneki-Neko Accessories</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Aside from gold coins and banners with Kanji inscriptions, Maneki-Nekos is also seen holding and wearing many other accessories. Some of them are as follows:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>1. <strong>Fish</strong> (carp, koi, etc.) - Fishes like carp and koi are known to be a symbol of fortune and abundance.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/YtXA1HE-IwBB4GgeX_0abjEv56I-Uu27LUl7yIvjCmE7Ye7oOsxrUS6v7_MZprJYYEn8ecNshy_zX81w8U8vgS0DIyLPFTh2Dscpn2tXiM--YvflkITAVYGyWLw15cchiUnUul8H" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is YtXA1HE-IwBB4GgeX_0abjEv56I-Uu27LUl7yIvjCmE7Ye7oOsxrUS6v7_MZprJYYEn8ecNshy_zX81w8U8vgS0DIyLPFTh2Dscpn2tXiM--YvflkITAVYGyWLw15cchiUnUul8H"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>2.<strong> Money Bag</strong> - Money bags symbolize wealth, and good luck.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>3. <strong>Fan</strong> - This object represents luck in businesses.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>4. <strong>Drum</strong> - The drum symbolizes a shop that is overflowing with customers.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>5. <strong>Hollowed Gourds (Hyotan)</strong> - The Hyotan is used as a container for Japanese sake and other beverages. This object is also used by Fukurokuju, one of the Seven Lucky Gods who represents wisdom and longevity. The Hyotan is known to cast out evil and bring good luck.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/LFc-rsZyqTfE3Q9qxMpobOlvxV5iMA69yR-qBu9Fv8Rw2iDa_KiM-hc8K89Ziq-ynxE6DRg-E4z2a6yY49WxuqmekWXTEZD3wVos18ehZ_Vhe7v4j46WV-StsB_MKDMtN92_7_yR" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is LFc-rsZyqTfE3Q9qxMpobOlvxV5iMA69yR-qBu9Fv8Rw2iDa_KiM-hc8K89Ziq-ynxE6DRg-E4z2a6yY49WxuqmekWXTEZD3wVos18ehZ_Vhe7v4j46WV-StsB_MKDMtN92_7_yR"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>6. <strong>Small mallet</strong> - A small mallet or hammer represents a magic money mallet that is believed to attract wealth when shaken.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>7. <strong>Gemstone or marble</strong> - A Maneko-Neki holding a marble or a gem is believed to attract wisdom and fortune to the owner.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>8. <strong>Bib and bell</strong> - These are usually worn on the neck of Maneki-Neko and are believed to represent protection, wealth, and material abundance.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Why do Japanese people buy Maneki Neko?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Maneki-Neko became widely popular among Japanese, Chinese, and other Asian countries because of its superstitious wealth attracting abilities. It’s even widely used in the practice of <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/index.php/2020/08/12/feng-shui-basics-attracting-positive-energy-into-your-home/">Feng Shui</a>. Many Japanese people buy the Maneki-Neko and use it as a charm to attract good luck and fortune for its owners. It's also very commonly used as display figures inside businesses in Japan.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Japan is also known to be obsessed with cats (just like their number one character export, Hello Kitty). Not only because they're cute, but the Lucky Cat's popularity is also partly because cats are a part of the Japanese folklore. They are believed to have protective powers and symbolize good fortune.  Truly, the spirit of Maneki-Neko.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Maneki-Neko popularity in Japan</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Festivals</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This lucky cat is widely adored in Japan. In fact, in the city of Seto, in Aichi Prefecture, they celebrate a Maneki-Neko themed festival named "Kuru fuku Maneki-Neko matsuri (Festival of coming fortune and Maneki-Neko)." The festival is held annually on September 29.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/4BeIGpcKao2hhN1s4z7FFvsWlaGfmxoDCBMjtfprTGltGHkdV_W0Epfchk049Ile8e7HMs9etrznuyWWC-g1kzvkTSlKImTXIKuVnn4hyr2uGQNNP5FY1j_AWbkEXcEoB8iaiLWG" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is 4BeIGpcKao2hhN1s4z7FFvsWlaGfmxoDCBMjtfprTGltGHkdV_W0Epfchk049Ile8e7HMs9etrznuyWWC-g1kzvkTSlKImTXIKuVnn4hyr2uGQNNP5FY1j_AWbkEXcEoB8iaiLWG"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There's also a "Maneki-Neko Art Exhibition," where they offer lunches in Lucky Cat shaped boxes and paint Maneki-Neko face makeup on for free at the festival. This city has massive production of Maneki-Neko ornaments with various "Fuku-Neko (good-luck cat)" ornaments hidden around 29 locations in the city.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Lucky Cat Train</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A "Lucky Maneki-Neko Train" was also made on the 110th anniversary of the Tokyu-Setagaya line, which goes by Gotoku-Ji Temple. The entire train was designed with Maneki-Neko from inside-out.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You'll also find dozens of Maneki-Neko themed items such as sweets, noodles, dishes, boxes, pouches, and even statues.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Where can I buy Maneki-Neko?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Aside from the traditional figurines, there are tons of Maneki-Neko products you can buy. Many Asian souvenir shops have Lucky Cat products, especially in Chinese or Japanese souvenir shops.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Maneki-Neko shops in Japan</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you're planning to visit Japan or are currently in Japan, here are some of the best places where you can buy Maneki-Neko products.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<h3>Gotoku-Ji Temple </h3>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Known as the birthplace of Maneki-Neko, you can buy cat figurines in this temple and make a wish on it. The Gotoku-Ji temple is located in Setagaya City in Tokyo.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/PEwo1dC1LMSMxScPhB1I6K6zwms4DLlq8XukeQOUoAe13Hh7wAziShChCWCpW4_WLRfFUPXaNO9Rfp3h0NsOKHVUTOaaq0eCaVIOTFwyR1sUGO7bB4RyuyPoiHaZxFtOMKmVKF3_" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is PEwo1dC1LMSMxScPhB1I6K6zwms4DLlq8XukeQOUoAe13Hh7wAziShChCWCpW4_WLRfFUPXaNO9Rfp3h0NsOKHVUTOaaq0eCaVIOTFwyR1sUGO7bB4RyuyPoiHaZxFtOMKmVKF3_"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<h3>Tohiken</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This is one of the famous sweets shops that sell Maneki-Neko inspired goodies. You will find some lucky cat-shaped butter cookies, Manju or some DIY Monaka – the Anko (sweet red bean paste) filling and wafers. You can find this shop near the Gotoku-Ji Temple in Setagaya.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<h3>Koide Shoten a.k.a. Orner Koide</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This shop specializes in Maneki-Neko souvenirs. A variety of Lucky Cat products in different kinds, styles, and prices can be found here, like figurines, chimes, wall paintings, and more. Their store is located in Kappabashi-Dori, or Tokyo's Kitchen Street in Matsugaya, Taito-Ku, Tokyo.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you can't visit their physical store, you can also order their products from <a href="https://www.rakuten.ne.jp/gold/manekineko-orner/">Rakuten</a>.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<h3>Imado Shrine</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Another place where Maneki-Neko was believed to have originated is in the Imado Shrine. The origin story involving the cat, the Geisha, and the snake was said to have taken place here. This shrine is a popular tourist destination, especially to people seeking good luck in love and marriage. It's because it enshrines a deity couple: Izanagi and his spouse, Izanami.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/tzfsl-h303elrIExmhBvG48yC6XX4Z54SX1QzwztStzGRIyXon2QLRUXv3fHoJxtPKmXwj5DlBcSfJEMO-65pmyYfXu8SwhREiuizNLXU0V-oLJHs4P5EHOuR0ELNOneA4-OY4FU" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is tzfsl-h303elrIExmhBvG48yC6XX4Z54SX1QzwztStzGRIyXon2QLRUXv3fHoJxtPKmXwj5DlBcSfJEMO-65pmyYfXu8SwhREiuizNLXU0V-oLJHs4P5EHOuR0ELNOneA4-OY4FU"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Besides having tons of feline imagery, including Maneki-Neko, you can find feline figurines for sale in this shrine. You can find the Imado Shrine in Imado, Taito-Ku, Tokyo.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<h3>Nekoemon Café</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For cat cafe lovers who have a creative touch, you can visit Nekoemon Café. This is a cat lover's haven. You'll find high-quality figurines, handkerchiefs, and cups with Maneki-Neko imagery. You can even buy an entire rack of 'birthday Maneki-Neko,' which are little lucky cat keychains with various designs depending on your date of birth.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also buy and paint your own Maneki-Neko figure in this shop. Visit this cafe in Yanaka, Taito-Ku, Tokyo.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<h3>Sweets Necoemon</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Located just right beside Nekoemon Café, you can find different Maneki-Neko sweets and pastry goodies in this shop. There are cat-shaped cakes, cookies, and other adorable goods. You can buy your snack here and head over to its sister shop, Nekoemon Café, to get Lucky Cat souvenirs.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This shop is also located in Yanaka, Taito-Ku, Tokyo.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Other Lucky Cat shops</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you can't visit these shops in Japan but still want some Maneki-Neko products, you can just order them online through different shops like <a href="https://manekinekoworld.com/">Maneki-Neko World</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Maneki-Money-Chinese-Japanese-Statue/dp/B003V1GBBC">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.etsy.com/market/maneki_neko">Etsy</a>, <a href="https://www.ebay.com/t/Collectible-Japanese-Maneki-Neko-1900-Now/165472/bn_3124222">eBay</a>, and more.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Which Maneki-Neko is for housewarming?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Giving Maneki-Neko as a gift always a good idea (especially when the recipient is a cat lover). We've talked about the different colors and accessories of Maneki-Neko, so you have to keep this in mind when thinking of giving one as a gift.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you want to give it as <strong>a housewarming gift</strong>, your best choice would be the classic<strong> tri-colored cat</strong>. Any of the accessories will be fine too (except for the fan and drum because it's mainly for businesses). </p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/SzCc9h6MZvDcHWKRHZ5W9iYYTMxObdsYb6ryz-r8hwKmShagcJuDg-oXBoRbzC2rYVQhIpLmv_RNBoeYL4Bp_AnGmETeNRuRxn0YUS4ueZ-IxaDXzdP58q9sPRZ_9uwM5qDKx5-i" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is SzCc9h6MZvDcHWKRHZ5W9iYYTMxObdsYb6ryz-r8hwKmShagcJuDg-oXBoRbzC2rYVQhIpLmv_RNBoeYL4Bp_AnGmETeNRuRxn0YUS4ueZ-IxaDXzdP58q9sPRZ_9uwM5qDKx5-i"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also go for the plain <strong>white cat</strong> if you want to wish them happiness. Or the <strong>blue cat</strong>, for peace, harmony, and happiness for the family members.. Or even the <strong>black cat</strong> if you're going to give the house owner some protection.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Just remember to always choose one made with quality materials, whether it may be ceramic, wood, metal, paper, etc. You may also want to consider ones that have modern designs and a cheerful face to make them more pleasant looking.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Where to place a Maneki-Neko?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Suppose you want to place a Maneki-Neko inside your business establishment. It should automatically be placed near the front door or a public entrance where all who enter can see it. This will help attract more customers as well as good fortune into your business. If that's not possible, you can alternatively put in the North-East of the business premises.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Having a Maneki-Neko displayed in your house, room or office could also help attract good luck and fortune. However, placement is different from that of a business. Consider the <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/index.php/2020/08/13/feng-shui-bed-placement-tips-for-good-luck/">proper placement</a> of this Lucky Cat if you want to get the best out of it.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Furthermore, the different colored cats should be placed in various places too. Here are some tips on where and how to put them correctly.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Note: Consider <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/index.php/2020/08/12/how-to-use-a-feng-shui-compass/">using a compass</a> to locate the directions accurately.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Tri-color Cat</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This classic Lucky Cat is best kept on the <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/index.php/2020/08/14/3-easy-ways-to-find-your-feng-shui-wealth-corner/">wealth corner</a> of your house, usually in your house's Southeast direction.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>White Cat</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can place the white Maneki-Neko in the Northwest part of your home to bring good connections and travel opportunities. You can also put in the North direction for income and opportunity.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Gold Cat</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you wish for more fortune and good luck in your home, you can put the gold Maneki-Neko in the wealth corner or Southeast. You can also put it in the Northwest part of the house for the breadwinner or the man of the house for better networking opportunities. For generating more income, salary increases, or business opportunities, place it in the North direction.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This golden cat can also be used to wish for prosperity and creativity for your children. Do this by placing it on the West corner of your home.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Pink and Red Cats</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you're wishing to enhance your romantic relationship, place these Lucky Cats in the Southwest part of the house. You can also attract fame if you put it in the South corner of your home.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Black and Blue Cat</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can set your Black or Blue cats in the North direction for prosperity. For protecting and enhancing health, place it in the East. But if you want to activate wealth and protect the female of the house (example: a pregnant wife), put it in the southwest corner.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Green Cat</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Enhance your education, travel, writing, and romance by placing a green Maneki-Neko in the South or Southeast part of the house. It can also be set in the South area to enhance your fame and success.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What should you do with a broken Maneki-Neko?</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you happened to have one of those ceramic Maneki-Neko figurines and it gets broken or shattered, it's best to replace it with a new one. Mainly because in Feng Shui, it's considered unlucky to keep broken or chipped items in your home.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/NnMbPyG8ze8RbCxawbDkEo7qBuQHWsXM5EXYQvIxO9NEtJN708xnNOYOG4w_tJzEUErB4vac58kAsFpFNwb_Oohn86-IwMFbsBI3ufpVyim1Jvm0dNh3ns712MHAL3zisjdDBd2k" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is NnMbPyG8ze8RbCxawbDkEo7qBuQHWsXM5EXYQvIxO9NEtJN708xnNOYOG4w_tJzEUErB4vac58kAsFpFNwb_Oohn86-IwMFbsBI3ufpVyim1Jvm0dNh3ns712MHAL3zisjdDBd2k"></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>But if it's the battery-operated Maneki-Neko where the arms are moving, the most common problem with it is the stopping of the arms. If this happens, you can check the batteries and try to replace them instead.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Get a Lucky cat for yourself!</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Lucky Cats or Maneki-Neko has appeared in various forms in pop culture. You can see them in literature, anime, and even video games. They are popping out almost everywhere, making their influence even more widespread.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>One great thing about that is you can find them quickly and get one for yourself. Whether it a figurine, a charm, a pouch, or any Lucky Cat-themed item is useful. Not to mention, they're incredibly adorable as well.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Try getting one for yourself and prepare to attract and welcome good luck and fortune on your way!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
