<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Lucky Cat Home</title>
    <link href="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome" />
    <updated>2022-08-28T18:59:45-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Melbren</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome</id>

    <entry>
        <title>How to Feng Shui Your Entryway: Top 8 Tips You Should Know</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/how-to-feng-shui-your-entryway-top-8-tips-you-should-know.html"/>
        <id>https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/how-to-feng-shui-your-entryway-top-8-tips-you-should-know.html</id>

        <updated>2022-08-28T18:59:45-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Doors are usually the first to greet you when you enter a home, an office, or pretty much&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/22/acIvrJQz-xqWn5r7XeBISJSDqc89BvGvLmiZ-dv7F2TrniQOQUaGwlJxah_nrSWsZpQIkgxie25hLdentCMSX4nUUC1Z0Mo0F2h6-IqqCSMpKrvaN49FEf24Doi1YoNHFJ9Peplh" alt=""></figure>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Doors are usually the first to greet you when you enter a home, an office, or pretty much anywhere. And in Feng Shui, the primary entryway holds a great deal of importance because it's where the <em>Chi</em> or the positive energy comes in.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In this article, we'll give you our top 8 tips on how you can Feng Shui your entryway.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #1: Activate your front door regularly</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/feng-shui-basics-attracting-positive-energy-into-your-home/">Feng Shui</a>, they consider the front as the portal of energy or the mouth of chi. Although there might be a backdoor or other doors that you use to go inside or outside, a home's official front door is still the mouth of chi.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>It's okay if you use the backdoor or some other doors daily, but never forget to activate your front door regularly. You can do this by passing through it daily or at least once every nine days. Opening and using the door is the most crucial part because if you're not using your front door, you block out energy and opportunities.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip # 2: Always consider the three elements that make up your entryway</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Entryways or your home's entrance have three essential elements: Door size, decor, and view. These three can affect the positive chi that enters your home.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Door size</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Your front door should be the largest door in your home. The bigger your door, the more chi can enter. But never forget to put the size of your home into consideration. It should still be in proportion to your house.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/22/1_TU-L43FnYjpcFYzjAHOziz0jwNskTxv6bDQXXSmm4HBATSAIdFXxo0F_xtsf94-HIjWhIgxZux5_gqhr5P0q6p9O3g1Dbcex1uaBElZ4FDFAiaU-ytAkmDhXj7bu2gGM3gDXf7" alt=""></figure>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Decor</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The welcoming decors of your entryway, such as the furniture, lightings, and others, should also be chosen carefully. We'll talk more about this later.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>View</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The view seen from your front door is also important. Ensure that the front door is not facing directly to the toilet, kitchen, or straight out to the back of your house. These are known as inauspicious views with your front door. If it somehow can't be avoided, you can place a curtain, standing screen, or plant to help slow down the sightline to an inauspicious view.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #3: Choose the right decor and furniture</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Each house has different entryways. Depending on how big or small your home is, your setup may be a lot different from others. But whether or not you have a spacious entryway, some decor and furniture would be suitable to attract positive chi energy. Here's what you should consider when picking them out.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Lights</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>It's essential to have proper lighting in your entryway. Good lighting can add beneficial energy to your home's entrance and lift its chi. You can elevate the lighting on your foyer by adding some lamps, a crystal chandelier, or some scones if possible. But if you want some minimalist and straightforward light fixture, just bright overhead lighting will do. What's important is to keep the space well illuminated and welcoming for anyone who's coming inside.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Artwork</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Add personality to your entryway by displaying lovely artwork. Choose ones that give a positive vibe to make the entrance calmer and inviting to people coming inside. You can also put a shelf or a small table underneath to give it a more homey vibe (given that you have a space for it). Avoid displaying personal objects like family pictures on your entryway. It's because this area is more public and easily seen from the outside, just a simple reminder to protect your privacy.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Elements</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also activate elements if you want to enhance a specific area in your life. Each sector represents a particular life area like wealth (southeast), fame/recognition (south), career (north), and so on. You can activate these energies by knowing the sector of your house's entrance and putting in the assigned element.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For example, if your entrance is facing north, it corresponds to your career. The north direction's governing element is water, so you can put a small fountain, an aquarium, or artworks that feature water to activate your career energy.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Plants</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"sizeSlug":"large"} --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/22/a9a0179a-4134-4e01-802e-d18cebe9279e" alt="Feng Shui your entryway with plants"></figure>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Incorporating plants into an area makes it a lot more vibrant and lively in an instant. You can also use plants as a barrier or protection from negative energies coming from outside or inauspicious views that can't be avoided. However, you must ensure that you choose the right kind of indoor plants and practice due diligence to maintain and nourish them.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Have a shoe rack</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you're the type who leaves shoes on your front door, it's best if you have a shoe rack or a cabinet where you can keep them. Never leave your shoes scattered near your front door as it is considered inauspicious.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Rugs</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Putting a welcoming rug or doormat on your front door is an excellent addition to your front door. It can give off an inviting feel instantly to the environment. Make sure your rug is low enough and allows the main door to open and close freely. You should also replace your rug or doormat with a new one at least once a year. Replacing the doormat will remove the accumulated negative Chi over the year.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can choose the color and material of the rug based on your door’s facing direction. Here are some ideas you can use:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Rug/doormat ideas based on your facing direction</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Direction</strong></td>
<td><strong>Element</strong></td>
<td><strong>Color</strong></td>
<td><strong>Shape</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>North</td>
<td>Water</td>
<td>Blue, Black</td>
<td>Round or wavy</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>South</td>
<td>Fire</td>
<td>Red, Purple, Orange</td>
<td>Angular shapes - triangles/stars</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>West / Northwest</td>
<td>Metal</td>
<td>White, Gray</td>
<td>Square or round</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>East / Southeast</td>
<td>Wood</td>
<td>Green, Brown</td>
<td>Rectangle</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Southwest / Northeast</td>
<td>Earth</td>
<td>Yellow</td>
<td>Square</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p><!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #4: Choose the right sector color</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/22/DagHEZCrebB63SKOTiyiIkJIR9tSxPjxXGl8KOVPb4PzSwnM9zNZwDIpChjH7te37i7-zsZEvrkUEzy7yyviKOutO0PmcC1k-E3tKJtiYpXHk_sq02CiSzH5KYHLD0XhdL3rIBwD" alt=""></figure>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Choosing the right colors is essential in Feng Shui. Having the right color in this sector can help enhance or elevate the positive energy that enters our home. Similarly, choosing the wrong colors can result in inauspicious energy, which is a big no-no.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can determine the right color for your entryway and front door by knowing your house's facing direction. You can do this by <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/how-to-use-a-feng-shui-compass/">using a Feng Shui compass</a> or an ordinary compass. Knowing your facing direction will help you determine the element that corresponds to your path. Thus, helping you select the color based on that element. Here are some of the perfect colors to use per direction.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>East </strong>- Green, Brown, Black, Blue, Purple</li>
<li><strong>Northeast </strong>- light Yellow, Beige, Clay, Red, Pink, Orange, Magenta, Coral</li>
<li><strong>North </strong>- Black, Blue, White, Gray, Metallic</li>
<li><strong>Northwest </strong>- Gray, White, Metallic, Clay, Beige, Light Yellow</li>
<li><strong>West </strong>- White, Gray, Metallic, Light Yellow, Beige, Clay</li>
<li><strong>Southwest</strong> - Beige, Clay, Light Yellow, Red, Pink, Orage, Magenta, Coral</li>
<li><strong>South</strong> - Yellow, Orange Pink, Coral, Magenta, Purple, Green, Brown</li>
<li><strong>Southeast</strong> - Green, Brown, Black, Blue, Light Yellow</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #5: Avoid Feng Shui mistakes that could drain your money from your home</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Activating your entryway to attract better chi inside your home could result in many positive things. But when you do it wrong, you might also break the right flow of chi, causing an unwanted imbalance in your home. Some mistakes could even result in financial problems, making money drain faster from your home.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here are some common Feng Shui mistakes to avoid if you don't want to encounter this problem.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>The fireplace is visible from the front door.</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Having your fireplace visible from the front door or directly in-line with the front door is inauspicious in Feng Shui. It means you're burning through money from the fireplace.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>The toilet is visible from the front door.</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/22/A3m0SwNU7zX2VsHg22vJ4QRtWs0KHi5s8NfpCYm2X0C1FBHHNSktZli7DoWjy8gzZU22z82Wr7kjsEzljCr3neRzOejV5185dNYZsld0GvOnkZNUmx7f8kXcdlkmJD3rc1kFuQoU" alt=""></figure>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Having a visible view of the toilet from your front door is also considered inauspicious and can cause money loss in Feng Shui. The money will fail to accrue if this happens. You can fix this by putting a standing screen, a plant, or any object that could block the view of the toilet view so that the chi won't flow right through.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The same thing could happen if you have a second floor and the toilet is directly above your entryway. In case you have this at home, you can keep the entryway light on to help lift the wealth and income chi at your front door.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>The backdoor is directly in-line with the front door.</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In Feng Shui, one of the most common ways to lose wealth and money is when your house has a poison arrow. A poison arrow is used in Feng Shui to describe when your front door is in-line with the back door or a window. Poison arrows may cause your money to drain quickly, so it's best to avoid this mistake.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>But if you encounter this mishap at home, you can also fix it by blocking the back door or window view using a standing screen, curtain, plant, etc.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #6: Use mirrors strategically</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>People often use mirrors to make spaces look bigger by reflecting surfaces and light. Mirrors are good decor in Feng Shui as it reflects and doubles the energy in an area. But remember that mirrors don't reflect selectively, it reflects everything - both positive and negative. You can place mirrors on your entryway but make sure that it's not reflecting your front door. It will result in the energy bouncing back out when it enters, pushing the chi energy and wealth away.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Place it somewhere that doesn't reflect your front door, sharp edges, or any other door. You should also check other mirrors in your house and make sure they don't reflect your main entrance at any angle.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #7: Check your stairs</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/22/XDOYRjMJJCsgFryIhHLttys-DHkoxu-dsQg95EZyA00A9F-j6IB9wyfNIsUe6kkvJTLRTsVptMG0Tf5tmObJmn7kqpxqFgcxWeMLFsR75GO5F0ZtSJ7-ywuBcQWeZlweDU2ZBdng" alt=""></figure>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Having your <a href="https://www.nst.com.my/property/2018/07/392311/feng-shui-stairway-rules-balance-energy" class="rank-math-link">staircase facing the front door directly</a> isn't a good sign in Feng Shui. If your staircase is right in front of the main entrance, it could result in the energy rushing quickly upstairs or downstairs and not going onto the main floor. It will leave the main floor empty of the positive chi energy it's supposed to have.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In case you have this problem, you can still fix it by placing proper decor and furniture onto your entryway. Use decors that could slow down the energy and guide it to the areas that need positive energy. You can use artwork, plants, mirrors, and other items appropriate for your wealth corner.  </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tip #8: You can apply Feng Shui on tiny entryways too</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you're living in a small apartment or studio type room where there's not much space from the front door, no worries, you can still apply Feng Shui on your entryway. You can do any of the Feng Shui tips mentioned above, even just one or two.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>And the most important thing is to keep your entryway clean. Remove shoes, clothes, and other unnecessary objects near your front door. Keep it clean and free of clutter so the chi energy can enter freely.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Bonus tips!</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Tip #9: Give your front door some love</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Aside from your entryway, the front door itself plays a significant part in good home Feng Shui. It's a big part of the entire entrance, so it has a substantial impact on the flow of energy that enters your home. With that said, it's worth giving your front door a bit of attention and take a look at it from time to time. Here's what you should do:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Check the doorknob and the locks. Make sure they are working fine.</li>
<li>Check for chips and cracks. Try and fix them if possible.</li>
<li>Choose a solid and sturdy wooden door. Try to avoid having windows on your door. Having a solid wooden door will give you a better sense of security too.</li>
<li>The front door or main door should be the biggest door in your home (some even use double doors). However, make sure that it's the right size and is proportional to your home.  </li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Tip #10: Keep everything clean!</h2>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This tip is mostly a given. Just like any other area in your house, always keep your entryway clean and clutter-free! Although some people like putting things near the front door for easy access, make sure you'll organize these things properly and not just leave them scattered around the area. Here are some things you can do.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li> Don't leave shoes near or right at your front door. It's considered inauspicious in Feng Shui and viewed as clutter. If you want to have your shoes near your entryway, make sure they are kept inside a shoe cabinet, shoe rack, or any other closed cabinet. This trick will keep your entrance tidy and free of unsightly messy footwear.</li>
<li>Don't put too much stuff on your entryway. You don't have to put furniture or cabinets if it's not necessary. Keep your foyer or entryway clean and spacious as much as possible. Remove obstructions and clear the pathway so the auspicious chi energy can come in freely and spread further and deeper into your home.</li>
<li>For those who have bigger entryways, put a console table in it. You can place your purse, keys, and other items you'd want for an easy grab on your way out. Again, it's essential to keep things well-organized.  </li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Time to Feng Shui your entryway!</h1>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Paying attention to details is what will make your Feng Shui entryway even better. By following these tips, you'll have pretty much everything covered. Just make sure not to overdo all of these and prioritize what will make your home feel comfortable.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Enhancing the Feng Shui in your entryway will attract and encourage the positive chi energy to enter your home. Combine this with other Feng Shui principles, and the auspicious energy will eventually spread throughout the different rooms and enhance all sectors in your humble abode.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>12 Fun and Easy Christmas Crafts for Toddlers</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/12-fun-and-easy-christmas-crafts-for-toddlers.html"/>
        <id>https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/12-fun-and-easy-christmas-crafts-for-toddlers.html</id>

        <updated>2022-08-28T18:53:26-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Happy holidays guys! Christmas is right around the corner once again, and you're probably about to go through&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image {"id":123,"sizeSlug":"large"} --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><figure class="wp-image-123"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/drz-__-H8f6I7-qvao-unsplash-1024x715.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" srcset="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/responsive/drz-__-H8f6I7-qvao-unsplash-1024x715-xs.jpg 300w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/responsive/drz-__-H8f6I7-qvao-unsplash-1024x715-sm.jpg 480w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/responsive/drz-__-H8f6I7-qvao-unsplash-1024x715-md.jpg 768w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/responsive/drz-__-H8f6I7-qvao-unsplash-1024x715-xl.jpg 1200w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/responsive/drz-__-H8f6I7-qvao-unsplash-1024x715-xxl.jpg 1600w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/responsive/drz-__-H8f6I7-qvao-unsplash-1024x715-xxxl.jpg 2560w"  alt="Christmas crafts for toddlers" /></figure></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Happy holidays guys! Christmas is right around the corner once again, and you're probably about to go through your Christmas shopping list for this year (or maybe already have). But before you make your purchase, why not throw in a couple of fun items to make fun Christmas crafts for toddlers! This is going to be a great bonding activity that your kids will enjoy.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>No worries for those who already did their shopping; we'll provide a link to the items so you can just order them online.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What are some good Christmas crafts for toddlers?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When you search through the web, you can find lots of fabulous Christmas crafts to make. You can find almost anything for all ages. But of course, making Christmas crafts will become more memorable when you make it with your family, especially your kids. They can explore and show their creativity that only kids can do.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>So if you're looking for some fun Christmas crafts you can do with our toddler, you've come to the right place. Read on, and we'll show you a bunch of good ones. To get things started, here is our list of compiled Christmas crafts for toddlers ages 2-3.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What crafts can a 2-year-old do?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Most toddlers at the age of 2 now know how to sort by shapes and colors, so making crafts using different shapes and colors will be a good idea. Playing with different textures will be an excellent tactile learning experience too. Here are some easy-to-do crafts you can do with your 2-year-old.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1.&nbsp; Sticky Wall Christmas Tree Mural</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/sauWx45qYB_A9sWlHuVVBeVSjeQ0M3fv9oiMpXnhR-ZVVt_K2Y_PdU5ZURA7dhWNwLseghJu3u2MPi51YoqHZIa7S6fQFTrfAF9_Ecv_JdA6vxiOHKSJBwhdAfZbkW6_D0o1vmXw" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This sticky wall Christmas tree mural by <a href="https://www.notimeforflashcards.com/2012/11/sticky-wall-christmas-tree-mural.html">No time for Flashcards</a> will let your toddler decorate a Christmas tree their own way. It's fun and easy to make, and your kids will surely enjoy it. The best part is, you can keep it up for days or even weeks to keep them busy for a few minutes.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Best for ages</strong>: 2 and up</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Low</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Estimated time:</strong> 10 mins.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>What you'll need:</strong>&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Item name</strong></td>
<td><strong>The amount you’ll need</strong></td>
<td><strong>Estimated price</strong></td>
<td><strong>Where to get it?</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Green wrapping paper</td>
<td>1 roll</td>
<td>$17 for 2 rolls</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/JAM-PAPER-Gift-Wrap-Wrapping/dp/B07PX3TGGD/ref=sr_1_8?dchild=1&amp;keywords=green+wrapping+paper&amp;qid=1607354426&amp;sr=8-8">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Contact paper</td>
<td>1 roll</td>
<td>$6 (1x36 ft)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Duck-1115496-Laminate-Adhesive-12-Inch/dp/B002AS9NC6/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;keywords=clear+contact+paper&amp;qid=1607354718&amp;sr=8-7">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tissue paper (different colors)</td>
<td>1 pack of assorted colors</td>
<td>$7 (100pcs of 12x18 inch)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Pacon-Spectra-Assorted-Tissue-59530/dp/B00006IE0H/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=tissue+paper+assorted&amp;qid=1607354967&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Painter’s tape</td>
<td>1 roll (you won’t consume the whole roll)</td>
<td>$4&nbsp;</td>
<td>Daddy’s toolbox or get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Pacon-Spectra-Assorted-Tissue-59530/dp/B00006IE0H/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=tissue+paper+assorted&amp;qid=1607354967&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Buttons (optional)</td>
<td>5-12 pcs (or depending on how many you want)</td>
<td>$10 (1 pack of 500-700 pcs)</td>
<td>You can recycle from old used clothes or get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Assorted-Childrens-Painting-Handmade-Ornament/dp/B076FLR6X1/ref=sr_1_5?dchild=1&amp;keywords=buttons&amp;qid=1607356627&amp;sr=8-5">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Pompoms (optional)</td>
<td>5-10 pcs (or depending on how many you want)</td>
<td>$9 (pack of 100 pcs)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Assorted-Creative-Crafts-Decorations-Colors/dp/B07PQ312XB/ref=sr_1_8?dchild=1&amp;keywords=pom+poms&amp;qid=1607358279&amp;sr=8-8">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Scissors</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $6</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Westcott-Straight-Titanium-Bonded-Scissors/dp/B072RV8SC7/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=craft+scissors&amp;qid=1607358652&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Pencil</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $2 (pack of 12pcs)</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dixon-Pencils-Wood-Cased-12-Count-14402/dp/B004X4KRW0/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;keywords=pencil&amp;qid=1607358624&amp;sr=8-7">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>How to make it?:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Cut out a big Christmas tree from your green wrapping paper with your scissors.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Grab the pencil, trace the Christmas tree cutout onto your contact paper and cut it.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 3:</strong> Tape the wrapping paper Christmas tree cutout onto your wall using the painter's tape.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> Place the contact paper Christmas tree cut out on top of the wrapping paper Christmas tree.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 5:</strong> Tape the contact paper using the painter's tape. Make sure that you tape the plastic part down and the paper part on the surface.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 6:</strong> Peel off the paper part of the contact paper to reveal the sticky part underneath. Now you have a sticky surface on your green Christmas tree.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 7:</strong> You can now let your toddler stick some tissue paper, pompoms, and buttons onto the Christmas tree mural. You can let them crumple the paper to turn them into balls or tear them into smaller pieces.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 8:</strong> You can help them stick different items onto the tree and teach them about colors and shapes while you're at it.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>2. Christmas tree pompom painting</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/d8HZly4Yy1oajcIABAF9PS9aFe52kP6_objRmfWwS4ZXgXywpFk3XaDdeX80AkqbrsDil18jGDzewqul8kXLHPdqkjvnhdKS1seIg7QYfhH6gloVEwM7Q6mz0dA1Wx_8FdFy7PeI" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Get your little one's hand busy by letting them paint their own tiny Christmas tree with this Christmas tree pompom painting by <a href="https://www.fantasticfunandlearning.com/pom-pom-painting-christmas-tree-craft-for-toddlers.html">Fantastic Fun and Learning</a>. It's a great way to let them explore colors and creativity. Plus, you can hang their artworks as ornaments.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Best for ages</strong>: 2 and up</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Low</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Estimated time:</strong> 5-10 mins.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>What you'll need:</strong>&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Item name</strong></td>
<td><strong>The amount you’ll need</strong></td>
<td><strong>Estimated price</strong></td>
<td><strong>Where to get it?</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Green construction paper</td>
<td>1-2 sheets</td>
<td>$4 (pack of 100)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SunWorks-Construction-Paper-Holiday-Sheets/dp/B001C5TW42/ref=sr_1_5?dchild=1&amp;keywords=Green+cardboard+paper&amp;qid=1607417081&amp;sr=8-5">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Pompoms</td>
<td>3-5 pcs (or depending on how many you want)</td>
<td>$9 (pack of 100 pcs)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Assorted-Creative-Crafts-Decorations-Colors/dp/B07PQ312XB/ref=sr_1_8?dchild=1&amp;keywords=pom+poms&amp;qid=1607358279&amp;sr=8-8">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Clothespin</td>
<td>3-5 pcs (depending on how many pompoms used)</td>
<td>Free or $7 (pack of 50)</td>
<td>Laundry area or get in on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Honey-Can-Do-DRY-01374-Clothespins-24-Pack-3-3-inches/dp/B002CH8704/ref=sr_1_8?dchild=1&amp;keywords=Clothespin&amp;qid=1607417181&amp;sr=8-8">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Non-toxic, washable paint (assorted colors)</td>
<td>1 of each color</td>
<td>$23 (set of 12)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Toddlers-Non-Toxic-Washable-Painting-Supplies/dp/B08BLGRR44/ref=sr_1_35?crid=OUCA0KCUM65T&amp;dchild=1&amp;keywords=non-toxic+paint+for+kids&amp;qid=1607417397&amp;sprefix=non-toxic+paint+for+%2Caps%2C476&amp;sr=8-35">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Scissors</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $6</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Westcott-Straight-Titanium-Bonded-Scissors/dp/B072RV8SC7/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=craft+scissors&amp;qid=1607358652&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>How to make it?:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Cut Christmas tree shapes on your construction paper.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Pour some paint on plastic cups or any shallow containers for easy dipping.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 3:</strong> Clip-on a pompom ball using a clothespin. The clothespin will act as a handle so your kids can quickly dip the pompom into the paint.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> Now, let your toddler paint and decorate the Christmas tree cutouts anyway they want!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Snowman ball sort</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/P7Lq3KGxWlqiGazSS0t2TVq_q_J7DvWJi-Hg2Zwp8wGyb0b7S_TPk_kyCsBj8qr8Kab2S-Aza0Hx7Q2K61jfyDlvCUYmJcFXHy8eapR4MlZCxIOdY_yDsfMQ8keiyNV-zrH5KY2v" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can't let your toddler play in the snow for too long because of the cold. Luckily, you can still bring home a snowman friend with this Snowman ball sort for toddlers by <a href="https://www.icanteachmychild.com/snowman-ball-sort/">I Can Teach My Child</a>. No real snow involved, totally safe, and it's great not only for Christmas but all winter long.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Best for ages</strong>: 2 and up</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Medium</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Estimated time:</strong> 20 mins.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>What you'll need:</strong>&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Item name</strong></td>
<td><strong>The amount you’ll need</strong></td>
<td><strong>Estimated price</strong></td>
<td><strong>Where to get it?</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Large cardboard / cardboard moving box</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or&nbsp;</td>
<td>You can recycle any cardboard box you have at home.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>White art paper roll</td>
<td>1 roll</td>
<td>$9 per roll</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hape-Paper-Replacement-Easel-Paper/dp/B00II022O6/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;keywords=large+art+paper+white&amp;qid=1607376396&amp;sr=8-7">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Baskets</td>
<td>2 pcs.</td>
<td>$30 (set of 2)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/mDesign-Farmhouse-Storage-Organizer-Handles/dp/B077Z4C58L/ref=sr_1_28?dchild=1&amp;keywords=metal%2Bbaskets&amp;qid=1607412675&amp;sr=8-28&amp;th=1">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Ball pit balls</td>
<td>10 pcs or more</td>
<td>$12 (pack of 50)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Click-Play-Phthalate-Crush-Plastic/dp/B07D2ML12R/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=ball+pit+balls+50+pack&amp;qid=1607414341&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Spary adhesive or glue stick</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>$9 (spray adhesive)$4 (glue stick pack of 4)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elmers-Adhesive-Disappearing-Purple-E464TR/dp/B077JV67WX/ref=sr_1_3?dchild=1&amp;keywords=elmers+spray+adhesive&amp;qid=1607414475&amp;sr=8-3">Amazon</a>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elmers-Disappearing-Purple-School-Sticks/dp/B008O0DO2E/ref=sr_1_13?dchild=1&amp;keywords=glue+stick&amp;qid=1607414452&amp;sr=8-13">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Zip ties</td>
<td>4-6 pcs</td>
<td>$4 (pack of 100)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/50-Pounds-Tensile-Strength-Pieces-Tantti/dp/B08BKSHJ93/ref=sr_1_9?dchild=1&amp;keywords=zip+ties&amp;qid=1607414709&amp;sr=8-9">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Construction paper (assorted colors)</td>
<td>1 sheet per color</td>
<td>$3 (pack of 50)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B007OCF0C0/ref=olp_product_details?_encoding=UTF8&amp;me=&amp;qid=1607414929&amp;sr=8-10">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Scissors</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $6</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Westcott-Straight-Titanium-Bonded-Scissors/dp/B072RV8SC7/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=craft+scissors&amp;qid=1607358652&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Pencil</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $2 (pack of 12pcs)</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dixon-Pencils-Wood-Cased-12-Count-14402/dp/B004X4KRW0/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;keywords=pencil&amp;qid=1607358624&amp;sr=8-7">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>How to make it?:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Cut out a huge snowman shape from your cardboard.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Trace your shape onto the art paper roll and cut it.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 3:</strong> Stick the cardboard and the art paper together using the spray adhesive or the glue stick.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> Find a cup or any circle that will fit the balls and another one slightly bigger. Trace it on your construction paper and cut it, including the middle circle. It's like making a thin donut. It's best if you're construction paper is similarly colored to the balls you'll be using.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 5:</strong> Use the same cup that fits the ball to trace onto your colored art paper. Trace several circles onto your snowman, depending on how many you want.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 6: </strong>Cut the traced circles on the cardboard. You can use an Exacto knife, cutter, or scissors, whatever will be the easiest for you to use.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 7:</strong> Stick the cut donut papers onto the holes you made on your snowman cardboard.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 8:</strong> This step is optional. You can draw a scarf outline on your excess art paper or old magazine at home. Cut it and stick it onto your snowman for added color. And to give the snowman friend a scarf.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 9:</strong> Use the sticks to give your snowman some support and tape them onto the back.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 10:</strong> Use some zip ties to attach the sticks of the snowman to your basket.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 11:</strong> Put the balls in the basket, and you're done!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 12:</strong> You can now let your toddler play with the new snowman friend by putting the balls through the holes on its body. You can play with them and teach them how to put the balls through the holes' corresponding colors, like the red ball into the red hole.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>4. Felt Gingerbread House</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/enfYvDu2UY0VXt2BfZcfxXXvHF5EWTI7hJil4JDHdhoIR_lPa5IQkH9CTg0XaEDsSgbB8ALZHpprzBXdWVZm1NJPD8AuuZidwHgIP9F2oPE92xBKJCgDnqLlcBKAgzf2WBkjY58h" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Making a real gingerbread house can be really challenging, especially with a toddler (because they might end up eating the house). Good thing you can still make one with this felt gingerbread house by <a href="https://toddlerapproved.com/2012/12/christmas-crafts-easy-felt-gingerbread.html">Toddler Approved</a>. It's safe for toddlers, and it's entertaining to make.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Reminder:</strong> This may include small decorating pieces, so make sure to supervise them while doing this. If you want, you can replace your embellishments with bigger pieces to avoid choking if they put it in their mouth. Because you know, kids taste everything *sigh*.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Best for ages</strong>: 2 and up</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Medium</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Estimated time:</strong> 10-15 mins.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>What you'll need:</strong>&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Item name</strong></td>
<td><strong>The amount you’ll need</strong></td>
<td><strong>Estimated price</strong></td>
<td><strong>Where to get it?</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Thin cardboard</td>
<td>2-3 pcs (or depending on how many houses you want to make)</td>
<td>Free</td>
<td>You can recycle any box you have at home (cereal box, cookie box, etc).</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Craft felt (brown and any random color)</td>
<td>2-3 pcs (or depending on how many houses you want to make)</td>
<td>$8 (pack of 25)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Image-Group-Classic-SFTFLT-49205/dp/B002VR40HE/ref=sr_1_4?dchild=1&amp;keywords=felt+sheets+brown&amp;qid=1607420705&amp;sr=8-4">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tacky glue</td>
<td>1 bottle</td>
<td>$1 (4 oz)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elmers-Liquid-School-Washable-Ounces/dp/B000Q3KHCM/ref=sr_1_17?dchild=1&amp;keywords=elmers+school+glue&amp;qid=1607420980&amp;sr=8-17">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Assorted crafting embellishments (beads, pompoms, pipe cleaners, etc.)</td>
<td>Depends on how many you want</td>
<td>$14 (1 set)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Carl-Kay-Supplies-Creative-Materials/dp/B07ZG6JY5J/ref=sr_1_50?dchild=1&amp;keywords=art+craft+supply&amp;qid=1607421187&amp;sr=8-50">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Scissors</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $6</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Westcott-Straight-Titanium-Bonded-Scissors/dp/B072RV8SC7/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=craft+scissors&amp;qid=1607358652&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Pencil</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $2 (pack of 12pcs)</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dixon-Pencils-Wood-Cased-12-Count-14402/dp/B004X4KRW0/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;keywords=pencil&amp;qid=1607358624&amp;sr=8-7">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>How to make it?:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Draw and cut out a house shape on your cardboard.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Trace the cutout on your felt and cut it too.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 3:</strong> Repeat steps 1, and if you want more houses to work on.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> Stick the felt cutout onto the cardboard cut out using a glue stick. Use a different color for the roof.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 5:</strong> Put a flat, heavy object on top of the cutouts while they're drying. This will prevent them from bending/curling.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 6:</strong> Once the house cutouts are dry, you can now start decorating it with your kids. Start putting on some tacky glue and stick your embellishments wherever you want them.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 7:</strong> Wait for it to dry, and you can now display your finished felt gingerbread houses!&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How can I make my toddler fun for Christmas?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can make Christmas even more fun for your toddlers in many ways. Aside from giving them gifts, you can also make it even more special by doing activities together like playing or making Christmas crafts with them. Not only will it give you a memorable bonding experience for the holidays, but it can also be an excellent learning experience for them.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To spice things up, here are some more crafts you can do with your kids!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>5. Mitten Ornament</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/vfp0izFH2h2YA3j2CNm9KZ4ezbm0y0UcMBwNBGhg2KWFfZUAsSsi9n33FcZFoVjjTxkIhHtwklmeNzrWDA1kEHGkN0G2tW6ypz1IeF5JfOSEQ34n3dO9-EXom1VAQSbLEWJCQDnV" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Decorate your Christmas tree with this fun DIY mitten ornaments by <a href="https://www.adventure-in-a-box.com/mitten-christmas-ornament/">Adventure in a Box</a> you can make with your toddler. It's fun and easy to make, with you and your kid will definitely enjoy.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Best for ages</strong>: 2 and up</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Low</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Estimated time:</strong> 10-12 mins</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>What you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Item name</strong></td>
<td><strong>The amount you’ll need</strong></td>
<td><strong>Estimated price</strong></td>
<td><strong>Where to get it?</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Cardstock paper</td>
<td>1-2 sheets of any color (or more)1 sheet white</td>
<td>$8 (pack of 72)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Neenah-Creative-Collection-Specialty-Cardstock/dp/B003A2I4V2/ref=sxin_11?ascsubtag=amzn1.osa.3bcc6e58-9317-418d-a457-adc9b0077b17.ATVPDKIKX0DER.en_US&amp;creativeASIN=B003A2I4V2&amp;cv_ct_cx=Cardstock+paper&amp;cv_ct_id=amzn1.osa.3bcc6e58-9317-418d-a457-adc9b0077b17.ATVPDKIKX0DER.en_US&amp;cv_ct_pg=search&amp;cv_ct_we=asin&amp;cv_ct_wn=osp-single-source-gl-ranking&amp;dchild=1&amp;keywords=Cardstock+paper&amp;linkCode=oas&amp;pd_rd_i=B003A2I4V2&amp;pd_rd_r=3c841dc3-94de-44f3-93e2-46411b25e710&amp;pd_rd_w=IbW9C&amp;pd_rd_wg=2bUpN&amp;pf_rd_p=5ca5891e-f8d5-441d-985e-3d725696ef70&amp;pf_rd_r=PEFD6D2TF7RSBVR2ZD83&amp;qid=1607447744&amp;sr=1-2-d9dc7690-f7e1-44eb-ad06-aebbef559a37&amp;tag=mlbonsitepub-20">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Clear packaging tape</td>
<td>1 roll</td>
<td>$5 per roll</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Scotch-Start-Shipping-Dispenser-Clear/dp/B01CCMKJ36/ref=sr_1_4?dchild=1&amp;keywords=Clear+packaging+tape&amp;qid=1607447513&amp;refinements=p_36%3A1253550011&amp;rnid=386479011&amp;s=office-products&amp;sr=1-4">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Buttons / sequins</td>
<td>1 pack (or depending on how much you want)</td>
<td>$10 (assorted pack)$7 (assorted pack)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dshengoo-600-700-Buttons-Assorted-Decorations/dp/B078W5GQDQ/ref=sr_1_20?dchild=1&amp;keywords=buttons&amp;qid=1607447778&amp;refinements=p_36%3A-1000&amp;rnid=2638325011&amp;s=arts-crafts&amp;sr=1-20">Amazon</a>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dshengoo-600-700-Buttons-Assorted-Decorations/dp/B078W5GQDQ/ref=sr_1_20?dchild=1&amp;keywords=buttons&amp;qid=1607447778&amp;refinements=p_36%3A-1000&amp;rnid=2638325011&amp;s=arts-crafts&amp;sr=1-20">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Glitter</td>
<td>1 pack (or depending on how much you want)</td>
<td>$6 (assorted color pack)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Horizon-Group-USA-Assorted-Metallic/dp/B07CZDPPVJ/ref=sr_1_8?dchild=1&amp;keywords=Glitter&amp;qid=1607447583&amp;refinements=p_36%3A-1000&amp;rnid=2638325011&amp;sr=8-8">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Ribbon</td>
<td>6 inches per ornament</td>
<td>$4 1 roll</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Burgundy-Ribbons-Perfect-Wrapping-Decoration/dp/B08M5KSXNS/ref=sr_1_4?dchild=1&amp;keywords=Ribbon&amp;qid=1607447758&amp;refinements=p_36%3A-500&amp;rnid=2638325011&amp;sr=8-4">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Scissors</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $6</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Westcott-Straight-Titanium-Bonded-Scissors/dp/B072RV8SC7/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=craft+scissors&amp;qid=1607358652&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Pencil</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $2 (pack of 12pcs)</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dixon-Pencils-Wood-Cased-12-Count-14402/dp/B004X4KRW0/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;keywords=pencil&amp;qid=1607358624&amp;sr=8-7">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>How to make it?:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Draw and cut a mitten shape on your cardstock paper. Don't forget to add a space for your cuff.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Cut the inside of the mitten, leaving about 1/4" thick of an outline.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 3:</strong> Using a clear packaging tape, tape the backside of your mitten, leaving the sticky side facing the front. The inside part of the mitten should have the sticky part.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> Have your toddler stick sequins and buttons to the sticky surface of your mittens and fill the surface up as much as you can.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 5:</strong> This step is optional. Fill in any gaps with glitter to achieve a solid color.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 6:</strong> Attach a cuff on your mitten using a different color cardstock paper. Just cut a rectangle shape and stick it to your mitten.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 7:</strong> Use a puncher or cut a hole onto your cuff and tie a ribbon through it.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 8:</strong> You can now hang your mitten ornament on your Christmas tree.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>6. Footprint Christmas Tree</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/Zli8cigorr-PDPbMRePGUNusz0b1sP3GUPvMWZDbWcc3IBiL9ojCgRRhJwH9DdAyi451oXIwxpcewN-bhY1tYxh9_E7zBISIeGRAiTs5DA6flfKyrPie5Prfs3Ew8HaW8YqKJbfq" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Have you ever seen a foot-shaped Christmas tree? If not, why not make one with your little one? This Footprint Christmas Tree by <a href="https://www.messylittlemonster.com/2014/12/footprint-christmas-tree-christmas-cards.html">Messy Little Monster</a> is a cute project you can make with your toddler. Just be ready to get a bit messy as they may run off with paint-covered feet.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Best for ages</strong>: 2 and up</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Low</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Estimated time:</strong> 5-10 mins</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>What you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Item name</strong></td>
<td><strong>The amount you’ll need</strong></td>
<td><strong>Estimated price</strong></td>
<td><strong>Where to get it?</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Construction paper</td>
<td>1-2 sheets of white (or more)1 sheet yellow1 sheet brown</td>
<td>$5 (pack of 50)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Tru-Ray-Construction-P103031-Standard-Assorted/dp/B00008XPH8/ref=psdc_12898141_t1_B007OCF0C0">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Non-toxic, washable paint (assorted colors)</td>
<td>1 green1 of other chosen colors (optional)</td>
<td>$23 (set of 12)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Toddlers-Non-Toxic-Washable-Painting-Supplies/dp/B08BLGRR44/ref=sr_1_35?crid=OUCA0KCUM65T&amp;dchild=1&amp;keywords=non-toxic+paint+for+kids&amp;qid=1607417397&amp;sprefix=non-toxic+paint+for+%2Caps%2C476&amp;sr=8-35">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Cardstock paper</td>
<td>1-2 sheets of any color (or more)</td>
<td>$8 (pack of 72)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Neenah-Creative-Collection-Specialty-Cardstock/dp/B003A2I4V2/ref=sxin_11?ascsubtag=amzn1.osa.3bcc6e58-9317-418d-a457-adc9b0077b17.ATVPDKIKX0DER.en_US&amp;creativeASIN=B003A2I4V2&amp;cv_ct_cx=Cardstock+paper&amp;cv_ct_id=amzn1.osa.3bcc6e58-9317-418d-a457-adc9b0077b17.ATVPDKIKX0DER.en_US&amp;cv_ct_pg=search&amp;cv_ct_we=asin&amp;cv_ct_wn=osp-single-source-gl-ranking&amp;dchild=1&amp;keywords=Cardstock+paper&amp;linkCode=oas&amp;pd_rd_i=B003A2I4V2&amp;pd_rd_r=3c841dc3-94de-44f3-93e2-46411b25e710&amp;pd_rd_w=IbW9C&amp;pd_rd_wg=2bUpN&amp;pf_rd_p=5ca5891e-f8d5-441d-985e-3d725696ef70&amp;pf_rd_r=PEFD6D2TF7RSBVR2ZD83&amp;qid=1607447744&amp;sr=1-2-d9dc7690-f7e1-44eb-ad06-aebbef559a37&amp;tag=mlbonsitepub-20">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Sequins</td>
<td>1 pack (depending on how much you’ll need)</td>
<td>$7 (assorted pack)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dshengoo-600-700-Buttons-Assorted-Decorations/dp/B078W5GQDQ/ref=sr_1_20?dchild=1&amp;keywords=buttons&amp;qid=1607447778&amp;refinements=p_36%3A-1000&amp;rnid=2638325011&amp;s=arts-crafts&amp;sr=1-20">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Star sequins (optional)</td>
<td>Depending on how many Christmas trees you’ll make</td>
<td>$5 (pack of 50)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Darice-1003522-Star-Sequins-50-Pack/dp/B0054G61QW/ref=sr_1_5?dchild=1&amp;keywords=star+sequins&amp;qid=1607451717&amp;sr=8-5">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tacky glue</td>
<td>1 bottle</td>
<td>$1 (4 oz)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elmers-Liquid-School-Washable-Ounces/dp/B000Q3KHCM/ref=sr_1_17?dchild=1&amp;keywords=elmers+school+glue&amp;qid=1607420980&amp;sr=8-17">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Scissors</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $6</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Westcott-Straight-Titanium-Bonded-Scissors/dp/B072RV8SC7/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=craft+scissors&amp;qid=1607358652&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>How to make it?:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Pour some paint on a paper plate and have your toddler step on it to cover his/her feet with paint.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Have them step on a plain construction paper to get some solid footprints.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 3:</strong> Repeat steps 1 and 2 until you have as many footprints as you need. Don't forget to wipe or wash off the paint on your toddlers' feet right after if you don't want footprints around your house.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> Once the footprint is dry, cut them out and decorate them with sequins or paint designs. You can do this with your kid and design as many as you can.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 5:</strong> Cut out brown rectangles using another construction paper. This will serve as your Christmas tree's trunk.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 6:</strong> Cut out some stars on yellow construction paper and stick them on top of your footprint Christmas tree. Alternatively, you can just use star-shaped sequins and attach them the same way.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 7:</strong> Stick your footprint Christmas tree on cardstock paper and use them as decor for your Christmas cards.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 8:</strong> You can also stick some strings and hang them as decorations.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>7. Cotton Ball Santa</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/pQsUnhk9vQJedozFLimcNthi4JuRfIvoU_BdmyYfQsSRVRLcIqdGo7xoOjGXdsPJJYOsJXyWK1YvZ6Z3blSnCnE_5kRJCx3ANZIgHJb1rEEbQfHDU0ehLEgZk0jzj_IxvSwoUtXy" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This fun and fluffy cotton ball Santa by <a href="https://www.journeytosahm.com/santa-claus-craft-toddlers-cotton-balls/">Journey to SAHM</a> is an excellent project to work on if your kid loves Santa. It's so easy to make that even our 2-year-old can help out and make them.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Best for ages</strong>: 2 and up</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Difficulty:</strong> High</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Estimated time:</strong> 20 mins. + overnight for drying</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>What you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Item name</strong></td>
<td><strong>The amount you’ll need</strong></td>
<td><strong>Estimated price</strong></td>
<td><strong>Where to get it?</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Construction paper</td>
<td>1 sheet red1 sheet white1 sheet tan/cream/brown1 sheet of any color</td>
<td>$5 (pack of 50)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Tru-Ray-Construction-P103031-Standard-Assorted/dp/B00008XPH8/ref=psdc_12898141_t1_B007OCF0C0">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Googly eyes</td>
<td>2 pcs.</td>
<td>$4 (pack of 500)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DECORA-Pieces-Wiggle-Googly-Self-Adhesive/dp/B01LWIYJH3/ref=sxin_9_ac_d_rm?ac_md=0-0-Z29vZ2x5IGV5ZXM%3D-ac_d_rm&amp;crid=26YQE6XRF1PKW&amp;cv_ct_cx=googly+eyes&amp;dchild=1&amp;keywords=googly+eyes&amp;pd_rd_i=B01LWIYJH3&amp;pd_rd_r=31ecd9a4-a7e5-411c-bb1a-6a3449af6057&amp;pd_rd_w=DQoo8&amp;pd_rd_wg=ks2r8&amp;pf_rd_p=b6dc128d-7461-4205-b97b-a956bf7315b7&amp;pf_rd_r=K3X3W5528Z8049EY5QYJ&amp;psc=1&amp;qid=1607456728&amp;sprefix=googly+eyes%2Caps%2C448&amp;sr=1-1-12d4272d-8adb-4121-8624-135149aa9081">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Cotton balls</td>
<td>1 pack</td>
<td>$4 (pack of 100)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DecorRack-Make-Up-Applying-Multi-Purpose-Absorbent/dp/B081P93444/ref=sr_1_10?dchild=1&amp;keywords=cotton+balls&amp;qid=1607456766&amp;sr=8-10">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tacky glue</td>
<td>1 bottle</td>
<td>$1 (4 oz)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elmers-Liquid-School-Washable-Ounces/dp/B000Q3KHCM/ref=sr_1_17?dchild=1&amp;keywords=elmers+school+glue&amp;qid=1607420980&amp;sr=8-17">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Contact paper (optional)</td>
<td>1 roll</td>
<td>$6 (1x36 ft)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Duck-1115496-Laminate-Adhesive-12-Inch/dp/B002AS9NC6/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;keywords=clear+contact+paper&amp;qid=1607354718&amp;sr=8-7">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Scissors</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $6</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Westcott-Straight-Titanium-Bonded-Scissors/dp/B072RV8SC7/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=craft+scissors&amp;qid=1607358652&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>How to make it?:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Cut out the shapes you'll need to make your Santa using construction paper. A large tan/cream/brown circle for the face, a red hat brim and a small white circle for the pom, and a large half-circle for the body.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Assemble the cutout shapes and stick them on a plain construction paper (any color of your choice).</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 3:</strong> Put some glue around the head for Santa's beard and some hair. You can also substitute it with contact paper by sticking it on the surface with the sticky side up.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> Let your toddler stick the cotton balls onto Santa's head and beard. Allow them to mess up and put the cotton balls anywhere they want to. This will make it more enjoyable for them.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 5:</strong> Put some googly eyes for Santa's eyes and cut a small red circle, and stick it just below the eyes for Santa's nose.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 6:</strong> You can now display your fluffy cotton ball Santa!&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>8. Handprint Santa Salt Dough Ornament</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/3EfrBbvDNwwTqrcgyFGfpcw7dOGhcyVtCnHOgir2cZMrAY_M_LXTZQt5Dui8aYHtQlAThgisyDPQmyFfYwc_gQJm4MnDPXb0K_SNSuOO3aLqoKPAum8dBwZuK40A9w_g8iqAvrf7" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For your toddlers who are a fan of Santa Claus, here is an excellent project to try! This will mostly need your help in the making, but you can keep the final product as a keepsake of your little one.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Best for ages</strong>: 2 and up</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Difficulty:</strong> High</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Estimated time:</strong> 20 mins. + overnight for drying</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>What you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Item name</strong></td>
<td><strong>The amount you’ll need</strong></td>
<td><strong>Estimated price</strong></td>
<td><strong>Where to get it?</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>All-purpose flour</td>
<td>1 cup</td>
<td>$4 (2 lb pack)</td>
<td>In your kitchen or get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Gold-Medal-Flour-2-lb/dp/B000SSXTP2/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;keywords=flour&amp;qid=1607440864&amp;refinements=p_36%3A698503011&amp;rnid=386454011&amp;s=grocery&amp;sr=1-1">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Salt</td>
<td>½ cup</td>
<td>$3 (4 lb pack)</td>
<td>In your kitchen or get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Morton-Iodized-Table-Salt-4lb/dp/B001GHYO4E/ref=sr_1_28?dchild=1&amp;keywords=iodized+Salt&amp;qid=1607441347&amp;refinements=p_36%3A698503011&amp;rnid=386454011&amp;s=grocery&amp;sr=1-28">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Warm water&nbsp;</td>
<td>¼ cup (have some extra on standby)</td>
<td>Free</td>
<td>In your kitchen</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Non-toxic, washable paint + paintbrush</td>
<td>1 red1 white1 black1 brown or skintone</td>
<td>$23 (set of 12)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Toddlers-Non-Toxic-Washable-Painting-Supplies/dp/B08BLGRR44/ref=sr_1_35?crid=OUCA0KCUM65T&amp;dchild=1&amp;keywords=non-toxic+paint+for+kids&amp;qid=1607417397&amp;sprefix=non-toxic+paint+for+%2Caps%2C476&amp;sr=8-35">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Yarn or ribbon (optional)</td>
<td>6 inches per piece (or depending on how long you want)</td>
<td>$4 per roll</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/HEART-Super-Saver-Minty-E300-0520/dp/B01FV607WI/ref=sr_1_11?dchild=1&amp;keywords=yarn&amp;qid=1607440800&amp;sr=8-11">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Wax Paper</td>
<td>15 inches (or depending on how long you want)</td>
<td>$9 per roll</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Parchment-Available-Greaseproof-grilling-Non-stick/dp/B08GLBHMND/ref=sr_1_11?dchild=1&amp;keywords=Wax+Paper&amp;qid=1607440819&amp;refinements=p_36%3A1253523011&amp;rnid=386465011&amp;s=home-garden&amp;sr=1-11">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Butterknife</td>
<td>1 pc</td>
<td>$9 (set of 2)</td>
<td>In your kitchen or get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Multifunction-Stainless-Spreader-Western-Spreaders/dp/B08DFW4KB8/ref=sr_1_9?dchild=1&amp;keywords=butter+knife&amp;qid=1607440841&amp;refinements=p_36%3A1253523011&amp;rnid=386465011&amp;s=home-garden&amp;sr=1-9">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>How to make it?:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Combine your flour, salt, and water into a bowl.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Lightly dust a surface with some flour and knead your dough to remove air bubbles. Do this until your dough is smooth. Make sure it's not sticky too.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 3:</strong> Flatten your dough to about 1/2 inch thick using a rolling pin and cut a piece.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> Time to call your little one and lightly dust his/her palm with some flour to prevent it from sticking onto the dough.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 5:</strong> Press their tiny hand lightly onto the dough to make a handprint.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 6:</strong> Cut the handprint along the edges using a butter knife. You can also poke a hole on one side to attach a string (if you want to use it as an ornament).&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 7:</strong> Put the handprint dough into the microwave and heat for about 15 seconds.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 8:</strong> Take it out of the microwave and check if it's still soft to the touch.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 9:</strong> Put it back into the microwave and heat it for another 20 seconds. You can repeat this step until you feel like the dough is starting to get dry and harden. It would most likely change color too.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 10:</strong> Once your dough is dry, you can start painting it. Try painting the entire handprint with white first and let it dry. You can let your toddler paint some pieces too.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 11:</strong> Leave it overnight to dry and harden further.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 12:</strong> Tie a yarn or ribbon onto the tiny hole on the side, and you're done! You can use this as a Christmas tree ornament too.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How do you make easy Christmas decorations for kids?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Decorating is always a part of Christmas. Besides putting up Christmas trees and other decorations, you can also make your own decorations with your kids. Here are some more crafting ideas for Christmas decorations that are also great for your toddlers.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>9. No-mess gingerbread suncatcher ornament</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/e_dQVhevVxN7hxlAT-gOwplhY4W5ryoHnw4jaroeEApU0gGTJXIcLdtDMQdLzffB8muUrZCHo4XACtC7M5W0A1-KYam-hTh6AvXebrJ054-hYIaZwYPdOEOeMdCkH0vvIzmrbgM1" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Gingerbread with no crumbs? Yes, we have that. You can also hang these gingerbread ornaments on your window or your Christmas tree! This no-mess gingerbread suncatcher ornament by <a href="https://teaching2and3yearolds.com/how-to-make-no-mess-gingerbread-ornament/">Teaching 2 and 3-year-olds</a> is an excellent addition to your holiday decorations.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Best for ages</strong>: 2 and up</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Low</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Estimated time:</strong> 10-15 mins</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>What you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Item name</strong></td>
<td><strong>The amount you’ll need</strong></td>
<td><strong>Estimated price</strong></td>
<td><strong>Where to get it?</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Paper plate</td>
<td>1 or more</td>
<td>$11 (pack of 100)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Empress-Uncoated-Paper-Plate-Inches/dp/B0044S1CDS/ref=sr_1_16?dchild=1&amp;keywords=paper+plate&amp;qid=1607459991&amp;refinements=p_36%3A1253518011&amp;rnid=386636011&amp;s=hpc&amp;sr=1-16">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Contact paper</td>
<td>1 roll</td>
<td>$6 (1x36 ft)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Duck-1115496-Laminate-Adhesive-12-Inch/dp/B002AS9NC6/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;keywords=clear+contact+paper&amp;qid=1607354718&amp;sr=8-7">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tissue paper squares (assorted colors)</td>
<td>1 pack assorted</td>
<td>$6 (pack of assorted colors)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Outuxed-4800pcs-Squares-Assorted-Scrapbooking/dp/B07SBSFN92/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;keywords=Tissue+paper+squares&amp;qid=1607460008&amp;sr=8-7">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Buttons</td>
<td>1 pack (or depending on how much you want)</td>
<td>$10 (assorted pack)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dshengoo-600-700-Buttons-Assorted-Decorations/dp/B078W5GQDQ/ref=sr_1_20?dchild=1&amp;keywords=buttons&amp;qid=1607447778&amp;refinements=p_36%3A-1000&amp;rnid=2638325011&amp;s=arts-crafts&amp;sr=1-20">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Googly eyes</td>
<td>2 pcs.</td>
<td>$4 (pack of 500)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DECORA-Pieces-Wiggle-Googly-Self-Adhesive/dp/B01LWIYJH3/ref=sxin_9_ac_d_rm?ac_md=0-0-Z29vZ2x5IGV5ZXM%3D-ac_d_rm&amp;crid=26YQE6XRF1PKW&amp;cv_ct_cx=googly+eyes&amp;dchild=1&amp;keywords=googly+eyes&amp;pd_rd_i=B01LWIYJH3&amp;pd_rd_r=31ecd9a4-a7e5-411c-bb1a-6a3449af6057&amp;pd_rd_w=DQoo8&amp;pd_rd_wg=ks2r8&amp;pf_rd_p=b6dc128d-7461-4205-b97b-a956bf7315b7&amp;pf_rd_r=K3X3W5528Z8049EY5QYJ&amp;psc=1&amp;qid=1607456728&amp;sprefix=googly+eyes%2Caps%2C448&amp;sr=1-1-12d4272d-8adb-4121-8624-135149aa9081">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Yarn (assorted colors)</td>
<td>Depends on how much you’ll make</td>
<td>$13 (pack of 20)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TYH-Supplies-Acrylic-Assorted-Colors/dp/B00XLP2UGI/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;keywords=Yarn&amp;qid=1607460030&amp;sr=8-7">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Double-sided tape</td>
<td>1 roll</td>
<td>$4 per roll.</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Scotch-Double-Dispenser-Standard-237/dp/B0000DH8IT/ref=sr_1_5?dchild=1&amp;keywords=Double-sided+tape&amp;qid=1607460042&amp;sr=8-5">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Scissors</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $6</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Westcott-Straight-Titanium-Bonded-Scissors/dp/B072RV8SC7/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=craft+scissors&amp;qid=1607358652&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>How to make it?:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Draw a gingerbread pattern on your paper plate or cardstock paper. Cut it out so you'll have a gingerbread-shaped hole in the middle.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Cut your contact paper. The piece should be big enough to cover the gingerbread-shaped hole. The sticky side should be on one side of the paper.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 3:</strong> Have your toddler stick on the small tissue paper squares onto the sticky side of the contact paper. Make sure to cover the whole gingerbread hole.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> When the gingerbread hole is covered with tissue paper, get another piece of contact paper, and cover it. The two sticky parts should be facing each other.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 5:</strong> Once you got your paper covered, cut around the edges of the gingerbread hole. Leave about 1/2 centimeter thick to serve as an outline for your suncatcher.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 6:</strong> Punch a hole on top of the gingerbread and thread yarn through it. Tie the yarn to create a loop. You can use this to hang your suncatcher.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 7:</strong> Put a double-sided tape on the gingerbread parts where you'll put the eyes and other details.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 8:</strong> Have your kid stick on the eyes and other details.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 9:</strong> You can now hang your finished gingerbread suncatcher!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>10. Paper Ornament</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/r32rGdtsZv2jV196CudZYhVoBKhGFe9eBFIWhLwvMFOqdEjAhNgBxX_wru36hbOykLzuqG7NQbL6xTL8FCUt7RtZsi7A0xKkT09oyewqVw6KSAlxtTIu3GQkfsLEEZCaRbVHManz" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Have your toddlers create and decorate their own ornaments with this paper ornament craft by <a href="https://www.glitteronadime.com/paper-ornament-craft/">Glitter on a Dime</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Best for ages</strong>: 2 and up</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Low</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Estimated time:</strong> 5-10 mins.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>What you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Item name</strong></td>
<td><strong>The amount you’ll need</strong></td>
<td><strong>Estimated price</strong></td>
<td><strong>Where to get it?</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Paper plate</td>
<td>1 or more</td>
<td>$11 (pack of 100)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Empress-Uncoated-Paper-Plate-Inches/dp/B0044S1CDS/ref=sr_1_16?dchild=1&amp;keywords=paper+plate&amp;qid=1607459991&amp;refinements=p_36%3A1253518011&amp;rnid=386636011&amp;s=hpc&amp;sr=1-16">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Buttons</td>
<td>1 pack (or depending on how much you want)</td>
<td>$10 (assorted pack)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dshengoo-600-700-Buttons-Assorted-Decorations/dp/B078W5GQDQ/ref=sr_1_20?dchild=1&amp;keywords=buttons&amp;qid=1607447778&amp;refinements=p_36%3A-1000&amp;rnid=2638325011&amp;s=arts-crafts&amp;sr=1-20">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Sequins</td>
<td>1 pack (or depending on how much you want)</td>
<td>$7 (assorted pack)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dshengoo-600-700-Buttons-Assorted-Decorations/dp/B078W5GQDQ/ref=sr_1_20?dchild=1&amp;keywords=buttons&amp;qid=1607447778&amp;refinements=p_36%3A-1000&amp;rnid=2638325011&amp;s=arts-crafts&amp;sr=1-20">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Foam stickers</td>
<td>1 pack (or depending on how much you want)</td>
<td>$12 (assorted pack)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/KATUMO-Christmas-Stickers-Decoration-Classroom/dp/B08GFR9R6T/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=christmas+foam+stickers&amp;qid=1607461150&amp;refinements=p_36%3A1253560011&amp;rnid=386491011&amp;s=toys-and-games&amp;sr=1-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tacky glue</td>
<td>1 bottle</td>
<td>$1 (4 oz)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elmers-Liquid-School-Washable-Ounces/dp/B000Q3KHCM/ref=sr_1_17?dchild=1&amp;keywords=elmers+school+glue&amp;qid=1607420980&amp;sr=8-17">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Crayons</td>
<td>1 box</td>
<td>$4 (1 box of 24)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Crayola-52-3024-7-Crayons-24-Count/dp/B000RTNMB8/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;keywords=crayons&amp;qid=1607461837&amp;sr=8-7">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Yarn (assorted colors)</td>
<td>Depends on how much you’ll make</td>
<td>$13 (pack of 20)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TYH-Supplies-Acrylic-Assorted-Colors/dp/B00XLP2UGI/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;keywords=Yarn&amp;qid=1607460030&amp;sr=8-7">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Scissors</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $6</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Westcott-Straight-Titanium-Bonded-Scissors/dp/B072RV8SC7/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=craft+scissors&amp;qid=1607358652&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>How to make it?:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Cut a big circle from your paper plate.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Have the kids decorate each circle. They can use different objects like markers, paper cut-outs, foam stickers, beads, etc. Let them be creative and design it however they want to.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 3: </strong>Punch a hole onto the circles, thread a ribbon through it and tie it up. This will serve as a loop for hanging.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>11. Christmas wreath</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/5DEpGEI0vr9Jsx13x50JIKa8I_R_o_pn31rLbXrKrVo7WkvYbU2MYfnUoaF_7oMRqF5wYLLc6A08_rb1OeUzaGflGcEH-z1gaPvDm2eHGq9Akgc5jdeNNpXT6OTa6ZqvurcytBNm" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Another easy-to-do decor you can make with your little one is this Christmas wreath by <a href="https://www.craftsonsea.co.uk/christmas-wreath-craft-for-toddlers">Crafts on Sea</a>. If you did craft number 10 or the paper ornaments, you could use the other part of the paper plate cut out for this project.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Best for ages</strong>: 2 and up</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Low</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Estimated time:</strong> 5-10 mins.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>What you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Item name</strong></td>
<td><strong>The amount you’ll need</strong></td>
<td><strong>Estimated price</strong></td>
<td><strong>Where to get it?</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Paper plate</td>
<td>1 or more</td>
<td>$11 (pack of 100)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Empress-Uncoated-Paper-Plate-Inches/dp/B0044S1CDS/ref=sr_1_16?dchild=1&amp;keywords=paper+plate&amp;qid=1607459991&amp;refinements=p_36%3A1253518011&amp;rnid=386636011&amp;s=hpc&amp;sr=1-16">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tacky glue</td>
<td>1 bottle</td>
<td>$1 (4 oz)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elmers-Liquid-School-Washable-Ounces/dp/B000Q3KHCM/ref=sr_1_17?dchild=1&amp;keywords=elmers+school+glue&amp;qid=1607420980&amp;sr=8-17">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tissue paper (different colors)</td>
<td>1 pack of assorted colors</td>
<td>$7 (100pcs of 12x18 inch)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Pacon-Spectra-Assorted-Tissue-59530/dp/B00006IE0H/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=tissue+paper+assorted&amp;qid=1607354967&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Yarn (assorted colors)</td>
<td>Depends on how much you’ll make</td>
<td>$13 (pack of 20)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TYH-Supplies-Acrylic-Assorted-Colors/dp/B00XLP2UGI/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;keywords=Yarn&amp;qid=1607460030&amp;sr=8-7">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Scissors</td>
<td>1 pc.</td>
<td>Free or $6</td>
<td>You may already have one at home or get one on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Westcott-Straight-Titanium-Bonded-Scissors/dp/B072RV8SC7/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;keywords=craft+scissors&amp;qid=1607358652&amp;sr=8-6">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>How to make it?:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 1: </strong>Grab a paper plate and cut out a circle in the middle part. You should have a paper plate ring.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Spread some glue all over the paper plate ring.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 3:</strong> Have your toddler stick on some torn and crumpled green tissue paper pieces and stick them onto the paper plate rings.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> Add some different colored tissue paper as well to create some design.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 5:</strong> Puch a hole on one side. Thread and tie some yarn to serve as a loop for hanging.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 6:</strong> Once it's done, you can now display your artwork!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>12. Popsicle Reindeers</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/21/-1IheEknRDsDLbivHMans0nPTZmzkWIAyFBxFZ7SMxMYGDkKQDhjhKuEVSPWC321EB9S2uA6VN3kBDw0qAWKBVlq6OxOKpOToCG5DIJtxgd4XWf53PpAqJmI_grV_HuS-KcHKm-c" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Christmas wouldn't be complete without Santa's reindeers. Make a bunch of them with your toddler using popsicle sticks! This popsicle reindeer by <a href="https://happyhooligans.ca/craft-stick-santa-elf-and-reindeer-ornaments/">Happy Hooligans</a> will surely add a unique ornament to your Christmas decorations.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Best for ages</strong>: 2 and up</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Low</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Estimated time:</strong> 5-10 mins.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>What you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Item name</strong></td>
<td><strong>The amount you’ll need</strong></td>
<td><strong>Estimated price</strong></td>
<td><strong>Where to get it?</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Big popsicle sticks</td>
<td>1 per reindeer</td>
<td>$5 (pack of 80)</td>
<td>Get it from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Darice-Piece-Natural-Finish-Sticks/dp/B001VDKHN0/ref=sr_1_10?dchild=1&amp;keywords=big+popsicle+sticks&amp;qid=1607464506&amp;sr=8-10">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Non-toxic, washable paint&nbsp;</td>
<td>1 brown color</td>
<td>$8 (16 oz)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Handy-Little-Masters-Washable-Paint/dp/B004QPMM1U/ref=sr_1_25?crid=1VC1W5HJ40OOX&amp;dchild=1&amp;keywords=non+toxic+paint+for+toddlers+brown&amp;qid=1607465331&amp;sprefix=non+toxic+paint+%2Caps%2C411&amp;sr=8-25">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tacky glue</td>
<td>1 bottle</td>
<td>$1 (4 oz)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elmers-Liquid-School-Washable-Ounces/dp/B000Q3KHCM/ref=sr_1_17?dchild=1&amp;keywords=elmers+school+glue&amp;qid=1607420980&amp;sr=8-17">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Googly eyes</td>
<td>2 pcs.</td>
<td>$4 (pack of 500)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DECORA-Pieces-Wiggle-Googly-Self-Adhesive/dp/B01LWIYJH3/ref=sxin_9_ac_d_rm?ac_md=0-0-Z29vZ2x5IGV5ZXM%3D-ac_d_rm&amp;crid=26YQE6XRF1PKW&amp;cv_ct_cx=googly+eyes&amp;dchild=1&amp;keywords=googly+eyes&amp;pd_rd_i=B01LWIYJH3&amp;pd_rd_r=31ecd9a4-a7e5-411c-bb1a-6a3449af6057&amp;pd_rd_w=DQoo8&amp;pd_rd_wg=ks2r8&amp;pf_rd_p=b6dc128d-7461-4205-b97b-a956bf7315b7&amp;pf_rd_r=K3X3W5528Z8049EY5QYJ&amp;psc=1&amp;qid=1607456728&amp;sprefix=googly+eyes%2Caps%2C448&amp;sr=1-1-12d4272d-8adb-4121-8624-135149aa9081">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Small pompoms</td>
<td>1 pc per reindeer</td>
<td>$10 (assorted pack)</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Caydo-Assorted-Elastic-Creative-Decorations/dp/B01MTQR32W/ref=sr_1_5?dchild=1&amp;keywords=small+pom+poms&amp;qid=1607464959&amp;sr=8-5">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Glue gun set</td>
<td>1 pc</td>
<td>$13 with glue sticks set</td>
<td>Get it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ccbetter-Upgraded-Removable-Anti-hot-Flexible/dp/B01178RVI2/ref=sr_1_5?dchild=1&amp;keywords=glue+gun+with+glue+stick&amp;qid=1607465154&amp;sr=8-5">Amazon</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>How to make it?:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Grab a popsicle and paint it brown.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Get some brown pipe cleaners and cut them in half.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 3:</strong> Get half of the pipe cleaner and fold it in half. Make sure to make some wavy ends for the antlers.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> Stick the pipe cleaner onto the painted popsicle stick using a hot glue gun. An adult should do this step as a hot glue gun can be dangerous to your kid.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 5:</strong> Stick on the googly eyes and the pompom nose onto your reindeer.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Step 6:</strong> You can also stick a piece of string onto the back for hanging. And you're reindeer is done!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Get crafting for the holidays!</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>I hope you enjoyed this list. Which of these fantastic projects will you try out with your toddler? For more crafting ideas with your kids, check out this list of <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/20-fun-and-easy-dr-seuss-crafts-for-kids/" class="rank-math-link">Dr. Seuss crafts</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to Make Lavender Essential Oils</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/how-to-make-lavender-essential-oils.html"/>
        <id>https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/how-to-make-lavender-essential-oils.html</id>

        <updated>2022-08-28T18:53:26-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Essential oils are known to provide therapeutic and calming benefits, especially when used for aromatherapy. And when we&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image {"id":117,"sizeSlug":"large"} --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><figure class="wp-image-117"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/romain-mathon-8KdWd21nmaU-unsplash-1024x769.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" srcset="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/responsive/romain-mathon-8KdWd21nmaU-unsplash-1024x769-xs.jpg 300w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/responsive/romain-mathon-8KdWd21nmaU-unsplash-1024x769-sm.jpg 480w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/responsive/romain-mathon-8KdWd21nmaU-unsplash-1024x769-md.jpg 768w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/responsive/romain-mathon-8KdWd21nmaU-unsplash-1024x769-xl.jpg 1200w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/responsive/romain-mathon-8KdWd21nmaU-unsplash-1024x769-xxl.jpg 1600w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/responsive/romain-mathon-8KdWd21nmaU-unsplash-1024x769-xxxl.jpg 2560w"  alt="" /></figure></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Essential oils are known to provide <a href="https://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;lr=&amp;id=dbqZDwAAQBAJ&amp;oi=fnd&amp;pg=PA155&amp;dq=lavender+essential+oil+benefits&amp;ots=mQgTKO8diK&amp;sig=EkxJND_DkxYY8Zf359lEsI1aR18">therapeutic</a> and calming benefits, especially when used for aromatherapy. And when we talk about 'calming,' one scent always stands out - Lavender. In this article, we'll talk about how to make Lavender essential oils in a few simple steps. So gather up those Lavender flowers, and let's jump in.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How to make lavender essential oils at home?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Fragrance oils can get a bit pricey. But one of the most popular, Lavender oil, is easy enough to make on your own. You'd only need a few items, and making them at home could be much cheaper, plus you can make lots of it in one batch.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>However, keep in mind that it could not be as potent as the ones you buy from stores. But hey, it's all-natural, and it could still work as well as the commercial variants.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Stuff you'll need:</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To make Lavender essential oils, you must prepare the following:</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>An airtight glass container</li>
<li>Dried Lavender flowers</li>
<li>Your choice of carrier oil (more info on this below)</li>
<li>Cheesecloth or a fine-mesh strainer</li>
<li>Funnel</li>
<li>A jar or bottle to store your Lavender oil</li>
<li>Mortar and pestle</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Procedure:</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Step 1</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you have a bunch of dried Lavenders attached to its stalk, pick out the flowers, and lightly crush them using the mortar and pestle. This will help release the scent of the flowers. We'll only be using the flowers since it's the primary source of the scent. You can also include some of the leaves, but it should mostly be the flowers.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"id":118,"sizeSlug":"large"} --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><figure class="wp-image-118"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/lav-1024x682.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" srcset="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/responsive/lav-1024x682-xs.jpg 300w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/responsive/lav-1024x682-sm.jpg 480w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/responsive/lav-1024x682-md.jpg 768w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/responsive/lav-1024x682-xl.jpg 1200w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/responsive/lav-1024x682-xxl.jpg 1600w ,https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/responsive/lav-1024x682-xxxl.jpg 2560w"  alt="How to make Lavender essential oils" /></figure></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Step 2</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Once you've picked out all your Lavender flowers, put them inside your airtight glass container. The size of the container and how many flowers you'll put inside is mainly up to you. But we suggest you fill in your container at least 3/4 full with Lavender flowers.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Step 3</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Pour in your carrier oil and fill the airtight glass container. Make sure your Lavender flowers are entirely soaked and submerged with oil. You can mix two types of oils if you want to, such as olive oil and almond oil.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Step 4</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Let your Lavender oil mixture sit for 1-3 weeks. It's best if you put your jar somewhere warm or sunny (but not direct sunlight) to help it infuse a lot better. Don't forget to turn and shake your container occasionally as the flowers may float on oil.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:file {"href":"https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/sfa8VjZYRBXVgdh9MDMvSypCc6QvxX__MIamwL3XbXeXjBb5N-CA_0R7Syk5iEKLOa-Kors2xqz0zj7PagCXhYNffTFT0v2_erYJY6J2-VOZgM2KY4vJpwpsBCaLKIbR62M1s2-m"} --></p>
<div class="wp-block-file"><a><img loading="lazy" width="624" height="413" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/sfa8VjZYRBXVgdh9MDMvSypCc6QvxX__MIamwL3XbXeXjBb5N-CA_0R7Syk5iEKLOa-Kors2xqz0zj7PagCXhYNffTFT0v2_erYJY6J2-VOZgM2KY4vJpwpsBCaLKIbR62M1s2-m"></a><a href="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/sfa8VjZYRBXVgdh9MDMvSypCc6QvxX__MIamwL3XbXeXjBb5N-CA_0R7Syk5iEKLOa-Kors2xqz0zj7PagCXhYNffTFT0v2_erYJY6J2-VOZgM2KY4vJpwpsBCaLKIbR62M1s2-m" class="wp-block-file__button" download>Download</a></div>
<p>
<!-- /wp:file --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Step 5</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>After 3 weeks, strain your Lavender oil mixture to remove the flowers. You can use a fine-mesh strainer by placing it on a bowl and pouring your Lavender oil mixture all through. But if you want to juice out all the good 'ol bits from those Lavender flowers, we recommend using cheesecloth instead of (or with) a strainer. You can then wring the cloth and squeeze all the remaining oil from the Lavender flowers.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Step 6</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Transfer your freshly-made Lavender oil into the jar or bottle where you'd want to store it. This will most likely have a wonderful mild scent that is not too overpowering when you use it. If you wish to make the smell more intense, you can mix it with store-bought Lavender essential oil since these are a lot more potent than homemade ones. Just be careful when adding more potent essential oils since yours is pretty much scented already.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Fun fact:</strong> Commercial or store-bought Lavender essential oils undergo a more complicated process like steam distillation. It also has a smaller yield than a homemade variant, which explains why they could be a bit pricey.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Shelf-life</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Homemade Lavender oils can last up to <strong>1 year</strong>. Make sure to keep it in a cool, dry, and not too sunny place to prolong its shelf-life.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How do you make Lavender oil from fresh Lavender?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/IQ7UhUlYE9xMebWsz1PW6K4B8TnbX_062mFfmGGXaMvUnjtrZ_Kv6A9DRUgqMDP5_EyTcUWacoppjv5MXR0VOiulN7Pbm6ZQX3S8CRY9fJi6Ekky-1p70O--7AHM-cK0ns8rLmfR" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you happen to harvest or simply get your hands on a bunch of fresh Lavender, you can turn them into Lavender oil as well.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the same procedure we mentioned above. However, you must first <strong>dry your fresh Lavender</strong> before proceeding with the steps above. Using fresh Lavender directly is not advisable because it could spoil your Lavender oil. Your flowers should be completely dry to prolong the shelf life of your essential oil.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Pro tip:</strong> If you're the type who keeps Lavender flowers in a vase in your home, don't throw them away when they are wilted and dry. You can use your dried up Lavender to make Lavender oil!&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>How to dry your Lavender?</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Step 1</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Cut your fresh Lavender into stalks (about 6 inches long).</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Step 2</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Group them into small bunches and tie the stalks together. Think of it as making a small Lavender bouquet.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Step 3</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Hang your 'Lavender bouquets' upside down in a warm and dry place. It's best if you place them somewhere with occasional sunlight to help them dry better.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/c-JItYor8_lOLfpdbeJNt9L40oNzdgitzuEDxctIWQ9gemkgz37PPMkfr9p1IoOHxGQldnHlhiqt4XyaxqpEgyjgWoJFuBVf_9Cfl2xNncyCF000N2zOYi5mMOe88HLfc_R8yVKU" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Step 4</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Let your Lavender flowers hang like this for at least 2-3 weeks to make sure they're completely dry. After 2-3 weeks, you can make your Lavender oil mixture (follow the procedure listed above).&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How much Lavender does it take to make essential oil?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The amount of Lavender you'd need for homemade Lavender mostly depends on how much Lavender oil you want to make. You must first choose the size of the container where you'll infuse your Lavender oil. The best ratio is to fill <strong>3/4 of your container</strong> with Lavender flowers. Then fill the rest of the container with a carrier oil.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Types of carrier oil</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/gNz55VFIS0sgSF0UpeK28HLEntvIY46VjMBbtHCRQo1MsKJQP2W5k69o6lqhe2_a0ySCf0laImmcZnRRBb9Uui8qenDCd1sH7LHkX_26quvIrIceNzVZwBWd0Q0cbkoI-05n0G5m" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Carrier oils come in different types. Most of them don't evaporate quickly compared to commercial essential oils and have various medicinal properties. You can choose from different varieties of carrier oils, depending on your needs.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here is a list of the different carrier oils you can use to make your Lavender essential oil. These oils are listed according to their comedogenic scale (since you'll most likely use your Lavender oil for different purposes).</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This <strong>Comedogenic scale</strong> ranking is based on how likely the oil may <strong>clog your pores</strong>. 0 being the non-clogging and 5 being the highest possibility of it to clog your pores.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Name</strong></td>
<td><strong>Comedogenic rating</strong></td>
<td><strong>Ideal skin type</strong></td>
<td><strong>Medicinal properties</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Argan Oil</td>
<td>0</td>
<td>Most Skin Types</td>
<td>Promotes hair growthRegenerates skin cells</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Hemp Seed Oil</td>
<td>0</td>
<td>Most Skin Types, Oily/Acne-Prone</td>
<td>Anti-inflammatoryA natural analgesic (pain-reliever)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Castor Oil</td>
<td>1</td>
<td>Most Skin Types, Oily/Acne-Prone</td>
<td>Rich in vitamin ERelieve inflammationSoothe irritated skin</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Grapeseed Oil</td>
<td>1</td>
<td>Most Skin Types</td>
<td>Loaded with antioxidantsHas antiseptic properties</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Sweet Almond Oil</td>
<td>2</td>
<td>Dry, Sensitive, Acne-Prone</td>
<td>Relieve inflammationSoothe irritated skin</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Jojoba Oil</td>
<td>2</td>
<td>Most Skin Types, Oily/Acne-Prone</td>
<td>Natural anti-fungalReduces inflammationExcellent moisturizer</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Avocado Oil</td>
<td>3</td>
<td>Dry, Acne-Prone</td>
<td>Anti-inflammatoryIdeal for irritable skin conditions</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Evening Primrose Oil</td>
<td>2-3</td>
<td>Oily, Acne-Prone, Combination</td>
<td>Potent anti-inflammatoryEffective in treating skin conditions</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Moringa Oil</td>
<td>3-4</td>
<td>Dry, Combination</td>
<td>Rich in antioxidantsAccelerate wound healing</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Coconut Oil</td>
<td>4</td>
<td>Very Dry</td>
<td>Excellent antifungal, anti-inflammatory and antibacterialDeep moisturizing properties</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Wheat Germ Oil</td>
<td>5&nbsp;</td>
<td>Very Dry, Damaged, Spot Treatment</td>
<td>Contains powerful antioxidantsRich in vitamin E</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What is the best Lavender for an essential oil?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Lavender, or Lavandula, is a flowering plant that belongs to the mint family. There are about 47 known Lavender species, but some of them are specially grown and cultivated for commercial purposes or as ornamental plants for landscape use.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Among these 47 species of Lavender plants, 2 stands out the most when making essential oils. These two are the following:</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Lavandula angustifolia or English Lavender</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/-0sDK3hm-lahk2DDl_xCDOPB4qKT2wE2SloVMY8BlycZKVDlUqgyEmm8MfqsBrgOOSMJW22CThrXYgR_xLwMLIaCvT1vktlMPK7yF629-L9iQZ8yvJgXSDNja8v0jcXJBcJLhqvn" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The <a href="https://plants.ces.ncsu.edu/plants/lavandula-angustifolia/">English Lavender</a> is one of the most popular Lavender species and is widely used in making essential oils. They usually have dark purple flowers with contrasting blue-green foliage. Even when dried, the English Lavender retains its color.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This flower yields an oil with sweet overtones, making them perfect for cosmetics, perfumes, salves, essential oils, and more.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>2. Lavandula × intermedia or Lavandin</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/31hfRJAn2UlVluRBlYie-ghrNC-bbOiTo0doRRuYd6monFpbMNEhrXaCnvI65fuvHyFR_j4lXDdcQIU1_iJOPyEiPZgnJ6kgvOUuT54Ny6MZnt5T-s3PJsPfYAPsZa_rvsS1VXA3" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This Lavender species is a crossbreed between English Lavender and Portuguese Lavender. They grow larger and have more flower spikes compared to the English Lavender.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><a href="https://plants.ces.ncsu.edu/plants/lavandula-x-intermedia/#:~:text=Lavandula%20x%20intermedia%20is%20a,seed%20from%20August%20to%20October.">Lavandin</a> also has a more medicinal aroma because of its higher camphor content, which produces a sharper overtone to its fragrance.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Benefits of Lavender oil</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Lavender essential oil is definitely a cult-favorite. Mainly because it doesn't only smell good, it's also versatile. Apart from aromatherapy, Lavender essential oils have tons of other uses. It also has many beauty and health benefits, which you might not know.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Relieves headache and nausea</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Lavender oils come in handy when you suffer from headaches. <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22517298/">Studies</a> show that applying Lavender oil to your temples, forehead, and behind your ears could relieve headaches. Inhaling the scent of Lavender oils can also help alleviate motion sickness and nausea.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Minimize acne</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Lavender is known to have antiseptic properties. Its antibacterial components can help treat and prevent acne, thus keeping your skin heal faster.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Nourishes skin</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/20/EZhKV6i4mT5lGj6p6m7h2-3ExLJ4mVpRK2to5Km_dyGMEU-tgds11YAR36GKXoHh9wWOb4km_0Mo_o4rkdNRr6ElJlK2bc7RAJh_Da8I6Pc31aTe4eMrcNh4qLY01SKx7iE-AfHW" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can use Lavender oil to nourish your skin. It's packed with antioxidants to keep your skin looking younger.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Soothes the nervous system</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3612440/">studies</a>, inhaling Lavender's scent has a calming and soothing effect and helps calm the nervous system. This can also help relieve stress, anxiety, and fatigue.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Heal minor wounds</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Applying Lavender oil mixed with some water can help stimulate cell regeneration and heal some minor wounds faster.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Got your Lavender ready?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Fill your home with the calming and relaxing scent of Lavender and make it last for a year long! I hope this article helps you make your very own Lavender essential oil. You can also give it away as an excellent gift for your loved ones for the holidays or sell them to gain profit!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Kua Number Calculator: How to Find Your Feng Shui Kua Number</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/kua-number-calculator-how-to-find-your-feng-shui-kua-number.html"/>
        <id>https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/kua-number-calculator-how-to-find-your-feng-shui-kua-number.html</id>

        <updated>2022-08-28T18:53:26-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    In Feng Shui, there is a fundamental concept known as the "Kua Number". It is a personal number&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/27/jxLxPZaApQJhDEW7zw1xRuDAvAtKd6kSEcOFcvBpXMLnyvPvNYc6O640QQFkkbZ6ndEoSJSUyQsjAtkw2dEvmVxK6721THGxbCQJgHn4zkPsqN4S8LHdBT3-2wkRNYXa_9g5CX6y" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In Feng Shui, there is a fundamental concept known as the "Kua Number". </p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>It is a personal number based on a person's birth year and gender. Your birth year is believed to significantly influence certain features, qualities, and abilities of an individual. It is also believed that having a better understanding of the Kua Number could help develop a person's potential and even overall life improvement.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you want to better understand the Kua number, here is a quick and simple guide about Kua Numbers and how to use a Kua Number calculator.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What is my Kua number?&nbsp;</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Kua Numbers are also known as the Eight Mansions or Eight Houses Feng Shui. It is commonly used to determine the favorable directions you should face and locations for your house's essential areas, such as your bedroom and front door. This number also offers insight into your energetic compatibility with other people.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Your Kua number can also be called your Bagua number, ming gua, gua number, or personal trigram.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>As mentioned earlier, your Kua number is determined by your birth year and your gender.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Why should I know my Kua number?</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The purpose of knowing your Kua number(pronounced as GWAH) is to make feng shui readings and adjustments that are specific to your PERSONALITY.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>It is significant to know your Feng Shui Kua number because it is used to identify good or bad directions and locations for the places you spend most of your time. You can use these directions to your advantage by facing your best ones when you're working or studying or eating. Likewise, you should avoid staying or facing your bad directions and locations.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Through the interpretation of different combinations of the trigrams (the black line symbols), it is believed that humans can be guided to follow the path of least resistance through the energy offered by the influential forces of Earth (Yin) and heaven (Yang).</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/27/d5ECWw-17gNff2zluje2lddKEvAGXaR93c1uawo24ARU9bSMnDM5BvyZPc9suV3eiflDqT9vXWqgUdTOAfyX5GjZnuYN8JF-HoqKOZi2vvKNDVP3ihV1eO8Tv1Iep-PF8kWwfSS7" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>By organizing your areas of personal energy in a certain way, spending time, or even just facing these directions when you sleep or sit down, you can minimize the stress and create more joy in your life. You can use it to directly benefit you in your interior living space, whether it may be at home or at work. Applying Feng Shui using your Kua number is one of the best ways to use Feng Shui to improve your life.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>It's great to make it a habit to use your Feng Shui Kua number as this is your specific Life Force Energy number. Then, arm yourself with a good feng shui compass to locate your best directions and spend as much time possible facing there.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How to calculate your Kua number?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The two main components of calculating your Kua number is your birth year and your gender.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>IMPORTANT</strong>: Because this calculation uses the Chinese calendar, if you were born before February 4, (January 1 - February 3) you'll use the year prior. For example, you were born on January 12, 1976, you'll use 1975 for your birth year.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you 'e born after February 4, you can use the same birth year in your birth certificate or your real birth year.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here's how you can calculate your Kua number.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Step 1: Turning your birth year to a single base number.</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You need to convert your birth year to a single-digit number. To do this, the first step id to add up the four digits of your birth year.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In this case, we'll use the year 1995.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>1+9+9+5 = 24</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Because 24 still has two digits, you should add up the two digits again as follows:&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>2+4 = 6</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>6 is the base number that you will be using in Step 2.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Step 2: Finding your Kua number based on gender</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This part uses your gender for calculation. If you prefer to identify with another gender, you use what you're most comfortable with.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>For males, subtract your base number from eleven.</li>
<li>For females, add four to your base number.</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Using the base number we got from step 1, we will get these Kua numbers:</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Male: 11 – 6 = 5</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Female: 4 + 6 = 10</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you get a single-digit number in this step, then you have your Kua number. Otherwise, you need to proceed to step 3.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>NOTE:</strong> 5 is basically a non-existent number. If you get 5 as a Kua number, you need to convert it to the following:</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Male: 5 = 2</li>
<li>Female: 5 = 8</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In the case above, our result for the male Kua computation is 5, so we need to convert it to 2 since it's for a male Kua number.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>That makes it 2 as the Kua number for the male born in 1995.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/27/zd3ECaxTNtcocQ5zrX78bNpfCWWnwa-EV3piuZCHZOmMCh9CKFpXrGQ-Cb8ExyNAg0pNjIhLWxjTJmgb43CKA3bouoFkC39yNBt50JWxqBgPpwmK-to5u26bzJ2LEHEO7_tgputu" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Step 3: Confirming your Kua number</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The Kua number must be a single digit, which means it should be between 1-9 only. Since we got 10 as the sum for the Female Kua number in the example above, we should subtract 9 to get the right Kua number. The same method applies to male Kua numbers as well.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In this case, 10-9 = 1.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>1 is the right or final Kua number for the Female born in 1995.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you're still confused with the computation, you can also use a <a href="https://redlotusletter.com/resources/kua-calculator/">Kua number calculator</a>. All you need to do is input your birthdate and gender, and the program will compute the Kua number for you.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What does your Kua number mean?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Two groups of Feng Shui Kua number</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The Feng Shui Kua Number is divided people into 2 groups - the East and West groups.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Those with Kua number is 1, 3, 4, 9, or a 5 (male) belong to the East group.</li>
<li>While those with Kua number is 2, 6, 7, 8, or a 5 (female) belong to the West group.</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The four auspicious directions of the East group include North, South, East, and Southeast. Meanwhile, the West group is the complete opposite, with their four auspicious directions at Northwest, Southwest, West, and Northeast.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here's a simple breakdown of the lucky and unlucky directions for the East group.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table {"className":"is-style-stripes"} --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>East Group</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Lucky Directions</td>
<td>Unlucky Directions</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Kua number</td>
<td>Success</td>
<td>Health</td>
<td>Love &amp; Relationships</td>
<td>Wisdon &amp; Growth</td>
<td>Misfortune</td>
<td>Five Ghosts</td>
<td>Six Killings</td>
<td>Total Loss</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>SE</td>
<td>E</td>
<td>S</td>
<td>N</td>
<td>W</td>
<td>NE</td>
<td>NW</td>
<td>SW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td>S</td>
<td>N</td>
<td>SE</td>
<td>E</td>
<td>SW</td>
<td>NW</td>
<td>NE</td>
<td>W</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td>N</td>
<td>S</td>
<td>E</td>
<td>SE</td>
<td>NW</td>
<td>SW</td>
<td>W</td>
<td>NE</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>9</td>
<td>E</td>
<td>SE</td>
<td>N</td>
<td>S</td>
<td>NE</td>
<td>W</td>
<td>SW</td>
<td>NW</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here's a simple breakdown of the lucky and unlucky directions for the West group.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:table {"className":"is-style-stripes"} --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>West Group</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Lucky Directions</td>
<td>Unlucky Directions</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Kua number</td>
<td>Success</td>
<td>Health</td>
<td>Love &amp; Relationships</td>
<td>Wisdon &amp; Growth</td>
<td>Misfortune</td>
<td>Five Ghosts</td>
<td>Six Killings</td>
<td>Total Loss</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5 (male)</td>
<td>NE</td>
<td>W</td>
<td>NW</td>
<td>SW</td>
<td>E</td>
<td>SE</td>
<td>S</td>
<td>N</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5 (female)</td>
<td>SW</td>
<td>NW</td>
<td>W</td>
<td>NE</td>
<td>S</td>
<td>N</td>
<td>E</td>
<td>SE</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2</td>
<td>NE</td>
<td>W</td>
<td>NW</td>
<td>SW</td>
<td>E</td>
<td>SE</td>
<td>S</td>
<td>N</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6</td>
<td>SE</td>
<td>NE</td>
<td>SW</td>
<td>NW</td>
<td>SE</td>
<td>WN</td>
<td>SW</td>
<td>NW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7</td>
<td>NW</td>
<td>SW</td>
<td>NE</td>
<td>W</td>
<td>N</td>
<td>S</td>
<td>SE</td>
<td>E</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8</td>
<td>SW</td>
<td>NW</td>
<td>W</td>
<td>NE</td>
<td>S</td>
<td>N</td>
<td>E</td>
<td>SE</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:table --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How to use the Feng Shui Kua number in your home?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Now that you know your Kua number, you can start utilizing its powers by applying the readings in your living space. You can use it to properly position your furniture and the overall layout of your home, office, bedroom, etc. Here are some easy to follow suggestions on how you can use your Feng Shui Kua number.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Sleep or position your bed with your head pointed to one of your good directions.</li>
<li>Your house's main door should face one of your best directions.</li>
<li>Sit at your desk facing one of your auspicious directions in your office or study area.</li>
<li>Dine and seat each family member at the table in their best directions.</li>
<li>Always negotiate (a mortgage, raise, or anything) facing your best direction.</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You may not always be able to face, sleep, eat, etc. in your best direction, but do try it as many times and as often as possible.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>What to do if you have a problem with placement?</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/27/FyUVK2upunJ4otgYpiDeHGHVI5OHr2r9Dp6K-NQQ5X79RvjU1gmpQmWogCi3YY4sPra4VeRKAok9tR0oc08k2_MzHzYmayDmCCk2s1DiA3aAmhMcmERMCuC9V_pCrdwMfP7ulhe_" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Unlucky directions may provoke fear for those who are new to Feng Shui. Remember, Your Kua number a great way to use Feng Shui for your personal benefit, but don't force it to apply on everything you own.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You'd never want to move your bed to a windowed wall just because it's in your auspicious direction. Same as turning your desk to the door because it will activate your success direction. This will result in poor placement — and that in itself brings bad luck and problems! So, don't be tempted.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When you have something placed in an unlucky location, don't fret too much. What's important to remember is that every corner of the home should be activated – even the ones that are in a loss direction. All you need to do is find Feng Shui cures to contradict the misplacement, and everything will be okay.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Have you found your Kua number?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The Feng Shui Kua Number is a powerful tool to apply Feng Shui for your own benefit. You can use it even in simple ways, such as what direction you should face when you’re sitting at your desk or sleeping in your bed.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>But if following it starts to become complicated and difficult, consider taking a step back and look at the bigger picture. Let the wisdom of using it help you rather than hold you back.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to Wear a Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/how-to-wear-a-feng-shui-pixiu-mantra-ring.html"/>
        <id>https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/how-to-wear-a-feng-shui-pixiu-mantra-ring.html</id>

        <updated>2022-08-28T18:53:26-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    There are many charms, bracelets, and other accessories related to Feng Shui. They are known to attract different&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/26/bXI4frqcMzSDaGaZ4iQys-y3uOlAY8pmDJV7dKSU29qkYL0QjDHpwX6vZb4KYzuje7bmFm2Brdl0b7dsQ3KC9qxvA7PNvG1WaMM8EZXDxJfqAXhVFzhUrmh6N6Mpc3xETeTQqYiV" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are many charms, bracelets, and other accessories related to Feng Shui. They are known to attract different energies, depending on their symbols and what they are made of. In particular, one is a ring known to attract good fortune and wealth - the Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In this article, we'll talk about the Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring and how its energy attracting abilities help you improve your wealth.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What is a Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring is commonly made of silver or copper with two distinct Feng Shui symbols, the Pixiu and the Mantra.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>What is Pixiu?</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/26/uoIjn-f_GAoeE1UA0-jR1-9ILqKHePi1E7lL4JCYNzYu_46KpPEoDlLG8pT2jVoVyIl_zdzXWo6Z8gpnYx062Na61z8eWGxa6XznAvNfy-3r8AK3TplxD1G7QKWM_CKrj_d2I0qy" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Pixiu or Pi Xiu is a Chinese celestial auspicious creature that is believed to draw money and wealth. According to Chinese legends, Pixiu can only eat gold, silver, and other precious treasures. When the Jade emperor sealed its anus, all the treasures Pixiu has devoured stayed in its belly for eternity.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This legend led to the belief that Pixiu attracts fortune and won't permit wealth to leave one's life. Thus, making it a truly powerful symbol of wealth.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>What is a Mantra?</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A mantra (originally from Buddhism and Hinduism) is a sacred sound or utterance repeated frequently. It is known to have religious, magical, or spiritual powers.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The Pixiu ring is also called a mantra Pixiu ring because a mantra is imprinted on the ring's inner part. This famous Mantra came from ancient Sanskrit and is called Om Mani Padme Hum. This Mantra is believed to possess the power of bringing the wearer good luck, accumulated fortune, and, of course, happiness.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"align":"center"} --></p>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/26/TONUvfdcQJn219sLC4fPIeEAsVCrhzYCssnbqpPX2wLPm4H76FJR5MwykUOOWBSErBvCmq5VhYQpcrajVJmuQuM4FVRyYuHqX-xFJRhchbUjktN34waZLKqsOdElynB5AuRtE2b-" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>What does the Om Mani Padme Hum Mantra mean?</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The Mantra, Om Mani Padme Hum, translates to praise to the jewel in the lotus. Each syllable has its own meaning too:</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --></p>
<h4>Om - Purifies ego.</h4>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Om is perhaps the most powerful and ancient word used in meditation and chants. It's believed that the frequency/vibration of this syllable connects your soul to the creator. It is used to purify or cleanse. It's also believed to detach the ego, so the soul can temporarily stay and reconnect with divinity.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --></p>
<h4>Ma - Purifies jealousy.</h4>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Ma represents ethics and is a cleaner of jealous tendencies. It aids you in releasing attachments and provides you with the energies that initiate compassion.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --></p>
<h4>Ni - Purifies desire.</h4>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Ni represents one's patience and compassion. It purifies the passionate emotions of want and desire.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --></p>
<h4>Pad - Purifies ignorance.</h4>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Pad represents diligence. It purifies ignorance and lets you release your prejudices, so you no longer stand in judgment of others.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --></p>
<h4>Me - Purifies greed.</h4>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Me represents concentration. It provides you the ability to disconnect yourself from various earthly attachments, such as greed.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --></p>
<h4>Hum - Purifies hatred.</h4>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Hum represents the unification of all things. It is the energy that diffuses inner wisdom and purifies hate by letting you release negative thoughts of hatred and aggressive desires.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>With all these, the Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra ring may:</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Conduct good luck and fortune</li>
<li>Enhance wealth and riches</li>
<li>Bring unexpected windfall luck</li>
<li>Protect individuals and building</li>
<li>Protect against evil forces, obstacles, and hardship</li>
<li>Generate good Feng Shui or earth luck</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How do you wear a Pixiu ring?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In Chinese culture and tradition, rings don't only function as an accessory. You should also wear them on the right finger as each one has significance and meaning.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For a Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring, it is best to wear it on your <strong>right middle finger</strong>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/26/0cMcuPx1hfzsfkyZBdepzvhR91V2c6New82F7ryepZKm5NR_8_fO6A-TrqEkialdYNy3qLSQNaSC0v0Of6GssprZtPkZC_9-x9wyzbI3UAGKFI88UTmHQTaxFrZaPaOLkfv2DJVV" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Placing a feng shui ring on your middle finger connects the gap between that finger and the index finger, right where the palm's Wealth Line runs. So it helps to strike a balance and is linked to responsibility. <strong>It is believed that a ring worn on the middle finger attracts money by increasing your money luck and assists you in accumulating wealth.</strong> Thus, making it perfect for a Pixiu Mantra ring.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Be careful <strong>not to wear this ring on your thumb</strong> because it is believed that a ring on the thumb will rob you of all wealth and sabotage your career success.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Where should Pixiu be placed?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When wearing the Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra ring, Pixiu must be placed on your finger's top center with it facing outwards. If it's in your right hand, Pixiu should face to the right. If it's in your left hand, Pixiu should face to the left.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Wearing Pixiu outwards symbolizes going out to gather wealth, luck and bring it back for you. Do not wear it facing towards yourself.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are also a few things you need to remember when wearing a Pixiu accessory. Just like the popular <a href="https://www.luckycathome.com/index.php/2020/08/12/feng-shui-black-obsidian-bracelet-how-does-it-work/">Pixiu Black Obsidian Bracelet</a>, a Pixiu Mantra ring also requires a few maintenance steps before using and when not in use. Feng Shui experts believe that Pixiu will remain devoted to its master when it's well taken care of. Once neglected, Pixiu can choose to fly away.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>How to activate your Pixiu Mantra ring?</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/26/XikziQlgnibW644Tn5F003jnvki1Cghqw-SLD_7Eu7_HCqhOg5zphdndw2rkRI4B_AfnwDRE1IJmj1RRF1NnHHO15LBS_UVe4Zxv_WuNP-ONKX_PD4rZd5IAhWo6-EA58-bRlj4_" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To activate your Pixiu Mantra ring, you'll need a silver bowl and a few pieces of gold (coins or other gold items), precious gems, or jewelry. Fill the bowl with these items and place it in your living room (never your bedroom). When not in use, put your Pixiu Mantra ring in the silver bowl with Pixiu facing your front door. It helps Pixiu draw more riches towards your home.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When in use, you must also give it attention by touching Pixiu a few times a day to bring luck and good fortune. Be careful not to touch its eyes and mouth. According to legends, touching Pixiu's mouth may ruin the owner's wealth. There's even an ancient Chinese saying that illustrates how to handle Pixiu:</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong><em>"Touch Pixiu once, good luck comes.</em></strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong><em>Twice money rolls in.</em></strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong><em>Three times, promotions all the way up!"</em></strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What finger do you wear a lucky ring on?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>As I mentioned earlier, in Chinese culture, rings must be worn on the correct finger as they have various meanings. The same goes for Feng Shui. Wearing the ring on the right finger has many superstitious beliefs. Here are they:</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/26/ogvE2EHpTxMvp9U9Ou6unguiIAcKIpl1rq2HVq6U7mzWgoSLT_uJSX_P91iiJHk7mWQyNM75SLsHZeUVImEUASvKmVVgC1UgoRjRhxWLjkjBB5ZnALHjTsFzTQOr3yQlV-Sqjnmo" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Appropriate hand</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The appropriate hand used for wearing a ring depends on the yin (female) yang (male) symbol. To attract the best Feng Shui energies, men should wear rings on their left hands. Women should wear their rings on their right hands.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>The fingers</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Index finger</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In Feng Shui, the index finger is known as the finger of authority. Choosing to put a ring on this finger is regarded as a way to demonstrate social standing, power, and authority. It is best for people in sales or business and for someone seeking a promotion or a raise.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Middle finger</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Wearing a ring on the middle finger attracts money by increasing your money luck and accumulating wealth. It is also known to help strike a balance and is associated with responsibility.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Ring finger</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The ring finger is known to attract everlasting love, so it is most connected to marriage and engagement. For Singles, you should avoid wearing a ring on this finger to prevent misunderstanding.&nbsp; Instead, you can wear a yellow gold ring on your index finger (left male, right female).</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When you meet the love of your life, move this ring to your middle finger to guarantee your relationship will move closer to marriage and your ring finger.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/26/d2FrnOWLX1DiVQAuhwC5SM6qVKVQZMDK-MZmiDl7FVkxSZG-32wvIosmY0PeGea5WMlcwG3K9J3NlAd94xYMrDCGRjd7Za98S1dSCDyVs_5kguhmRY7DIH55IdOvDN1I3Km86e52" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Little/pinky finger</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Wearing a jade ring on your little/pinky finger is believed to bring you wealth. You should wear the lucky ring on your left hand for males, and for females, you should wear it on your right hand. Besides that, it is also said to protect you from villains and backstabbers.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Thumb finger</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Some cultures believe the thumb represents longevity and health and advise to wear a ring on this finger. However, in Feng Shui, it is recommended to never wear a ring on this finger. It is believed that a ring on the thumb will take away all your wealth and sabotage your career success.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Can I wear Pixiu to sleep?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are two instances where you should NEVER wear your Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra ring: when bathing and sleeping.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When not in use, place it in your living room, on the silver bowl I mentioned earlier. Remember, Pixiu should be facing your front door or a window to attract wealth luck towards you.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here are other things you should remember when wearing a Pixiu Mantra ring:</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Do not allow others to touch it as it could disconnect from you. When someone else touches your ring, cleanse it with water.</li>
<li>Don't let your Pi Xiu be contaminated by blood. Otherwise, its money-drawing effect could be ruined.</li>
<li>People aged under 16 and over 70 should not wear a Pixiu Mantra ring as they might not control the vital energy from the fierce creature.</li>
<li>Pregnant women should not wear any Pixiu accessories. They can do this after giving birth.</li>
<li>When wearing Pixiu, remember to touch it frequently to let it know you are its master.</li>
<li>Don't eat chili while wearing Pi Xiu because it can ruin your luck in making money.</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Should you wear a Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra Ring?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Now that you know many things about the Feng Shui Pixiu Mantra ring, You can try out its luck and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DATOO-Adjustable-Mantra-Protection-Wealth/dp/B07SSH2K1S">purchase one</a>. But do take note of the responsibilities attached to this ring. You must be ready to do it for you to maximize its wealth-attracting effects.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What Color to Paint Your Bedroom?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/what-color-to-paint-your-bedroom.html"/>
        <id>https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/what-color-to-paint-your-bedroom.html</id>

        <updated>2022-08-28T18:53:26-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    There are thousands of colors and color combinations you can use for a bedroom wall paint. With so&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/25/nadJLiI1lYLQ2fH3X4NZa3ccCuhz9rtbqgSxCDQDYrRRN9TOmx1GTOu6qktWZgx4Wr8mOrqBPAs1AhdyT--iFdhNCiaqSjBGOqM9Q5W1WA4ueszjzoyA2NS8sRbfeSpqeVrfUsWW" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are thousands of colors and color combinations you can use for a bedroom wall paint. With so many options on your hands, it can be quite tricky to choose which color is the best.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To help you determine the right paint color for your bedroom, here are some tips and tricks you can follow to make your selection process a lot easier.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Tips on selecting the best paint color for your bedroom&nbsp;</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Start with colors you love</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The easiest way to determine what colors you're going to use is to choose from the colors you love. Since bedrooms are spaces where you can showcase your personal style, picking a color from your favorites is a no-brainer.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You don't have to bind yourself with traditional colors. You can definitely choose and create your desired mood for the room. Picking colors that reflect your personal vision for the room will help you create a colorful space that feels yours uniquely.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>2. Look for a paint color inspiration</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/25/to7LUpRi41hvqeTaa8_CR8jZl9PSUUC2K70EYyWZMQ8nClQkZ04z-k02oGW9lbzBoCK1kxjXrTdZKCGX6Nq7slPePVycwmPIgH1BTIWKE7n8VthasU1DrLVNZrUUrlDYwcIJeOMb" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are tons of paint color ideas across different mediums. Catalogs and magazines have always been the staple of decorating inspiration. Retailer sites and paint company websites also offer different inspirations for using colors as well as mixing and matching them to craft a beautiful color harmony in a space.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Social media sites like Instagram and Pinterest also offer tons of paint color inspiration refreshed in real-time. If you want to compile different looks to choose from, Pinterest is great for creating inspiration boards for your favorite ideas. All you need to do is pin it on your profile.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Choose a color scheme based on your furniture</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Consider choosing a color that matches the colors of your bedroom furniture. For example, you have a favorite painting in your bedroom, you can pick a subtle tone from that painting as your walls' inspiration. You can also use colors from other larger pieces like your a chair, floor rug, or beddings, and choose paint colors that match these hues.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>But if you're starting from a new bedroom (no furniture), you can disregard this tip.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>4. Use lighter or darker shades and its undertones</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/25/evnvTinhOSckuv35_zeXvToG9SY0H4Ont10N21CvnVgEhYe4zE9O-A4rHAQsRytbPu_-NIoxW6tPfa4a4GWXwL798QKHTsoj861CN0v0U99AEd36E1qasd58hWLMdigzu7z2PDIh" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you feel like your chosen color doesn't work, don't give up on it right away. Sometimes, you just need a little adjustment to find the perfect paint color. Consider using a lighter or darker shade of the same color. Many paint color samples are put on a paint strip in gradual shades. If you can't find a paint color you'd like, you can also ask the paint store to customize the color depending on the percentages of light or dark shades.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also work on the undertones of a specific color. A simple peach color may lean to either a pinkish undertone or a more orange undertone. Knowing your chosen color's undertones can help you color coordinate your wall paint from the rest of the components inside your bedroom.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>5. Sample your paint colors</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>One important tip before committing to a paint color for your bedroom is to apply a sample color on your wall. Many people tend to return their purchased paint because it was not the one they wanted. Don't make this mistake and apply a sample color on your walls before buying gallons of paint.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>It'll also be helpful if you could calculate the amount of paint you'll be needing for your bedroom walls. This will save you from buying too much and wasting paint or buying too little, forcing you to make another trip to the paint center.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>6. Paint an accent wall</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/25/OJBilSw_N62k4_uUhlEsPgQJg3XzyGsgS94zk4HTe8ijgV_kz0bswp4fWVCutyQ3_bhEcNgoVhz0Wf5M_WAWGFsQS5n5vMHsS8-pkyE4PU7hKnrUOwBc--_A5JzZ-ayBcivpD8Fs" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Bold and bright colors aren't advisable for bedroom wall paint because it can make a space too enclosed and affect your sleep. But you can still use the bright colors you love while also giving it depth and variety by painting it on one wall instead of all the walls in your bedroom. This is called an accent wall.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can paint it on the wall behind your bed, or the side with a window or a closet. Then, you can pick a coordinating color for the rest of your walls.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>7. Don't forget your ceiling</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>It's nice to repaint your walls but don't leave your ceiling behind. Painting your n ceiling can also add depth to your bedroom and create an entirely different mood. If you have low ceilings, choose a light color to make it appear higher. But if you have an elevated ceiling in your bedroom, you can try painting it with a warmer color or a color that's 2 shades darker than your walls.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>8. Pick the right sheen</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Paints have different sheens on gloss. For your walls, you'd want to avoid paints with a really glossy finish as it can accentuate the flaws of your walls.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here are a few general guidelines for the different paint finish choices:</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Flat (Matte): </strong>Zero shine and really matte. It's perfect for bedrooms and ceilings.</li>
<li><strong>Flat Enamel:</strong> This has no shine, but is easier to clean compared to flat paint. It's also perfect for bedrooms, living rooms, and ceilings. If you have kids or pets, this is a better choice compared to flat paint.</li>
<li><strong>Eggshell Enamel:</strong> This paint has a bit of shine and is suitable for living rooms. It's easier to clean as well where most scuffs can be wiped off using a damp cloth.</li>
<li><strong>Satin Enamel:</strong> This has more shine compared to the former mentioned. It works well on areas with moisture and is also easily wipeable, making it perfect for bathrooms and kitchens.</li>
<li><strong>Semi-Gloss Enamel: </strong>This paint is shiny but not super glass-like glossy. It's perfect for trims, cabinets, and high-moisture areas.</li>
<li><strong>Hi-Gloss Enamel: </strong>This is the super shiny type, almost like a glass finish. It is perfect for high use surfaces like railings or furniture.</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Choosing your color family</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Choosing the right color family for your bedroom paint color can be influenced by different factors. Listed below are some color family ideas you can consider.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Neutrals: Calm and Inviting</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/25/mPUJOK5Wc_J6-xe_UASGFAERY_hWcBsDZaahiA8AgL1ozbahFaz76tEf2DDSPsOTTq8Dj5Reqy-4OOUkk3u1Q68oKoZczpkaMZnJ7GGalOtX6H57oGVShemHeaEHUZ-nYVSrW6aL" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you want more calm and serene ambiance, go for neutral shades like white, ivory, beige, gray, black, and creme. These shades can also mix with different undertones and are very versatile. If you have a small and boxy bedroom, you can make it appear more spacious by painting it with bright and neutral colors. These colors fade into the background and can make your furniture and other bedroom accents pop.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Blue: Peaceful escape</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/25/f9QWWgELu1dqHa18a481Uxokl9_qPicu3jDY1BXFAGF_ldN8ByXlzVkHqefE6Lgi5ZKVS6lqtTH-QYtpZ89pBraZvYCgSY0UzIlozRYq2q-lE1pyhB8OfYWewiSj61lHTXJSr3Jl" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Blue is a peaceful and soothing color, so it's perfect for helping you relax at the end of a long day. Choose shades of light blue and aqua if you want to create a carefree, calming atmosphere. You can also go with some medium to deep blues for a more tranquil feel.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Green: A nature-like atmosphere</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/25/8GIl5TkmQAZ4pyHnN7mSdPDjy1qQn0tmu3sK1zcJMzcQ03PS3YUMX56XGaaeu52aZWmOvDCVmA7zD_gROYhWz7-no9fd1KgNB32hGMyI1oaKuAfzFui7cfmvQcolJrQAGWskAMum" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Nature can give a very refreshing and relaxing vibe, which is why painting your bedroom green will make it feel so peaceful. Light green is excellent for creating an earthy backdrop reminding you of spring and renewal. Medium-toned greens can make your room feel like a cozy escape. And deep, saturated green tones bring in the moody effect of the forest.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Yellow: Happy and cozy</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/25/i05csCNzrqcrZ0B4yJK3XXnyKP4MCzJdNOO04D1GYhDaD8f77hUImV68Dp9O0tmmlpuWMHXTkic6w9_UXt2GCkbFe476FjAwYI5o_FHTo6cBol9BUUo2969bd3QXmFZTAin9yEiB" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Yellow is often associated with happiness. Using yellow paint on your walls can put yourself in a good mood after a long day, and it can also make you feel energized in the morning. Golden hues of yellow create warmth, while pale ones open space and create the illusion of additional light. Avoid using green-based yellows as these may be too dramatic to use as a paint color for your bedroom wall.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Violet: Serenity and romance</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/25/3cPmwwha_hNwzIeLGiV8buMKlS51WuwVb7zDjoUKM7EWkBu4sCtGbWGtMs2GPxmTZvQB-Sbi-INxvY1yMN3Iq6-8yJJDeoZdI_bKhuZ_eOMAX-VGyky6jCsJQ6lYqCzRqVphdvJK" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Choosing the violet paint color for your walls can make your bedroom feel more vintage and romantic. Cooler shades of purple, like periwinkle and lilac, are perfect if you want a peaceful, harmonic vibe. Warmer shades of purple, such as lavender, magenta, and eggplant, are more cheerful and bold.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Red and Orange: Passion and energy</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/25/mc0pnsEoQRRpzTZXJDztEb0nB3uKqsujqa-2EMPd9974Wijw_RPUQmXgNJ_egcmZRX8PrScW3UFmFwpKPPdK5sDR54nmMOobo8KCPQnAP3ya498YQmwvaKZZVP8Cjk4a4XNgksxW" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>While painting your walls in bright and vivid colors is a bold choice, using hues like burgundy red and burnt orange can inspire passion and warmth in your bedroom. However, be careful when choosing these shades. Over-saturated red and orange tones might be too energizing and make it difficult for you to sleep at night.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Pink: Cheerful and youthful</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/25/sZwyZ0KqvYHwaVBN-TfW8PcS-E1lyfSV5bJ-wMi9XpwoY3JZRe2FTUGdHyQOlidaC2_vBviH983g215NsWRnvnBbKMeCZHvfsB87KGoImVowPdl71_n-ysknovDQOyn1VxauaGUV" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Although pink is often associated with kids' rooms, this happy hue can also be used to beautifully brighten up any bedroom. This bright, cheery, and youthful color conjures up happy memories and feels invigorating and optimistic. This is why it's a perfect shade to wake up to each day. You can use pastel shades for a more relaxed and neutral feel or throw in some baby pink to brighten up your bedroom's mood.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>Terracotta: Warm and rustic</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/25/0tadj836jH-VDZbnutvM3ylO0ztKfpcYqlsxLYhWyePlsHX6SUD5GsW1ylyBE4h-c0abVeDIzUKMJ9x-k6mYrxDH9PF27r6tspPiQVjmsA0Xxd8SdSkh6a8EcBN8mbpsMiJdDcYV" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The brownish shade of terracotta has been trending for the past few years and shows no sign of declining popularity. This earthy color gives off a rustic feel and can warm up any space. If you want something more tame than orange, throw in a few brown undertones and go for a terracotta shade instead.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What color will you choose?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Colors are fun to play with. Don't be afraid to try painting new colors on your bedroom walls and explore what will work best based on your personality and mood. Your bedroom is your personal space, after all. I hope you learned from the tips listed in this article and apply them to your next bedroom paint color revamp.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Time to pick your color inspiration and start painting!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>5 Easy Ways to Open a Locked Bedroom Door</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/5-easy-ways-to-open-a-locked-bedroom-door.html"/>
        <id>https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/5-easy-ways-to-open-a-locked-bedroom-door.html</id>

        <updated>2022-08-28T18:53:26-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Your bedroom is your ultimate private space, where you can always be in control. But there are some&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/24/SgYVICG3AN6SjfxrN-PEfIYk8wuh0AMDzJoqt5U45ZGmbsV7EQfMBVQ3jv1pN1qQTCqnHj3t2Tq6xQ5EMFGet2GEDKDHMAMk5pzarlatD1UImsjV9QqjFBePXZaHYlKpI-DfI9Qb" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Your bedroom is your ultimate private space, where you can always be in control. But there are some instances where you can get locked out of it.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>It may be due to a relative, roommate, or a toddler accidentally locking himself/herself inside the room; you, accidentally locking yourself outside, or any other reason. Now you can't get in.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>No keys.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>No locksmiths.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>What should you do?</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To help you get through this situation (or if it ever happens again), here are some tips and tricks on how to open a locked bedroom door (without a key).</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What to do before opening a locked door?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Doors are made with different materials for various purposes. Usually, a bedroom door isn't designed for security but for privacy. Which is why it is possible to open them with a bit of force and maneuvering.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>But before all the unlocking action, you must first determine the type of lock your bedroom door has. Generally, a bedroom door has a push button in the knob or one that will use a twist button to lock. However, some people install more secure locks (like a deadbolt lock) on their bedroom door; these types are harder to open. So do consider what type of lock you're going to deal with.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For this article, we'll consider the standard type of lock for bedroom doors, which are the push button or twist button locks.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Ways to open a locked bedroom door</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>We compiled a list of different methods on how to unlock a locked door without a key. Some of these may cause some damage to your doorknob or the tool you'll be using, so keep that in mind.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Using a card</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/24/0P3Px_nZ1yvqqgB3faTwaq0yj2K9GFZxtm5ir4ZaULPXcYAz-ql4-1hKdjak7Ua6a4QrKdgEjn-7PT8Ca_9zFas8dKCqfwoNdFCw05cOk3gul3KEGM3EMJptZgV6cwozc-2MbEjB" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If your bedroom door has a latch bolt, with the angled edge is facing toward you, you can pop it free with a card. The card might get damaged/bent during the process, so make sure you're not using an important card like your debit or credit cards. Use cards that can be easily replaced, like a store rewards card, library card, or other flexible and quickly replaceable cards are best.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Procedure:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Take the plastic card and slide it into the gap between your door and the doorjamb.</li>
<li>Begin right above the door handle, and slide the card downwards and in.</li>
<li>You may have to wiggle or maneuver the card a bit. It could press against the latch assembly and allow you to open the door.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Some doors may require you to lean against them so that there is a little pressure. That pressure may help engage the lock more securely when you are sliding the card down. If it doesn't work when you slide the card down, try sliding the card up.</li>
<li>If you're lucky, you'll be able to open it on the first try. But it may require you to do this several times.</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>&nbsp;2. Using a hairpin</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/24/81eFZo3OQxrRoTvL8XBLLav9UJ752ZzSESidmbd-FRDWEObPf83AOEOfcAgavA_mmdEAZ38TgCS1sc56rGm9GCqq0ILAfkMkMSYNxFNS2t7GCaI7NQfjMAlBin855GHDVlPLMP70" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also use hairpins or bobby pins to unlock your bedroom door, just like the old trick you see in movies. Hairpins are usually easy to bend and manipulate to the shape you're aiming for since it's made of thin metal. It's not that had to open a door lock using a bobby pin, which is why many people opt for this method. You'll be needing two hairpins for this procedure.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> you can also use paper clips for this method.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Procedure:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Get one bobby pin. Bend one centimeter or so of the joint end for about 90 degrees, so it is perpendicular to the two free ends.</li>
<li>Insert this into the bottom of the keyhole and use the two free ends as a handle.</li>
<li>Take another hairpin and stretch it all the way through, so it becomes a single straight metal stick.</li>
<li>Add a small upward bend to one straight end. This acts as the "pick," and it goes into the top half of the keyhole.</li>
<li>Use your pick to push the spring-loaded pins up. Do this one at a time until the cylinder is free to turn.&nbsp;</li>
<li>There are two ways to pick the locks in your doorknob:</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Scrubbing Method</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>With this method, push the hairpin at the lower part of the keyhole and lift it upward. You have to repeat this in a circular motion until you successfully lift all the pins inside the doorknob. Remember to apply constant pressure to the other bobby pin below and turn the doorknob until it eventually opens.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Pin by Pin Method:</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If the scrubbing method does not work, you can try this method instead. Insert your hairpin, and as it comes into contact with the pins inside the doorknob, try to catch it right on the bend and lift the pins upward until it snaps into place. Repeat this with multiple pins until the lock will turn.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Using a butter knife</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/24/O7BlnePCEmt8HhOggNShHtlhwbe4laAjrjsV4IUmkIxXqS6Hb7VXs1jB26N18N-UGkMFpvlQpaT-qKv75chUEXwb2pfpCTt2-c78mlXFawsrufANVv2GqopQQVdXs00i0zlBJuu9" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you don't have plastic cards, bobby pins, or paper clips around, you might have a butter knife in your kitchen. Don't use a sharp knife for this method because you might accidentally hurt yourself. This method is very similar to the plastic card method.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Procedure:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Put the butter knife between the door and the doorjamb, just right above the doorknob.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Slide the knife down quickly, while leaning against the door.</li>
<li>Try this a couple of times until the door unlocks.</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>4. Using a screwdriver</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/24/X4KKB3BmCLesJnXit5DkQ3Wv9IOWmqTU-7wFewUujyyuU5BQdMlVSiccRe5k9-t6mHaDLEJE8cMz8qYVf_wC63JYAP2Ld-ARlr-ufNhv77zopLAQv2jpdbMFXM3b8PfBr6oLiLcZ" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If none of the above-mentioned methods above work, you can try to use a screwdriver to unlock your door. There are two ways on how you can use a screwdriver. Different types are used for these two procedures, so it's helpful to have a small and a standard-sized screwdriver.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Procedure 1:&nbsp;</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Use a small and flathead screwdriver and push the screwdriver into the keyhole on the doorknob. Put it straight through for as far as you can.</li>
<li>Twist or turn the screwdriver until the lock is opened.</li>
<li>You can also use a slotted screwdriver to open the spring locks if you wedge it between the bolt and frame.</li>
<li>Then, wiggle the screwdriver until you push the lock back into the door.</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Procedure 2:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>You can also use a larger, flathead screwdriver to remove the door hinges. This will only work if the hinges are exposed.</li>
<li>Grab a flathead screwdriver and a hammer or mallet (or anything hard that can be used to strike the screwdriver).</li>
<li>Position the screwdriver at the bottom of the knuckle, and the pin on the door hinge. Tap the handle of the screwdriver downwards using the hammer/mallet.</li>
<li>Once they are loose enough, remove the head and pin. You must repeat this for all the hinges. This may take some force and effort to finish.</li>
<li>Or you can also just remove the screws of the door hinges if it's exposed.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>5. Using a drill</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/24/qWD1eSCjMDj-xz8sIMPol5AFkm0_Pql47emcI2HTfcOUd4pTpPhmxDTNECeG1GpUcr-h2iQ-aA-qTn8myFKnwxg0gT4ShGf9L8pCgQYJqBakN4sbQXgoj0kBfxi8TQnzBwA343NI" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This method requires a more complicated tool, but you may have it at home - an electric drill. Unlike the previous ones, this method will leave permanent damage to your lock. You'll definitely need a new doorknob after this one.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Procedure:</h3>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Use the drill to trill the pins on the lock of your doorknob.</li>
<li>Drill it just above the top of the keyhole, in line with the cylinder's threshold and the pins' position when they are pushed free.</li>
<li>Experiment with different drill bit sizes. Start with a small one, and try using some lubricating oil to help.</li>
<li>Once you've finished drilling, try using a screwdriver into the keyhole, and you should be able to turn it.</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>When nothing else works</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you've tried everything to unlock the door and nothing is working, then you have some other options. Here are some of them.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Force the door open by kicking it</strong>. This may destroy your entire door, the doorknob, and the door frame. Not only will it shatter your bedroom door, but you can also hurt yourself in this process. This should definitely be the last resort and use it only in emergency situations.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/24/nvZC6HfiaQ9RNmCdko8MIbxzHjVPu9ZCFModcypCt9W081u2uEZcw_ORqpmi0X9yxVUIYWGbG7ZASC0EuGhU6NVb0SXDLksdsTGozM8cwhq5nFrWkczX1TwnFN4PjC4nB4DQfWFB" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Use a hammer to smash the doorknob</strong>. This will definitely damage the doorknob, and you'll need to purchase a replacement. Strike your doorknob repeatedly using a hammer, mallet, or any other hard object. A broken doorknob is an unlocked doorknob, that's for sure.</li>
<li><strong>Call a professional.</strong> When you don't want to do any damages and are not really sure of what to do, you can just call a professional locksmith to unlock the door for you. These professionals have the needed skills and tools to unlock a door, so it's a guarantee that you'll have it opened.</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>No more locked bedroom doors!</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Now you know different tricks to open a locked bedroom door. But remember, do these tips ONLY when you get locked out of YOUR BEDROOM. Don't ever do it to try and break into someone else's rooms. These methods take several minutes and very obvious, so you'll most likely be caught.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can practice these tricks, so it'll be easier for you to do it when an actual emergency comes. Nothing or no one could ever lock you out of your bedroom again. Not your toddler, not your roommate, not even your own door.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>20+ Fun and Easy Dr. Seuss Crafts for Kids</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/20-fun-and-easy-dr-seuss-crafts-for-kids.html"/>
        <id>https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/20-fun-and-easy-dr-seuss-crafts-for-kids.html</id>

        <updated>2022-08-28T18:53:26-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Childhood wouldn't be complete without reading Dr. Seuss's books. Kids certainly love the whimsy and fantasy of the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/u1Kxlcja-4SIwjg6f_jPA2CAYZtpp7Q3pX3r8OfpmoAzHwgQNN-dJDRHyHAdVudgDUjyLvcRNmMaeZXnYtv2DkSP_Z-dQvc3nvfWMU4Vw_Dhl51YMO1LOwfs_P6dUudc4tuzmnvU" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Childhood wouldn't be complete without reading Dr. Seuss's books. Kids certainly love the whimsy and fantasy of the stories. With those colorful illustrations, coupled with outlandish characters, funny, made-up words, and silly antics, children can't help but adore these creative stories.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Perhaps you can make it EVEN MORE fun by helping them make some Dr. Seuss inspired crafts. Here is our list of fun and exciting Dr. Seuss crafts you can make at home or school. They are perfect for your kids, and you'll surely enjoy them too!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Cat in the Hat Crafts</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Cat in the Hat paper plate</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/llSWp9cnioSD3YOvtuTg1_O5esyx9FtUlkCuCf4fymSYafwvQnNohgXljATRnvCvfXu1lVoYvHmylgtjDIYtsFxL7GY0W-uZTBpd4JdWkrlthDqBpTLkwZtC9hcxRN3BgQvWtNPr" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Let your kids make their own Cat in the Hat face with this paper plate craft. It's easy to make, and you won't have any trouble finding the materials needed. It's great for kids of all ages, even preschoolers.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://www.gluedtomycraftsblog.com/2015/01/paper-plate-dr-seuss-cat-hat-kid-craft.html">Glued to My Crafts</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>2. Cat in the Hat hats</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/BoU179y1cX565j60IlmwM25ae6GwJlArT698oJYjfd8Z5xVlgx0rGRKuu8vcyoNvKtnRhwZHfG5GTlozzLGDFL4_FnD5oaeYkkcnCNqVhzPBkO4vBd1CiWbMePQlMhfTpyu98abw" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Make Cat in the Hat reading even more fun by having your make (and wear) these iconic red and white striped hats. I a perfect craft to complement any Dr. Seuss's book. You can use it for parties too!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://www.mamacheaps.com/diy-dr-seuss-cat-in-the-hat-solo-cup-hat-craft/">Mama Cheaps</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Cat in the Hat patterned Hat</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/uvdnL_oOjN2lEEgid4ZCEGZjOygkG5p5dBKnA7V7tI4Yz5-ObKf2Ohe9Gh1uFQ6R9AevIaDuatNiTO2X1hBczcxxCH1Q_a4Kq5DGS8L05qh_TKqZIoy4GY5A9aM7CqkDCot-PLGb" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Speaking of the signature pattern, you can also let your kids make their own Hat designs with different colors with this Cat in the Hat patterned hat craft. Play with varying strips of paper and see how your child his very own top Hat.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://teachpreschool.org/2011/02/23/making-patterns-with-dr-seusss-hat/">Teach Preschool</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>4. Cat in the Hat handprint craft</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/3mnk96MRS2nUgmDqFyelx-s8d2iNc6d6WkjIsvsUZVc1MFCaZyWtbXC5t-vbw_8kKt9fdBQiOMnoLUHQl86sfCsflrSKeUKPf8kakDTod0YMWnesr1J2Z6waVKn471ElF2jaiwWn" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Let your toddlers recreate Cat in the Hat characters using their tiny hands. They'll have fun indeed in making these handprints, and you can keep it as a keepsake too. But watch out, this craft can get a bit messy.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://kidscraftroom.com/cat-in-the-hat-handprint-crafts/">Kids Craft Room</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>5. Cat in the Hat Kabobs</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/iYCGSmm9Ep_QW_cjsr5J0cVPpIgygt_NToV_hZqFgoQH_qH7bO2hky-5bqm0H659_HGAXzlgWwMzFPR3NC0Sx60yeQwtweSWRpRcMTqHns-gr1dGExSHMqntLLfTBovBkurBCxA5" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Alright, this one isn't exactly a craft, but it's too cute not to add. If you want Cat in the Hat themed snacks, you can try these Cat in the Hat Kabobs. Your kids will definitely love it.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://todayscreativeideas.com/dr-seuss-inspired-snacks-and-crafts/">Today's Creative Ideas</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>The Lorax Crafts</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>6. The Lorax plate</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/5b-wGEmQHbdgNcciI0StDYW0bTsYKSB6LbSHOIp1VCb_FUJ8QmAeOzDPefjjUbSueUaNsuLkBMXkCUhQp4DnGc8cl8zZTAdgm3ShS8849-YMcX0hA9eA2qYGx0m1pFDr313Gx8-6" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Recreate the iconic Lorax face with some paper sheets and a paper plate. This fun The Lorax plate craft is so easy to make, and your toddler or preschooler will surely have fun making them. You can even let them use their tiny hands to create The Lorax's mustache. Isn't that fun?&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://www.anightowlblog.com/lorax-paper-plate-craft/">A Night Owl</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>7. The Lorax cupcake liners craft</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/DdqAvpQGHcI-hrjArV7n6aPWMcQ6VGm7RH0HV8g3bffXXrBoRJADUCIpkfg8rKd1J5dN8ZGNua6LMieBM1x7r_zPi2CpPZ75PdNSbIwNjJX05JVsmMy1vxuU8IonfvzRGWRV7y_f" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Cupcake liners aren't just for those sweet cupcakes; you can also make crafts out of them. Have your kids recreate their Lorax scene using colorful cupcake liners, a few strips of paper, and some straws. You can also keep this craft as a keepsake or hang it on a wall and turn it into nice, cute wall decor.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://iheartcraftythings.com/the-lorax-dr-seuss-kids-craft.html">I Heart Crafty Things</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>8. Mustache matching puzzle</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/LNzxUwWa6eZU8YNEECRV3aUTY1qceCaGHgVFBmUTe2MIAI8NxAEh9OZGOHXhkvdSyIdOXUAYrwGCxQlReplI0kNSI_yu3SyZzw1ZYtRcHSPSYaNUXxcLmQzRQ3DZUUQeVzJ4Y16E" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The Lorax has probably the most iconic mustache in all of Dr. Seuss's stories. If you think so too, try making this mustache matching puzzle craft with your kids inspired by The Lorax. You can also use this to teach your toddler about shape matching and how mustaches can be shaped differently. Don't forget to let them try out some of the mustaches too. It'll be hilarious!&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://www.notimeforflashcards.com/2012/03/mustache-matching-activity.html">No Time for Flash Cards</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>9. The Lorax fingerpainting art</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/XmLpF1IvYI_pT7BDLICpUkV8CRd-lgl76l7M6n17p9pi83VdrhodVG6i4OmAtLZxqk2LdKYReVJAicULtsuvKCgTar8aUJYS25JfGBf5q1ffzYms6zEAMma4RS-Do5VfezUNLXdH" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Let your kids create their own Lorax-inspired Truffula tree using some paint and their little fingers! Let them explore their creativity and design their own colorful trees, just like in the book. With paint and fingers combined, you need to be ready because this can get real messy! But still fun.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://www.amomstake.com/lorax-trees-finger-painting-art/">A Mom's Take</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>10. Lorax Toilet Paper Roll Craft</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/YQQSOR6BtfKj8TEAWQmCfph0tOmc-CwtdiGJ9qI-L8lB1Hk-qrnpSllL30YGQzhk1wjT6wMlh6dTPwlmw4iIX3VjHQbdNJuIoWCCQZuRjVqCybNHr5XsUVigZzJmGMjavt-gaTGO" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Make toilet paper rolls more interesting by turning them into a small Lorax puppet. Kids will definitely love this adorable little Lorax craft made with just simple materials. You can use this to teach your kids about the characters while reading the book. Try adding some Truffula trees to complete the look.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://www.craftymorning.com/lorax-toilet-paper-roll-craft-kids-dr-suess/">Crafty Morning</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>One Fish, Two Fish, Red Fish, Blue Fish Crafts</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>11. One Fish Two Fish Wine Cork Painting</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/HjHSJVzoDn4uPJToemmV6d_RXRUN8DpGaCZZKyK61lrJ7jXruxGKrG6ohyjjncwVzuq7c-_lf4DKsrIoVpeKff0V-wil7DeqhKEc7xoolfgrtkYFODKLC27efvyVykd5749Q7by6" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Since your kids still couldn't have some of that red wine, let them have the cork. Make some easy fish paintings with your little one using wine corks you may have lying around the house. It's a fun activity and is excellent for recycling too!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://musthavemom.com/dr-seuss-activities-one-fish-two-fish-wine-cork-painting/">Must Have Mom</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>12. One Fish Two Fish Flying Fish Craft</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/jqfHy8YBzHqkE7UFqF3lohw2peJkFEBhh09q55NDIwE9S0BeSddQgSPiCUwKTc_AuGhgntom7FBISJh5AcLtWRn2rj01ijnf667PHqXF6QL0tCik6it8fsCiVM9gGWV8zQ-CvpgQ" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here's an easy-peasy craft to make with your kids that doesn't only take a few minutes to make; it's interactive as well. This flying fish craft can be enjoyed by the whole family or your whole kindergarten class. Make as many fish as you can and create a fun game for everyone using these fishes.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://eighteen25.com/one-fish-two-fish-flying-fish-craft/">Eighteen25</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>13. One Fish Two Fish Paper Plate Aquarium</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/hMet3pylWs1LiKmhRe5FeTccAuSJ9-1KjfFgbOedXEa7IeGOZLyICLK9bw6pCT99hOqGV7q0c-C9h_ytizdjUHvTjxJFtPXjqeKC2QWDqCkQKajqaN01DZYxYUyV8d83A9VMpgE1" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Have your kids make their own One Fish Two Fish inspired aquarium with this craft. All you need is a paper plate, some paint, some fish cutouts, or even some fish crackers that your kids are munching on during snack time. Just make sure they don't eat it after making this craft.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://www.mrsthompsonstreasures.com/one-fish-two-fish-red-fish-blue-fish.html/">Mrs. Thompson's Treasures</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>14. 1 Fish 2 Fish Red Fish Blue Fish Craft</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/S2B2rIRmncjxZMY-BSKoGVfz6due7q_1giNJWbk4sOUbIcmUIxjIb2SsUNyBRVWASKk3ooYXARMYkazBf-bQ1AJUO-ASvrjOOBPrkqYnb4KUK3mTrSi_mCduAmYZDTjO9YTszl3Q" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Another great artwork to do with toddlers is this fish craft. It's really an easy craft to do, and kids will enjoy how colorful it is. You can make the fishes by using plain cupcake liners and painting them, or you can also just use colored liners. Simply cutting circles out of colored paper to make the fish would also work.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://amomsimpression.com/1-fish-2-fish-red-fish-blue-fish-craft/">A Mom's Impression</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>More Dr. Seuss Crafts</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>16. I Can Sleep with My Eyes Shut Sleeping Mask</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/hRe1foql9wbapl78qm_zM6TZdrfdACdFy7BB5vI8PdZFKcLVfKks8iInlbMAkaCbhNYX3D6Jd4yTW-Fl5AEtCJmHINx_osAojOAw9wn91TcdPiFLJ53pkVhKFHkIzm1g6czcyHNP" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The story of I Can Sleep With My Eyes Shut is another Dr. Seuss classic. Just like what the story is all about, you can make this sleep mask with your kids or students and introduce a fun activity with them wearing this mask. You can even let them paint and design their own mask to showcase their creativity.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://30minutecrafts.com/2014/02/i-can-sleep-with-my-eyes-shut-dr-seuss-mask-2.html">30minute Crafts</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>17. Green Eggs Sensory Play</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/KWh1XqugAIX3fxzNLVeglDxHCk0g_zz5n2pXMaeJpCVTqZQD6iel7vK0_04NBDcbcq74ulL_v2jZmJgByFInbrmvkQBfPdkVGCKc1DU9DDC0GCxJwkApRzvUUj3_NO9Bj0vpCe8o" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Green eggs? You can let your little ones examine these oddly-colored eggs by making one from slime. No, they are not edible, so make sure your kids only play with them and not eat them. It'll be a fun sensory activity nonetheless.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://www.stillplayingschool.com/2013/02/green-eggs-sensory-play.html">Still Playing School</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>18. Horton Hears A Who Foam Cup Craft</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/fJScjUwOegg_sM1uOTPCsIxmbfyHYB8PbHE9tY0Lkoblc8EvCwFV9oyfIDa1b0mTOQR37BBD9OB1waTGapINiMEljHa9w_RBNYnDoUWGCI2O98oRGuIhdGL6amCwbBO2tyrWgHTI" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here's a perfect craft to pair along while you read Dr. Seuss's Horton <em>Hears A Who</em> book. Horton's styrofoam cup version is a cute character model to help your kids understand the story better. They'll definitely enjoy making it too.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://www.iheartartsncrafts.com/styrofoam-cup-dr-seuss-horton-hears-craft-kids/">I Heart Arts and Crafts</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>19. Yertle the Turtle Toppling Turtles Craft</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/YKEnxXONu5QnvfkJc_fMHVmUSWNhJwdoWGrbcgOlEHYA6S3-97vWGxliFzPBGid-ls1kIpFiPb7bU5o_LkijABerfzp4XH5BPf_nKdH89B5btg_kGy7VJjrJ7CJ78gqlMT3_kBaT" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Enjoy crafting and playing games using these adorable little turtles inspired by Dr. Seuss's story, Yertle the Turtle. It's a great recycling activity as well because this craft uses plastic bottle caps. You can collect as many bottle caps as you can and create a tower of turtles. See who can stack the highest one.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://www.kiwico.com/diy/Arts-and-Crafts-Ideas/1/project/Toppling-Turtles-/2747">Kiwi Co. Corner</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>20. Fox in Socks Tweetle Beetle Battle Bottle</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/ewbcrzBSOFCcXSomNvWniYqW77wxhN8zstAcXk1BC9yUyBQOZcres0OoJtYqWghSEKn7gcCocCz5GfkXFHmc0gRW49_MXG-udoj2uJll07XdHhV6rlHA9XUQi8xWTsUC_kVE2LDk" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Those who've read the Fox in the Socks book will know how funny the tongue twisters are in the book. Especially on the last part about the Tweetle Beetles and their fierce battles inside a bottle. This bottle craft is inspired by that battle in the story, and it's effortless to make. Your kid can shake it up and learn about the different bugs inside. Pretty cool!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://madincrafts.com/dr-seuss-activity-make-fox-in-socks/">Mad in Crafts</a></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>21. The Shape of Me and Other Stuff shape recognition</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/FOqBbB7CAF22IiS6Pw3qMd2uaO1VpEm8bhgDE16A1fYk9WJLM7luS0Uz-v004l_iNm1WlF9KvAfI7EDy_hY4TH9W8Yyqc9iFMRNUlIxqy3C_fhlltM0BrMUk6ncRd2VqsVolOge1" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Teach your kids everything about shapes and how they change, just like in the book <em>The Shape of Me and Other Stuff </em>by Dr. Seuss. It's a fun drawing and learning activity for kids that you can do while reading the book.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://www.momendeavors.com/dr-seuss-shape-recognition-activity/">Mom Endeavors</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>22. Dr. Seuss Inspired Rhyming Game</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/md8R_WVikcIVCDsyNnOaefZYtFctru5wc865MwPEz0bjNkoiSdCTh3CAf6198gCWx98FjZl7oCJ3TH2KY7NWeQ2xuahNE9u6nZffD7Ntip-QWH8y76YxigqFSMCRZifh4y6AMye2" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For kids who are building this vocabulary, this Dr. Seuss Inspired Rhyming Game is a fun craft to make and a great educational activity for learning kids.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://sweetrosestudio.com/2013/02/dr-suess-inspired-rhyming-game.html">Sweet Rose Studio</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>23. Green Eggs Eggs and Ham Pretzels</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/ZLGwyigERHGZydm3nxDEh67kHN9ekOh88qEEKQOaqQ8VvE5fSjqu17bUtjvAQLnkM51Mj6i_y3QzGEdDu8Q8WMflvONgJiTy6MEo_o3b8_hYvDhpfaN30M1XJsX0YSEv_88Yryjj" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Another adorable craft/treat to make with your kids (that looks too cute to skip) are these Green Eggs Eggs and Ham Pretzels. They make for great snacks when you have a Dr. Seuss storytime session. You can make these on St. Patrick's day too. ('cuz they're green!)</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://www.the-girl-who-ate-everything.com/green-eggs-ham-pretzels/">The Girl Who Ate Everything</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>24. Put Me in the Zoo Paper Craft</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/23/_aysgwpmFdCpIW8bgmKmOI_QQrvqNcLqm1CeZcKK6Mu3ywlwuc0PrJelFbNc8gUmMX3F8vObiCgngHPpoQFCS69D1JwjchXS36Foj82EdaRtr054CyEnbwt5HVvzIily70aGGU32" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This cute paper plate craft inspired by the book Put Me In The Zoo is a great craft to teach kids about colors. You can do it at birthday parties as well. It's a super simple activity that will be enjoyed by kids of all ages.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can see the full instructions on <a href="https://www.naturalbeachliving.com/put-me-in-the-zoo-craft/">Natural Beach Living</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Get crafting with Dr. Seuss!</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Dr. Seuss's books are, without a doubt, a part of everyone's childhood. I hope you can make your reading sessions more fun by combining these fun and creative artworks you can do at home or school. Which one of these will you make with your kids? Try them out today and get crafting with Dr. Seuss.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>15 Easy Ways To Make A Small Bedroom Look Bigger</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/15-easy-ways-to-make-a-small-bedroom-look-bigger.html"/>
        <id>https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/15-easy-ways-to-make-a-small-bedroom-look-bigger.html</id>

        <updated>2022-08-28T18:53:26-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    If you're struggling with having a small bedroom, you're not alone. Having a small bedroom is one of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/18/ZjgzVYKpq82MtxAgsU9XzQuJrUKLpd4bfka8-RVTfhopZ19-R88khvXyEWys7hV4N9yK77t4X37vp3BB9GMbbUvfzknK-EVnPqLq0MKgD6uSMy9ogyqeu8p5j763sCSEyKj4c4v_" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you're struggling with having a small bedroom, you're not alone. Having a small bedroom is one of the most common issues with decorating. It's a challenge because there are lots of essential furniture you'd want to put inside.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Remodeling and adding some actual space in your bedroom needs too much work (and money). Luckily, there are some cost-effective and easy tricks you can do to make your small bedroom look and feel larger. You can reasonably do these yourself - no need to take down walls and remodel.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To give you some useful ideas, here are a few tips on how to make your small bedroom look bigger.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>What colors make a small room look bigger?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Colors play an essential role in any space. Putting the right colors on your walls can actually help make your bedroom appear larger. Here are some points to consider when choosing a paint color for your bedroom walls.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Use light colors on your walls</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/18/1L4Pb3MYvDdw0eXDO3FqTREzrnkKnvk84ZApIAjT9kfowbRnsupAAgGGjjPyY-jxEHX1sZEPKwMKhsBiAmEyRSNuxNLCEgY7zgek_OxD33W_ZoYIf7VGh243LlbJQQNY80NQeAEl" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Lighter colors like white, cream, pastel colors, and others can reflect light. This will make a room seem brighter, airier, and roomier. Meanwhile, dark colors absorb light. Painting your walls with dark colors will make it feel smaller and more constricting. It's best to stick to light colors if you want to make your room look bigger.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also use wallpaper with horizontal or vertical stripes. These patterns create the illusion of height or width.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>2. Use a lighter color for your trim</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Painting your trim with a slightly lighter color than your walls creates an optical illusion making your walls appear farther back. This can help make your bedroom seem larger. You can paint your door frames, wall trims, even your ceiling a lighter color to create depth.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Use monochromatic paint</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/18/HV3mfPzMHomXOJyOKYVuI77c-vSopIlKqpxtvyxyv4wOVuY3K_scqDK-doOtcDiGuu34zlA1S5lxPnS_pT5fRJNRQLBwcam5F0RMY0J2rBOb-Zrjp4uahd728McxgXmCg8zNK_lz" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Coordination is also necessary when choosing colors for your room. Painting your bedroom with different or opposing colors will segment off portions when viewing, making it feel smaller. You should opt for monochromatic paint colors throughout your room to create fluidity and space. Try picking a light color and use different shades of it instead of using different colors.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How do I arrange my small bedroom?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Choosing the right furniture and arrangement also matters when setting up your bedroom to be bigger. Remember that you should only put in what's really necessary and try to be creative when choosing your furniture.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>4. Don't put too much furniture</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Bedside tables are good to have, but using two of them isn't necessary if you have a small room. Instead of using pairs of furniture like bedside tables, or a two-seater couch, opt for using just one. Using less furniture vacates more space, thus, making your room seem much bigger.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You should also avoid tall furniture as it can make the ceiling seem lower than it actually is. Another positioning you can do is to place your furniture against the wall or at an angle. Putting it at an angle leads the eye through a longer diagonal distance rather than the shorter wall. You'll also often get some additional storage space behind a diagonally-positioned piece in the corner as a bonus.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>5. Use space-saving furniture</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/18/atbdl8tXYAWNH3fLj12MGjA1eKZfmzRd7hGPMg9_7HKUWhQtWdB6LGf8zXxJQAfRCTwUcd3pK52dNDLMtG1Hdlt8N-8yiCkPytw3Xnvu6igEUGFMdDbGZ59eXJqy7rteQRxvd83j" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Just from the name itself, space-saving furniture allows you to save more space and create more room inside your bedroom. One popular trend in space-saving is using a raised bed.&nbsp; It almost looks like a double-deck or bunk bed, but the lower part is made into a study area or a closet. If you're not into that, you can also try using a bed with a built-in storage underneath. It will allow you to store more stuff without having to get another cabinet or drawer for it.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can also try folding beds. There are ones which transform into a sofa when you fold them. You can just tuck your bed away when not in use, making more space for you to move around your bedroom. There are tons of space-saving and double-purpose furniture in the market. Some stools double as storage bins, folding tables, folding chairs, etc.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>6. Use furniture that has legs</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>"Floor gang" is a trend. But if you want to make a more spacious illusion in your bedroom, choose furniture that has legs. Lifted furniture creates an airy and open feel in the bedroom, making it look bigger. But make sure to keep the area underneath clean and organized. Not everything needs to be legged, but try to have at least one piece with some height.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>7. Use transparent furniture</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/18/8t0cC5Jk43BgTLkHHJ4xuZBUHFmnPJV7InxWyRB5MXVzlYYCeJTtxRHR8vh6ePuZrvHbbfJD3y1Mrb2V4mQiLU6Nw8zg6brO5xh92RNiro0zp4ClqOzWU_QXUOlBLGOwt0zg0H0v" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Instead of using wooden chairs or desks, try using transparent furniture. Although it still takes up the same amount of space, it can trick your eyes into feeling like it's not. Try using glass-top desks and pair it with acrylic or lucite chairs. This will give you a study area that has a minimal visual impact, thus making it appear like there's a lot of space in your bedroom.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>8. Make built-in shelving around your headboard</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/18/5U_u9dx9mqeBLlfXaau1yEGYsh-NYuphYs9shY1LEzJ-l6QEuthfRxmG05dc1c3jriV_JCARtIDFgkrSiESKDaCKIxLecH3DW_y8IP2Myy6nZ1lllP2cI-36seKTXec1IPo2DZac" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Built-in shelving can function as a good storage space. Having some of it above, beside, or even around your headboard will save you the unnecessary drawers. Shelving beside your bed can also double as a bedside table. This will save you space and creates an illusion of depth in the wall, making the small room feel bigger.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How do I decorate my room to make it look bigger?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Using the right decor also makes a big difference when it comes to the appearance of your bedroom. Like your furniture, the fewer, the better. Less is more. Make sure it's on the right scale as your bedroom and avoid overly huge decors. Here are some useful decorating tips you can follow for your bedroom.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>9. Have a full-length mirror</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A small bedroom should have a full-length mirror. Using mirrors is the easiest way to trick the eyes into thinking a room is bigger than it is. Mirrors not only reflect light, but it can also create depth or height, especially a cleverly angled mirror. It's not only a nice decor, but it's also useful for checking your outfit from head to toe.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>10. Hang Ceiling-to-Floor Curtains</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/18/b7bKOxcBpNUDJf7cfSm9IogFPyhoiRpD2COZe608Ul00UAdFtyL0MU97TdN4awhkEAloNoiiAWUhqfaIq00GHCav3tSVDn0biyHUJwCzBzkmivolywru79i9yPqaJqhZOr_ibCYX" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For curtains, use a ceiling-to-floor type of curtain as they can make a space seem taller. Go for simple cotton or linen curtains that go well with your walls and avoid heavy drapes. You should also remember not to let the ends of the curtain touch your floor as this can disrupt the room's flow.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A simple solution is to tie them up or choose a curtain that is a few inches shorter. If there is a constraint in space, you can opt for blinds that are sleek in appearance.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>11. Keep your beddings simple</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A clean and simple look will make your room feel more spacious. You should also apply this to your beddings. Avoid heavy patterns for the pillows, bedspread, and throw cushions. Try to coordinate the colors and shapes of your bedding with your curtains to match the room's flow.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>12. Keep It Simple</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/18/CYd8mPZz6gAEu3mTLn_OTeHyYPoZsHhNSC95cXuavZS0fXbRyyBKZ1jZhC-xWU2Ut4OK8kWkQWr91psqzyjFptSXTFRYhjcWK8m3cQikHVOREWDtCui6YWtJxBaM9Xd8LNWzV2cO" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>While it's easy to place decors in your bedroom, having so many unnecessary decorations in your room will just make it look clumped and cluttered. If you want to make your room appear bigger, keep everything simple. The only essentials you need are a small lamp, a lovely plant, and a few pictures. That'll be enough.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>13. Maximize lighting</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>A well-lit room makes a big difference compared to a dark one. Try to maximize the flow of natural light inside your room during the daytime. It can open up the interior and make the room look larger. If you don't get too much daylight, try using different lighting fixtures to bring some light inside.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>14. Use wall-mounted lamps by the bed</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/18/eH4HMY5ENgIqfjtlZTM1cKdvy8bZ-Kpxu4zDWdHqywwB0_neTTqjteeKSHHs76VLTr6OJmMjMsyMLTkxUzS3jtHPeNcOUIDlWU9sYu0w3plCbhDe4Tp-GSrr1UdadvfN6beWNOVS" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Instead of using a bedside lamp, you can use wall-mounted lights and place them slightly beside your headboard and a bit higher than your bed. This draws the eye upward and helps give the room an open, airy look. It also reduces the visual clutter around your bed. Choose adjustable lamps as they are perfect for reading during the night.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>15. Clear all the clutter</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Last, but is no doubt, the most important tip is to clear your room from clutter. If you want a bigger space, you should try making more space by clearing out unnecessary things inside your bedroom. A well-organized, clutter-free, and minimalist bedroom looks visually bigger than how it actually is. Do cleaning and decluttering a habitually and avoid overcrowding your space.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Transform your bedroom and open more spaces</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Keeping your room clean and organized can already make a significant change. But if you still feel like your bedroom is constricted and small, you can follow the tips we've given above. You don't need to change or entirely remodel your room. A few changes and the elimination of unnecessary stuff will do. I hope this guide is useful for your bedroom. Which of these tips will you try?</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>15 Fun Halloween Crafts for Toddlers</title>
        <author>
            <name>Melbren</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/15-fun-halloween-crafts-for-toddlers.html"/>
        <id>https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/15-fun-halloween-crafts-for-toddlers.html</id>

        <updated>2022-08-28T18:53:26-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Halloween is definitely the wackiest and most fun holiday celebrated in almost every part of the world. Dressing&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Halloween is definitely the wackiest and most fun holiday celebrated in almost every part of the world. Dressing up with costumes, trick or treating, making Halloween themed food and decor - there are tons of activities to do to join the fun.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/afmqaeWsyVUmwEMxwJZoAelhvP0hBhxgltGHjqxXnBwA89emMLhJwOA1fIlYGq48op2eP7qUVCRiYn7e7uz636kZ4JNFtUM2eW_0j--eX-6yO2HZCg6RtQ8goLp2r5jSMZmPJD37" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Even young toddlers love this holiday. Make it even better by teaching them some cool Halloween crafts to make, so they can participate in the fun too. Get those little hands working as we present you this list of fun Halloween crafts for toddlers.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>How to make Halloween crafts?</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are different ways to make fun and exciting Halloween crafts for your home, school, or office. Aside from the traditional Jack-o-lantern, Halloween crafts made of paper, pipe cleaners, paper plates, and just about anything you can find at home can work as Halloween decor. It'll be fun to create a bunch of easy and entertaining projects, especially with some little helping hands to assists you.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Before doing these crafts with your kids, make sure you use kid-safe materials and always supervise them, especially when using tools like scissors. Here is a list of fun Halloween crafting projects you can make with kids at home or school.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Pumpkin crafts</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>What's Halloween without pumpkins? Carving jack-o-lanterns is a bit too hard for a kid (even to some adults...lol). But don't let them miss the Halloween pumpkin fun and let them try making these awesome pumpkin crafts.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>1. Paper Plate Pumpkin</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/RG8QUWWhMxTP0AZWogUFBSpKd8cX6cBhq2lmznf7WjoLc0wXSLERVQm3fktyby4OWL-DMCky-aSraRM3dwXAkV7lf6XXDP8nCHHGXFMa3t3vLFAcGfCoVmDgYn4CtdQQZoQS0xyH" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Paper plates</li>
<li>Pipe cleaners (green)</li>
<li>Orange and black crayons or markers (You can use other colors too!)</li>
<li>Hole punch</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Have your toddlers color and decorate their own pumpkins using paper plates. These are really easy to make, and you can hang them as Halloween decors too.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://thesimpleparent.com/easiest-paper-plate-pumpkin-craft/">The Simple Parent</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>2. Pumpkin painting</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/0TTCc6CGS0lux8yf6VAXXajcPXpQVSqMw-bpvnYUAoodHKsqUkjfLx4nfWkmI8lDyV0Y82rYefats4_RJw9IAC4VcAc5XHuEf4aY7uht3CP4BA9hg0aZKSMuaiOK6VxbyttwnRc1" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Pumpkins</li>
<li>Non-toxic different colored craft paints</li>
<li>Paintbrushes</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Toddlers may not be allowed to carve pumpkins yet. But you can still get them involved by letting them do the next best thing after carving - painting! Have them paint your pumpkins for more fun colored jack-o-lanterns. The brighter the colors, the better!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://www.gluedtomycraftsblog.com/2013/10/toddler-fun-pumpkin-painting-craft.html">Glued to My Crafts</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>3. Fist bump-kins</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/u6NpkFmnDUs-kCCLFugkTFuCxW5nzRvVZO4gKgiYklQir5cZDqhAmwg1TCdoBfvFSbk96c57gPopBPYk1IQELTAmsawecrMCnTc-2-bmzVfdQa8fbZTXPjeJIF1gj-UYoR1RPD7H" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Washable, non-toxic craft paint (orange and brown)</li>
<li>Small paintbrush</li>
<li>Construction or card stock paper (They used green for this project)</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>These cute fist bumpkins are perfect for Halloween. You can also keep at as keepsake or hang them as an autumn decor for your home. The best part about this project is getting the whole family to participate in making them.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://thriftyjinxy.com/easy-fist-bump-kins-pumpkin-craft-create-a-memory/">Thrifty Jinxy</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>4. Apple Stamping Pumpkins</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/qjpaEYI6Fi59HXRVE5edCXwQ122xHOdJirLmOBW0JVSMae5s2KTPMXv80ZPvqCjOxhXrjEs9LICMUFbyIwrQD_wY7AEqEYHpdYL_Nb0OD1bUkIMchvmWDTQ1oMnJt8-SxC747ENC" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Apple (cut in half)</li>
<li>Orange craft paint</li>
<li>Pipe cleaners (brown and green)</li>
<li>Googly eyes</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Orange apples kinda look like pumpkins in disguise. Have your little one stamp those apples on paper to create their own pumpkin art. You can decorate it with googly eyes and some pipe cleaners to make them look more fun. Just watch out, make sure your toddler isn't trying to bite on that apple while there's some orange paint on it!&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://www.madetobeamomma.com/apple-stamping-pumpkin-craft/">Made to Be a Momma</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Monsters and Spider Crafts</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Make monsters and spiders less scary and turn them into cute little Halloween art by trying out these fantastic crafts.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>5. Spider suckers</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/K7vP89v512sOlDNIf8HKG7jbFpX9LIMtxett8vUsyYOQjP6wS9IfyBGa2b6ceuJa7THx9TimrKfABbjNjjfBNy4PbES7IAhyEbcAdydT1C5Ijg5inlLVA9_pAkPflgBXY-LurxsV" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Lollipops</li>
<li>12-inch pipe cleaners (2 per spider)</li>
<li>Googly eyes</li>
<li>School glue</li>
<li>Scissors/wire cutters</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Turn those lollies into a more Holloween inspired treat by transforming them into spiders. These are really fun to make and can also serve as a treat your guest or even a giveaway to trick or treating kids. Just make sure your small kids aren't eating them all as you do it.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://theinspirationboard.com/spider-suckers/">The Inspiration Board</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>6. Mess-free monster painting</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/6dI9eAa2HyJrdRLXG40C7f3Aeb-vuNBDqUiZVgbtD_urFeY3GkbidXTMXvnPmuK9fRcftptR-aFWQxUJ9vhvlMuZs7M_mh7axT_6QoM7M0G0QbPi00alSP3OS148wdWssJ5_rLJ6" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B7O7K83TCScYZjRld1owTmlZTm8/view?usp=sharing">monster template</a> printed out on cardstock&nbsp;</li>
<li>large Ziploc bag (gallon size)&nbsp;</li>
<li>washable paint&nbsp;</li>
<li>googly eyes</li>
<li>scissors&nbsp;</li>
<li>white glue</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Worried about your kids making a huge mess? Worry no more with this mess-free monster painting craft. This craft is safe for kids of all ages, even babies. They'll enjoy mixing and smudging colors all around. What's even better is that you have no mess to clean up later.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://toddlerapproved.com/2015/10/mess-free-monster-painting.html">Toddler Approved</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>7. Styrofoam cup spiders</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/M4PdTAxJGt-R3tO6ziSAvJzH7n0jxEEXRfNIDk9IGQ5LIUnrAGCQgqg5G-4o2vlP8pWGpeE-12hWhVbz9EPcruqGJbbIx-ubf7B2wrcZVJlbH_f2nyipLxdu-EWLs-Z0wljNL6mW" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Styrofoam cups</li>
<li>Googly eyes</li>
<li>Pipe cleaners</li>
<li>Craft paint</li>
<li>paintbrush</li>
<li>School glue</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Spice up those extra cups you have lying around and turn them into these adorable styrofoam cup spiders. There's painting, sticking, and cutting using scissors involved, so you need to assist your little ones with this project.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://onelittleproject.com/styrofoam-cup-spiders/">One Little Project</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>8. Monster Mobile</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/TcWfdqjQWZvW1H-ciEY-FVkzquKsXZ5RT730l-qtjMesqrR_uRLPi2toiOcG87njXU1UZI5i7ekrUw_1tuzWU3D1Xysq_8eKwPnj-qNHe4bqHfw-zSQAqrpE4cwpLx9H8Mk5fc0f" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Toilet paper tubes</li>
<li>googly eyes</li>
<li>pipe cleaners</li>
<li>paint (black, green, purple, and orange are great for Halloween)</li>
<li>craft foam</li>
<li>yarn</li>
<li>scissors</li>
<li>glue</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Don't throw away your paper towel rolls. Recycle them instead and turn them into these cute monster mobiles. They look adorable, and your kids will definitely enjoy making these monsters, making them look fun, friendly, and a bit wacky!</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://happyhooligans.ca/monster-mobile/">Happy Hooligans</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Ghost and Mummy Crafts</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Ghosts and Mummies are known to be scary creatures. But you can make them look fun and cute with these exciting crafts.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>9. Puffy ghosts</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/BJEwM0l2lHOas3HMQiDBa9fN4TuDNGdrsH5fuv1S1mf1ky_1AnzEs6oq3rAu0ZELMPp8lmBpUFhiRpZRRWFp85us7q6kW2YStFBgnU-iZhl5h5cTsOocl8spcnyC5AdFBoyKpnDC" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Puffy Ghost Template</li>
<li>White card stock paper (you can also use paper plates)</li>
<li>Cotton Balls</li>
<li>Black construction paper</li>
<li>Scissors</li>
<li>Glue</li>
<li>Yarn or string (optional)</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Make cute little hanging puffy ghosts and use them as decor in your home. You can hang or stick them anywhere for a more Halloween vibe. You can also make different facial expressions to make them look more fun.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://thrivinghomeblog.com/halloween-craft-puffy-ghosts/">Thriving Home</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>10. Masking tape mummy</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/zpF3krQKwlvdOocCndIVK_aSWZdd9bl9PACTx_0SHqSBdoGI5sp4JV1stSKy8wxThbLpR-NQr2UoqOHHxOUreuKHTkCV7L3n2YZAqhNqkKXLaH50qRPecYHJCFDYzjyQYhHKQI8C" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Black paper</li>
<li>Masking tape</li>
<li>Scissors</li>
<li>Googly eyes</li>
<li>Glue</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>These masking tape mummies are easy to make and don't require that many skills at all. Just let your kids go crazy with taping the mummy and create their own patterns. Add those cool googly eyes, and your adorable mummy is done.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://thrivinghomeblog.com/masking-tape-mummy/">Thriving Home</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>11. Paper cup ghosts</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/cD_yGC6DKfX1JjCj2PorYJTFLpKbk778438S065JIHuwND548WiKj5LAcOxxaxgSsZE09WaBapuNE84rEk0KcsiyiUekUXjWKDRJf2STXLxmuOzhi4Z4zPIgWJoVRx8zcMECngCE" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>white paper cups</li>
<li>white streamers</li>
<li>clear tape</li>
<li>black marker</li>
<li>scissors</li>
<li>white string</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>These paper cup ghosts are easy to make and need only a few materials. You can make a bunch of these and use them as Halloween decor in your home.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://www.sheknows.com/parenting/articles/973091/3-fun-and-easy-halloween-crafts-for-kids/">She Knows</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>12. Mummy pumpkin</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/bA0NoAx8cV6yWRFXYghpZtCqxve5vtPjCifTQl0HOkBxYpeaPcJlRLYGS0vC8TSDSwDBFMfzEuj7MlCAd4K7gzkGpdu_hsXbqQf_58JeQHEX8cefTjUe1IFJnY16xJQTj1M_pO6B" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Hot Glue</li>
<li>Gauze (some people used cheesecloth)</li>
<li>Wiggle Eyes</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you're looking for the easiest and the cheapest craft to make during Holloween, you've just found it. Mummy pumpkins require only a few items to do, plus they're enjoyable to make.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://mothersniche.com/mummy-pumpkins-easiest-craft-ever/">Mother's Niche</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>More silly Halloween crafts for toddlers</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>13. Toilet paper roll bat armbands</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/OlOqT9mbLhlftvIWKdmSF8QDIzg62Z_j5A0zlI3-fiAAUYW8tjnb3AI1RiHlwCs3pAZYVKVQPUYfRmxraZwUUrCYGZChTKW-NGBTbP8i8eS6xQML_Tz46LzJMIojoYwgPcmsW7ie" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Toilet paper roll</li>
<li>Craft paint (black)</li>
<li>Paintbrush</li>
<li>Eye stickers</li>
<li>Scrapbook paper</li>
<li>Glue</li>
<li>White marker</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Make some cool bat armbands using your old toilet paper rolls. You can use these as a display or let your kids wear then on their arms. These rolls fit perfectly on a toddler's arm, and their wings will flap slightly with every move.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://savvysassymoms.com/halloween-bat-craft-for-kids/">Savvy Sassy Moms</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>14. Halloween Slime</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/Z4hC7yBoy3HC76TKm1y7YHwnw6_loCb8YoxSffGNv-GKXSYRKhY0uT-PAACV4U5sJaWbvJuwU3umpA2xhmeaaVXXE8Oi-Rvql00nriClw5rCAyfosC5UAoysId_JO9dwDR0Ux850" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>6 ounces of white Elmer's glue</li>
<li>Orange food coloring</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon of Baking Soda</li>
<li>1½ tablespoons of Contact lens solution</li>
<li>2 tbsp of water</li>
<li>Mason jars</li>
<li>Googly eyes</li>
<li>Black felt</li>
<li>Glue dots or Hot Glue</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Try making this ooey-gooey fun with your kids and decorate your jars to give it a more Halloween vibe. They are fun to make and works great even after Halloween. These slime jars will surely keep your kids entertained for hours.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://www.thebestideasforkids.com/halloween-slime/">The Best Ideas for Kids</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>15. Witch Paper Craft</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/3bZD9N-UKEbkoHlC9b47grrkHvAip3k2M7Kqr6SXelWR04ESAgR4YAuCuZq5AseYIVMOZef9t1nqFKxZWszobPQDcoV9BTHlmQCFUiEfFsYO9yIbgsWqIfDCy3spES3A5i0UV1YI" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Witch Paper Craft Pattern (optional)&nbsp;</li>
<li>Black cardstock</li>
<li>brown cardstock</li>
<li>Tan cardstock</li>
<li>Green or purple cardstock</li>
<li>Orange construction paper</li>
<li>Googly eyes</li>
<li>Markers</li>
<li>Scissors</li>
<li>Glue</li>
<li>Stapler</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can make some fun witch paper craft using a couple of shapes. This paper witch is so easy to make. Great for preschoolers and Kindergarteners too! It involves some cutting using scissors, so you may want to assist them with this one.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://iheartcraftythings.com/witch-paper-craft-halloween.html">I Heart Crafty Things</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Bonus craft</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading --></p>
<h2>16. Q-Tip X-Ray Craft</h2>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://chrisgliddon.github.io/luckycathome/media/posts/17/2DypIpuDiz_nfNq63QGW3xj222bXXRwM8FBGr5zzFXCqPBpr6HlE0lco2S5SAj26KdrkNMcaHH9QB5_CCUuPpBz2OOG_WSo_R_YxcvRsN98egmELQ3rN8yQ9iHayfNaXwdO9pUm0" alt=""/></figure>
<p>
<!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Things you'll need:</strong></p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Black construction paper</li>
<li>White chalk</li>
<li>Q-Tips</li>
<li>Glue</li>
</ul>
<p>
<!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This fun and spooky craft are perfect for Halloween and for kids who like skeletons. It's also a great project to make as you can teach your kids about the human body as they glue these phalanges together.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>You can follow the full tutorial at <a href="https://fromabcstoacts.com/q-tip-x-ray-craft-for-preschoolers/">From ABCs to ACTS</a>.</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":1} --></p>
<h1>Spark creativity with these Halloween crafts&nbsp;</h1>
<p>
<!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Make your Halloween celebrations more exciting and enjoyable by creating some colorful and wacky crafts with your kids. This will also create a nice bonding moment that is worth sharing during this spooky but fun season. Which of these crafts will you make?</p>
<p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
